<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	
	>
<channel>
	<title>
	Comments on: Awnings For Doors And Windows &#8211; Solar Shading	</title>
	<atom:link href="/blog/burning-reduction-methods/awnings-for-doors-and-windows-solar-shading/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/blog/burning-reduction-methods/awnings-for-doors-and-windows-solar-shading/</link>
	<description>Censys.org</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 19:41:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>
		By: Marie		</title>
		<link>/blog/burning-reduction-methods/awnings-for-doors-and-windows-solar-shading/comment-page-1/#comment-10803</link>

		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Marie]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2010 03:56:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1374#comment-10803</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Energy mislaid by windows alone can comment for 10 percent to twenty-five percent of a household’s heating bill, according to a U.S. Department of Energy.One great energy saving tip is to get yourself the “right window film”. Window film is a known and trusted &quot;Green&quot; technology. You can find out more about window film at www.TintBuyer.com,  like most window films are for reducing solar heat gain in the summer, low-e films both block summer heat and improve winter heat retention. Be informed about the unbiased facts on the types window films that are available in the market that suit your needs. Getting the “right window film” is not only practical but also eco-friendly.]]></description>
			<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Energy mislaid by windows alone can comment for 10 percent to twenty-five percent of a household’s heating bill, according to a U.S. Department of Energy.One great energy saving tip is to get yourself the “right window film”. Window film is a known and trusted &#8220;Green&#8221; technology. You can find out more about window film at <a href="http://www.TintBuyer.com/" rel="nofollow ugc">http://www.TintBuyer.com/</a>,  like most window films are for reducing solar heat gain in the summer, low-e films both block summer heat and improve winter heat retention. Be informed about the unbiased facts on the types window films that are available in the market that suit your needs. Getting the “right window film” is not only practical but also eco-friendly.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
