<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>energy efficient windows Archives - Community Energy Systems</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/energy-efficient-windows/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/tag/energy-efficient-windows/</link>
	<description>Censys.org</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 19:39:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Windows That Lock In Your Energy &#8211; Never heard of Marvin but I am sure they have been around</title>
		<link>/blog/architecture/windows-that-lock-in-your-energy-never-heard-of-marvin-buti-am-sure-they-have-been-around/</link>
					<comments>/blog/architecture/windows-that-lock-in-your-energy-never-heard-of-marvin-buti-am-sure-they-have-been-around/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2010 21:09:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy Tough Love Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[residential energy efficiency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy efficient windows]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[windows]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=2158</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I believe these are custom made windows so they are not cheap either. ( on further review &#8211; I was wrong about that )  You can take that however you like. http://www.marvin.com/?page=Energy_Efficiency&#38;gclid=CP39jvGm4qQCFcu7KgodfGqqJw Stimulus Package Offers Up to $1,500 Our windows &#8230; <a href="/blog/architecture/windows-that-lock-in-your-energy-never-heard-of-marvin-buti-am-sure-they-have-been-around/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/blog/architecture/windows-that-lock-in-your-energy-never-heard-of-marvin-buti-am-sure-they-have-been-around/">Windows That Lock In Your Energy &#8211; Never heard of Marvin but I am sure they have been around</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I believe these are custom made windows so they are not cheap either. ( on further review &#8211; I was wrong about that )  You can take that however you like.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.marvin.com/?page=Energy_Efficiency&amp;gclid=CP39jvGm4qQCFcu7KgodfGqqJw" target="_self" rel="noopener">http://www.marvin.com/?page=Energy_Efficiency&amp;gclid=CP39jvGm4qQCFcu7KgodfGqqJw</a></p>
<h2 id="_ctl1__ctl2_heading">Stimulus Package Offers Up to $1,500</h2>
<p id="_ctl1__ctl2_paragraph">Our windows and doors aren’t just  beautiful – they can help you save energy. Virtually all Marvin products  already meet or exceed federal ENERGY STAR guidelines. <a href="http://www.marvin.com/?page=Tax_Credit"><strong>Now, you may qualify for a federal tax credit of up to $1,500 under the new stimulus program</strong></a> when you install energy-efficient Marvin windows and doors. At Marvin,  we’re committed to providing you with durable, high-performance products  that bring lasting value to your home. Your <a href="http://www.marvin.com/?page=where_to_buy">Marvin dealer</a> will help you choose the windows and doors that give you the  personalized look you desire – and the energy efficiency you need.  Whether you’re building new or looking at <a href="http://www.marvin.com/?page=Remodel_And_Replace">remodeling or replacement</a>, there’s never been a better time to purchase distinctive, energy-efficient windows and doors that are Built around you®.</p>
<div><a href="http://www.marvin.com/?page=Energy_Efficiency&amp;gclid=CP39jvGm4qQCFcu7KgodfGqqJw"> </a></p>
<h2 id="_ctl1__ctl3_heading">Energy Efficiency Made Easy</h2>
<p id="_ctl1__ctl3_paragraph">Always striving to meet the needs of an  ever-changing environment, Marvin builds energy effiency into product  performance while bringing your inspiration to life. Marvin offers a  variety of energy efficient glass options:</p>
</div>
<div><a href="http://www.marvin.com/?page=Energy_Efficiency&amp;gclid=CP39jvGm4qQCFcu7KgodfGqqJw"> </a> <a id="_ctl1__ctl4_imageAnchor"> <img decoding="async" title="Stimulus Room" src="http://www.marvin.com/newsletters/imageserver.ashx?id=223" border="0" alt="Stimulus Room" /> </a></p>
<p id="_ctl1__ctl4_paragraph"><strong>Low E II</strong> &#8211; Low E II features a  double metallic coating on the inside glass surface to reflect or absorb  the sun&#8217;s warmth and reduce damaging UV rays. Offers enhanced U-factor  and Solar Heat Gain Coefficient.</p>
<p><strong>LoE?-366? Glass</strong> &#8211;  Featuring three metallic layers of silver, this glass rejects solar heat  and features a lower Solar Heat Gain Coefficient than Low E II.  Recommended for warm climates where cooling costs are high and also for  areas where intense exposure to the sun is an issue.</p>
<p><strong>High-R Tripane</strong> &#8211; Features two layers of Low E glass with a clear center pane for a lower U-factor.</p>
</div>
<div><a href="http://www.marvin.com/?page=Energy_Efficiency&amp;gclid=CP39jvGm4qQCFcu7KgodfGqqJw"> </a></p>
<h2 id="_ctl1__ctl5_heading">Marvin also offers these enhancements to further increase the energy efficiency of your windows:</h2>
<p id="_ctl1__ctl5_paragraph"><strong>Energy Panel</strong> &#8211; Often confused with  storm windows, an Energy Panel is a glazing option consisting of a  removable, exterior glass panel finished on the edges by a surround.  Energy panels cover the exposed glass surface of each sash, and offer  added energy efficiency for wood windows with single glazing.</p>
<p><strong>Storm and Screen Combos</strong> &#8211; A combination unit is composed of two movable glass panels and one  movable screen panel. The individual panels can be configured multiple  ways, and can be easily removed from the interior for cleaning.</p>
</div>
<div><a href="http://www.marvin.com/?page=Energy_Efficiency&amp;gclid=CP39jvGm4qQCFcu7KgodfGqqJw"> </a></p>
<h2 id="_ctl1__ctl6_heading">Things To Know About Energy Efficiency</h2>
<p id="_ctl1__ctl6_paragraph2">Understanding these common terms will help you select the right windows and doors.</p>
</div>
<p><a href="http://www.energystar.gov/index.cfm?c=products.pr_tax_credits" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> </a> <a id="_ctl1__ctl7_imageAnchor" href="http://www.marvin.com/?page=redirect&amp;refer=http://www.energystar.gov/index.cfm?c=products.pr_tax_credits" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> <img decoding="async" src="http://www.marvin.com/images/logos/energystar/energystar_120.jpg" border="0" alt="" /> </a></p>
<p id="_ctl1__ctl7_paragraph"><strong>U-factor</strong> &#8211; This measures the rate  of heat loss and how well a product insulates. The lower the number, the  better a product is at keeping heat inside a building. The U-factor is  key in the winter months, and important to consider in choosing a  window.</p>
<p><strong>Solar Heat Gain Coefficient (SHGC)</strong> &#8211; This measures  how well a product blocks heat from the sun. The lower the number, the  better. In southern climates or high sun intensity areas, you might  actually want to keep the sun’s heat out of your house. Windows can help  do that.</p>
<p><strong>R-value</strong> &#8211; This measures resistance to heat loss.  Many people are familiar with the R-value because of its use in home  insulation. But actually, for windows and doors, U-factor and solar heat  gain coefficient are more important measurements.</p>
<p><strong>Design Pressure Rating</strong> &#8211; The “DP” measures the amount of pressure a door or window will  withstand when closed and locked. Each DP rating also establishes other  performance factors such as water penetration; air infiltration;  structural pressure; forced entry; and operational force. The higher the  DP numbers, the better the performance. Look for the certified hallmark  of the Window and Door Manufacturers Association.</p>
<p>To request more information about Marvin’s energy-efficient product offerings, <a href="http://www.marvin.com/?page=Request_Literature">click here</a>.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>More tomorrow.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/blog/architecture/windows-that-lock-in-your-energy-never-heard-of-marvin-buti-am-sure-they-have-been-around/">Windows That Lock In Your Energy &#8211; Never heard of Marvin but I am sure they have been around</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/blog/architecture/windows-that-lock-in-your-energy-never-heard-of-marvin-buti-am-sure-they-have-been-around/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
