<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>aquifer damage Archives - Community Energy Systems</title>
	<atom:link href="/censys/category/blog/aquifer-damage/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/censys/category/blog/aquifer-damage/</link>
	<description>Censys.org</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 19:55:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Handling Hanfords Radioactive Waste &#8211; It has been a fiasco from the begining</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/aquifer-damage/handling-hanfords-radioactive-waste-it-has-been-a-fiasco-from-the-begining/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/aquifer-damage/handling-hanfords-radioactive-waste-it-has-been-a-fiasco-from-the-begining/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 21:11:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[aquifer damage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bad health effects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dumb ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[no nukes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=8554</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>What genius decided to put Hanford Nuclear Site so close to the Columbia River that it is about to ruin it for good? Actually whose idea was it to put in a river valley in the first place? They really &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/aquifer-damage/handling-hanfords-radioactive-waste-it-has-been-a-fiasco-from-the-begining/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/aquifer-damage/handling-hanfords-radioactive-waste-it-has-been-a-fiasco-from-the-begining/">Handling Hanfords Radioactive Waste &#8211; It has been a fiasco from the begining</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>What genius decided to put Hanford Nuclear Site so close to the Columbia River that it is about to ruin it for good? Actually whose idea was it to put in a river valley in the first place? They really could have done a much better job. I mean look at the other World War II sites like Tennessee and New Mexico. It is almost collectively like they said, &#8221; Heh&#8217; lets do something like Rocky Mountain Flats in Denver.  But we well do it better&#8221;. And now after 80 years and one 12 story failed attempt, they are &#8220;excited to get going&#8221; with the attempted clean up. Sometimes I do not want to admit I am part of the Human race. sigh.</p>
<p><a href="https://news.yahoo.com/doggone-exciting-historic-treatment-begin-204249785.html">https://news.yahoo.com/doggone-exciting-historic-treatment-begin-204249785.html</a></p>
<header class="caas-header">
<div class="caas-logo"><a class="link rapid-noclick-resp caas-attr-provider-logo" title="" href="https://www.tri-cityherald.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-ylk="sec:logo-provider;elm:logo;slk:Tri-City Herald;g:"><img decoding="async" class="caas-img" src="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/FDocUHMUcKNq2kpAFgfDKA--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTE2MDtoPTQwO2NmPXdlYnA-/https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/013f6ca0-5e93-11ec-befd-4bbb6f221340" alt="Tri-City Herald" data-src="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/FDocUHMUcKNq2kpAFgfDKA--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTE2MDtoPTQwO2NmPXdlYnA-/https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-12/013f6ca0-5e93-11ec-befd-4bbb6f221340" /></a></div>
<header class="caas-title-wrapper">
<h1 data-test-locator="headline">‘Doggone exciting.’ Historic treatment to begin on decades-old Hanford nuclear waste</h1>
</header>
</header>
<div>
<div class="caas-attr">
<div class="caas-attr-meta">
<div class="caas-attr-item-author"><span class="caas-author-byline-collapse" data-id="m-0">Annette Cary</span></div>
<div class="caas-attr-time-style"><time class="" datetime="2021-11-16T20:42:49.000Z">November 16, 2021</time><span class="caas-attr-meta-separator">·</span>6 min read</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="caas-content-contain-share">
<div class="caas-attr-separator">
<div class="separator-ext"></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="caas-body">
<p>Hanford is close to starting the first large-scale <a class="link rapid-noclick-resp" href="https://www.tri-cityherald.com/news/local/hanford/article214168754.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener" data-ylk="slk:pretreatment of the millions of gallons of radioactive waste">pretreatment of the millions of gallons of radioactive waste</a> stored for decades at the site.</p>
<p>In about two months it could start operating around the clock, <a class="link rapid-noclick-resp" href="https://www.hanfordvitplant.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener" data-ylk="slk:preparing waste to be fed to the $17 billion vitrification plant">preparing waste to be fed to the $17 billion vitrification plant</a> to turn it into a stable glass form for disposal.</p>
<p>Hanford officials say that will be a historic moment.</p>
<div class="caas-da">
<div id="sda-INARTICLE"></div>
</div>
<p>“Being on the verge of the first use of large scale tank waste treatment on the Hanford site is pretty doggone exciting,” said John Eschenberg, president of Hanford’s tank waste contractor, Washington River Protection Solution.</p>
<p>The Department of Energy announced on Tuesday that construction and the readiness assessment of the Tank-Side Cesium Removal. or TSCR, system at Hanford had been completed.</p>
<p>“What a lot of people don’t recognize is the start of tank waste treatment actually starts when TSCR operations begin, so we will be actually treating waste on the industrial scale in just a few months for the first time in the history of the site,” said Brian Vance, the DOE Hanford manager.</p>
<p>The system, placed next to a Hanford underground waste storage tank, was developed in three years as a workaround to the Pretreatment Facility, which stands 12 stories high and covers an area larger than a football field at the vitrification plant.</p>
<p>The Pretreatment Facility was planned to separate waste into low-activity and high-level radioactive waste streams for treatment, but after possible technical issues related to high level waste were identified in 2012, construction on the building stopped.</p>
<p>DOE changed course, deciding to start treating just low activity radioactive waste first and delay treatment of high level radioactive waste for more than a decade.</p>
<p>It estimates that about 90% of the waste in underground tanks could be treated and disposed of in a lined landfill at Hanford as low activity waste.</p>
</div>
<p>:}</p>
<p>I dare you. Go there and read. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/aquifer-damage/handling-hanfords-radioactive-waste-it-has-been-a-fiasco-from-the-begining/">Handling Hanfords Radioactive Waste &#8211; It has been a fiasco from the begining</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/aquifer-damage/handling-hanfords-radioactive-waste-it-has-been-a-fiasco-from-the-begining/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How We Drained The Largest Lake West Of The Mississippi &#8211; OH My</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/aquifer-damage/how-we-drained-the-largest-lake-west-of-the-mississippi-oh-my/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/aquifer-damage/how-we-drained-the-largest-lake-west-of-the-mississippi-oh-my/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 19:49:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[aquifer damage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burning behavior]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dumb ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[masters of the universe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outdoors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[penetrating ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self inflicted wounds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=8386</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>This is the story of a man named Boswell and Boswell had a very lovely wife (Sorry Brady Bunch) who turned the San Joaquin Valley from a lush river and lake wildlife area into the nation&#8217;s bread basket. Also how &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/aquifer-damage/how-we-drained-the-largest-lake-west-of-the-mississippi-oh-my/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/aquifer-damage/how-we-drained-the-largest-lake-west-of-the-mississippi-oh-my/">How We Drained The Largest Lake West Of The Mississippi &#8211; OH My</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is the story of a man named Boswell and Boswell had a very lovely wife (Sorry Brady Bunch) who turned the San Joaquin Valley from a lush river and lake wildlife area into the nation&#8217;s bread basket. Also how it destroyed a massive habitat This was and is a despicable enterprise. Sort of on the order of a Nuclear Testing site in the desert. Or a Copper Mine for that matter. If you want to hear a video about it. There is This:</p>
<p><a href="https://digg.com/video/heres-why-the-united-states-drained-its-ninth-largest-lake">https://digg.com/video/heres-why-the-united-states-drained-its-ninth-largest-lake</a></p>
<p>If you want to read about it. You can go here:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.tularebasinwildlifepartners.org/history.html">http://www.tularebasinwildlifepartners.org/history.html</a></p>
<h2 class="wsite-content-title">Hydrologic History of the Tulare Basin</h2>
<div></div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The Tulare Basin historically supported an amazing complex of wetland habitats, unique in the world. This largely flat and arid region served as the floodplain for water flowing west from the southern Sierra Nevada, north from the Transverse Ranges, as well as from small intermittent arroyos flowing east from the Coast Ranges. Oak woodlands and riparian forests formed green corridors across the broad prairie on the eastern edge of the Tulare Basin. Freshwater tule marshes and alkaline wetlands adorned the slow-moving sloughs and shallow margins of Kern, Buena Vista, Goose, Tulare, and Summit lakes. Emergent marsh vegetation, such as tules and cattails, grew in permanent standing water at the shallow edges of freshwater wetlands. Upslope from the marshes, water intermittently flooded iodine bush scrub and alkali grassland habitats.</p>
<p>This highly-productive, shallow water system supported abundant populations of endemic lake-adapted fishes such that American white pelicans (Pelacanus erythrorhynchos) nested by the thousands on islands in Tulare Lake and Buena Vista Lake. The Tulare Basin&#8217;s extensive wetland habitats historically attracted significant numbers of resident and migratory waterbirds, including grebes, pelicans, cormorants, herons, egrets, ibises, geese, swans, ducks, rails, sandhill cranes, plovers, stilts, avocets, sandpipers, phalaropes, gulls, and terns.</p>
<p>The conversion of this water system to a lake-and-slough wetland to agriculture began in the mid-1800s when European settlers began to build canals and diversion structures to irrigate their crops.  This early irrigation infrastructure upstream from Tulare Lake slowly cut off the lake from its source waters, shrinking the lake&#8217;s footprint.  By 1899 &#8211; less than 50 years after irrigation was initiated &#8211; Tulare Lake went dry for the first time in history.</p>
</div>
<div>FOR STARTERS</div>
<div>:}</div>
<div>Go there and read. More next week.</div>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/aquifer-damage/how-we-drained-the-largest-lake-west-of-the-mississippi-oh-my/">How We Drained The Largest Lake West Of The Mississippi &#8211; OH My</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/aquifer-damage/how-we-drained-the-largest-lake-west-of-the-mississippi-oh-my/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Oil Companies Have Poisoned The World &#8211; I am not talking about their refined fuels</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/aquifer-damage/the-oil-companies-have-poisoned-the-world-i-am-not-talking-about-their-refined-fuels/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/aquifer-damage/the-oil-companies-have-poisoned-the-world-i-am-not-talking-about-their-refined-fuels/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 19:33:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[aquifer damage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bad health effects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dumb ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dying planet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green wash. corporate cover ups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self inflicted wounds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stewardship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=8374</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I am talking Plastics. A friend of mine once remarked to me that he thought he probably would be carrying around a pound of DDT by the time he died. That may be true but think about a pound of &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/aquifer-damage/the-oil-companies-have-poisoned-the-world-i-am-not-talking-about-their-refined-fuels/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/aquifer-damage/the-oil-companies-have-poisoned-the-world-i-am-not-talking-about-their-refined-fuels/">The Oil Companies Have Poisoned The World &#8211; I am not talking about their refined fuels</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am talking Plastics. A friend of mine once remarked to me that he thought he probably would be carrying around a pound of DDT by the time he died. That may be true but think about a pound of plastic by-products circulating around your body. 60 years again the stuff didn&#8217;t even exist. Bakelite did exist and other form forms as well. But not the &#8220;soft&#8221; stuff. The stuff that universally breaks down. Now plastic and it&#8217;s by-products are everywhere AND there is more coming. Yum!</p>
<p><a href="https://getpocket.com/explore/item/the-world-is-stuck-with-decades-of-new-plastic-it-can-t-recycle?utm_source=pocket-newtab">https://getpocket.com/explore/item/the-world-is-stuck-with-decades-of-new-plastic-it-can-t-recycle?utm_source=pocket-newtab</a></p>
<header>
<h1 class="huwp7ir">The World Is Stuck With Decades of New Plastic It Can&#8217;t Recycle</h1>
<h2 class="dbjv4gk">We&#8217;ve been hoodwinked into thinking recycling is a solution.</h2>
</header>
<div class="b12pz0kr">
<p><a href="http://qz.com/?utm_source=pocket">Quartz</a></p>
<ul>
<li>Zoë Schlanger</li>
</ul>
</div>
<p class="body">Ants are useful creatures. As the most numerous insects on Earth, they have colonized nearly every habitat on land. So when a researcher wants to understand how far a contaminant has spread, they turn to ants.</p>
<p class="body">In 2012, a group of French researchers found phthalates in the body of every ant they sampled. Ants from France, Hungary, Spain, Morocco, the Greek island Egine, and Burkina Faso all had at least some of the common plastic additive embedded in their skin. In the conclusion to the <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/24713390">paper</a> announcing their findings, they added a restless-sounding note: “In an attempt to find ants bearing no phthalate on their cuticle,” they wrote, they would next look farther afield. There had to be ants out there not yet full of plastic.</p>
<p class="body">But there were not. Five years later, the team published their follow-up. They had sampled ants from the most remote forests of Guyana, and the areas in the Amazon rainforest farthest from any urban center. Again, phthalates were embedded in their skin. “These findings suggest that there is no such thing as a ‘pristine’ zone,” they wrote in a <a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/304744861_Phthalate_pollution_in_an_Amazonian_rainforest">2017 paper</a>.</p>
<div id="root-3-2">
<div id="main-3-2" class="e76xF default-marquee">
<article>
<div class="cqh93">
<div class="tDvCK f_SV5">
<div class="au9XZ">
<div id="article-content-3-2">
<p class="cyhZ9">Or, as Pete Myers, an environmental health expert and adjunct professor at Carnegie Mellon University put it, “there is no untouched centimeter.”</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</article>
</div>
</div>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/aquifer-damage/the-oil-companies-have-poisoned-the-world-i-am-not-talking-about-their-refined-fuels/">The Oil Companies Have Poisoned The World &#8211; I am not talking about their refined fuels</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/aquifer-damage/the-oil-companies-have-poisoned-the-world-i-am-not-talking-about-their-refined-fuels/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>In The Race To Despoil The Environment, China Wins &#8211; They are First, Second and Third</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/evil-polluters/in-the-race-to-end-despoil-the-environment-china-wins-they-are-first-second-and-third/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/evil-polluters/in-the-race-to-end-despoil-the-environment-china-wins-they-are-first-second-and-third/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 20:56:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[air pollution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aquifer damage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burning behavior]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dumb ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dying planet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evil polluters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[military polluters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pollution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self inflicted wounds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stupid old men]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water pollution]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=8283</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>This is an article from 8 years ago. Imagine how much worse it has gotten since then. They have no shame. Who will stop this? Not the Central Government. Not the Provencial Government and not the local for surel. This &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/evil-polluters/in-the-race-to-end-despoil-the-environment-china-wins-they-are-first-second-and-third/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/evil-polluters/in-the-race-to-end-despoil-the-environment-china-wins-they-are-first-second-and-third/">In The Race To Despoil The Environment, China Wins &#8211; They are First, Second and Third</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is an article from 8 years ago. Imagine how much worse it has gotten since then. They have no shame. Who will stop this? Not the Central Government. Not the Provencial Government and not the local for surel. This is what we call in the United States call, a National Sacrifice zone. Remove the people and keep on going. Its disgusting and it&#8217;s despicable. Big YUCK for everyone to see.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2012/aug/07/china-rare-earth-village-pollution">https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2012/aug/07/china-rare-earth-village-pollution</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h1 class="content__headline ">Rare-earth mining in China comes at a heavy cost for local villages</h1>
<div class="content__header tonal__header">
<div class="u-cf">
<div class="old-article-message-wrapper u-h">
<div class="old-article-message"></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="tonal__standfirst u-cf">
<div class="content__standfirst" data-link-name="standfirst" data-component="standfirst">Pollution is poisoning the farms and villages of the region that processes the precious minerals</div>
</div>
<p>Health hazard &#8230; pipes coming from a rare-earth smelting plant spew into a tailings dam on the outskirts of Baotou in China&#8217;s Inner Mongolia autonomous region. Photograph: David Gray/Reuters</p>
<p>From the air it looks like a huge lake, fed by many tributaries, but on the ground it turns out to be a murky expanse of water, in which no fish or algae can survive. The shore is coated with a black crust, so thick you can walk on it. Into this huge, 10 sq km tailings pond nearby factories discharge water loaded with chemicals used to process the 17 most sought after minerals in the world, collectively known as <a class="u-underline" title="" href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2012/jan/27/rare-minerals-global-renewables-industry" data-link-name="in body link">rare earths</a>.</p>
<p>The town of <a class="u-underline" title="" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baotou" data-link-name="in body link">Baotou</a>, in Inner Mongolia, is the largest Chinese source of these strategic elements, essential to advanced technology, from smartphones to GPS receivers, but also to wind farms and, above all, electric cars. The minerals are mined at Bayan Obo, 120km farther north, then brought to Baotou for processing.</p>
<p>The concentration of rare earths in the ore is very low, so they must be separated and purified, using hydro-metallurgical techniques and acid baths. <a class="u-underline" href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/china" data-link-name="auto-linked-tag" data-component="auto-linked-tag">China</a> accounts for 97% of global output of these precious substances, with two-thirds produced in Baotou.</p>
<p>The foul waters of the tailings pond contain all sorts of toxic chemicals, but also radioactive elements such as thorium which, if ingested, cause cancers of the pancreas and lungs, and leukaemia. “Before the factories were built, there were just fields here as far as the eye can see. In the place of this radioactive sludge, there were watermelons, aubergines and tomatoes,” says Li Guirong with a sigh.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and vomit. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/evil-polluters/in-the-race-to-end-despoil-the-environment-china-wins-they-are-first-second-and-third/">In The Race To Despoil The Environment, China Wins &#8211; They are First, Second and Third</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/evil-polluters/in-the-race-to-end-despoil-the-environment-china-wins-they-are-first-second-and-third/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Do Not Have To Be A Weatherman To Know Which The Wind Blows</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/aquifer-damage/do-not-have-to-be-a-weatherman-to-know-which-the-wind-blows/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/aquifer-damage/do-not-have-to-be-a-weatherman-to-know-which-the-wind-blows/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 20:43:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[aquifer damage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burning behavior]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate change]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=8189</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>It ain&#8217;t good news. So I will just put them up. https://www.erienewsnow.com/story/42470351/canadian-ice-shelf-larger-than-manhattan-collapses-into-the-sea Canadian ice shelf larger than Manhattan collapses into the sea Saturday, August 8th 2020, 4:16 PM EDT Updated: Saturday, August 8th 2020, 4:16 PM EDT The size of &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/aquifer-damage/do-not-have-to-be-a-weatherman-to-know-which-the-wind-blows/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/aquifer-damage/do-not-have-to-be-a-weatherman-to-know-which-the-wind-blows/">Do Not Have To Be A Weatherman To Know Which The Wind Blows</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It ain&#8217;t good news. So I will just put them up.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.erienewsnow.com/story/42470351/canadian-ice-shelf-larger-than-manhattan-collapses-into-the-sea">https://www.erienewsnow.com/story/42470351/canadian-ice-shelf-larger-than-manhattan-collapses-into-the-sea</a></p>
<h1 class="Article-title">Canadian ice shelf larger than Manhattan collapses into the sea</h1>
<div class="Timestamp">
<div class="Timestamp-text"><span class="Timestamp-time">Saturday, August 8th 2020, 4:16 PM EDT</span></div>
</div>
<div class="Timestamp-updated"><span class="Timestamp Timestamp-prefix">Updated: </span></p>
<div class="Timestamp BylineSocialNetwork">
<div class="Timestamp-text"><span class="Timestamp-time">Saturday, August 8th 2020, 4:16 PM EDT</span></div>
</div>
</div>
<div>
<div class="Article-paragraph">
<p>The size of Canada&#8217;s last fully intact ice shelf was reduced by 43% over July 30 and 31 when the Milne Ice Shelf on Ellesmere Island in the northern territory of Nunavut collapsed into the ocean.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div>
<div class="Article-paragraph">
<p>This large sheet of ice then drifted into the Arctic Sea, further breaking into two large chunks. This entire calving event &#8212; the scientific term for the breaking of ice chunks off glaciers &#8212; was captured by the Copernicus Sentinel satellite.</p>
</div>
</div>
<div>
<div class="Article-paragraph">
<p>The piece that broke off was around 80 square kilometers &#8212; larger than the 60-square-kilometer Manhattan.</p>
</div>
</div>
<p>&#8220;Above-normal air temperatures, offshore winds and open water in front of the ice shelf are all part of the recipe for ice shelf break up,&#8221; according to the Canadian Ice Service.</p>
<p>AND THIS</p>
<p><a href="https://news.yahoo.com/heat-wave-bakes-california-more-123049167.html">https://news.yahoo.com/heat-wave-bakes-california-more-123049167.html</a></p>
<div data-reactid="22">
<div id="mrt-node-Lead-1-HeadComponentTitle" data-locator="subtree-root">
<div id="Lead-1-HeadComponentTitle-Proxy" data-reactroot="" data-reactid="1" data-react-checksum="1019721783">
<div data-reactid="2">
<header id="Lead-1-HeadComponentTitle" class="canvas-header" data-yaft-module="tdv2-applet-CommonHeader" data-reactid="3">
<h1 class="Lh(1.15) Fz(40px) Fz(36px)--modalMinWidth Mb(14px) Ff($ff-primary) Lts($lspacing-md) Fw($fweight) Fsm($fsmoothing) Fsmw($fsmoothing) Fsmm($fsmoothing) Wow(bw)" data-reactid="4">From &#8216;firenadoes&#8217; to record heat, California extreme weather a glimpse of future</h1>
</header>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div data-reactid="23">
<div id="mrt-node-Lead-2-HeadComponentAttribution" data-locator="subtree-root">
<div id="Lead-2-HeadComponentAttribution-Proxy" data-reactroot="" data-reactid="1" data-react-checksum="-2143120986">
<div id="Lead-2-HeadComponentAttribution" class="auth-attr W(100%) Mb(12px) Pos(r) Mah(75px) Mb(15px)" data-yaft-module="tdv2-applet-CommonAttribution" data-reactid="2">
<div class="auth-prov-logos D(tbc) Va(t) Pos(r) Mah(40px) Maw(70px)" data-reactid="3">
<div class="provider-logo Va(m) Pend(10px) Pos(a) Lh(25px)" data-reactid="4"><a href="https://www.latimes.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow" data-reactid="5"><img decoding="async" class=" H(a) Mah(40px)--sm Maw(40px)--sm Mah(40px) Maw(70px)" title="LA Times" src="https://media-mbst-pub-ue1.s3.amazonaws.com/creatr-uploaded-images/2020-02/f6e47060-4932-11ea-a7fe-c762a271bf55" width="auto" data-reactid="6" /></a></div>
</div>
<div class="auth-prov-soc Mend(4px) Va(m) D(tbc) Mah(45px) Mah(40px)--sm Maw(650px) Start(80px) Pos(r) Lh(36px) Fz(12px)" data-reactid="7">
<div class="author Mb(4px) D(ib) " data-reactid="8">
<div class="author-name Lh(18px) Td(n) Fw(b) Fz(12px) C(#000)" data-reactid="9">Tony Barboza, Louis Sahagun, Joseph Serna<span class="attrib-sep Mend(5px) Fx(13px)" aria-hidden="true" data-reactid="10">,</span></div>
</div>
<div class="D(ib)" data-reactid="11"><span class="provider Mb(4px)" data-reactid="12"><span class="provider-link" data-reactid="13"><a class="Fz(13px) C($c-fuji-grey-l)" href="https://www.latimes.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow" data-reactid="14">LA Times</a></span></span><i class="Mx(5px) C(#9ea2af)" aria-hidden="true" data-reactid="16">•</i><time class="date Fz(11px) Mb(4px) Fz(13px) C(#9ea2af)" datetime="2020-08-18T12:30:49.000Z" data-reactid="17">August 18, 2020</time></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div data-reactid="11"></div>
<div data-reactid="11">
<p>In the last few days, a moisture-laden heat wave has unleashed extreme weather in almost every corner of California.</p>
<p>In a single day, Northern California was hit with triple-digit temperatures, as well as hundreds of lightning strikes that ignited brush fires. The mercury hit 107 degrees Sunday in Santa Cruz, known for its moderate climate, and Death Valley reached 130 degrees — one of the hottest temperatures ever recorded there.</p>
</div>
<div data-reactid="11">
<p>Meanwhile, unusually muggy air made Los Angeles feel like Houston, and warm nights failed to offer much relief. The Central Valley sweltered with temperatures exceeding 110 degrees. A fire-caused tornado touched down near the Sierra Nevada community of Loyalton. And a pyrocumulus cloud towered over Southern California, where heat and wildfires pushed smog levels higher than they’ve been in years.</p>
<p>Did we mention the power went out too?</p>
</div>
<div data-reactid="11">:}</div>
<p>Go there and read. More Next week if I survive.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/aquifer-damage/do-not-have-to-be-a-weatherman-to-know-which-the-wind-blows/">Do Not Have To Be A Weatherman To Know Which The Wind Blows</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/aquifer-damage/do-not-have-to-be-a-weatherman-to-know-which-the-wind-blows/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Habitat Destruction Squeezes Diseases Out Of Mammals &#8211; Then they invade humans and kill us</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/bad-health-effects/habitat-destruction-squeezes-diseases-out-of-mammals-then-they-invade-humans-and-kill-us/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/bad-health-effects/habitat-destruction-squeezes-diseases-out-of-mammals-then-they-invade-humans-and-kill-us/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 20:51:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[aquifer damage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bad health effects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burning behavior]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dumb ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dying planet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evil polluters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[industry apologists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[military polluters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self inflicted wounds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smoke]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water pollution]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=8176</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Seriously, how long can it be before HUMANs realize that by killing the world in general they are killing themselves. Squeezing animals out of their habitats squeezes their viruses out into us. We have no immune defenses against them and &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/bad-health-effects/habitat-destruction-squeezes-diseases-out-of-mammals-then-they-invade-humans-and-kill-us/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/bad-health-effects/habitat-destruction-squeezes-diseases-out-of-mammals-then-they-invade-humans-and-kill-us/">Habitat Destruction Squeezes Diseases Out Of Mammals &#8211; Then they invade humans and kill us</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Seriously, how long can it be before HUMANs realize that by killing the world in general they are killing themselves. Squeezing animals out of their habitats squeezes their viruses out into us. We have no immune defenses against them and we die. I mean it is Earth&#8217;s ultimate defense system. I have a hunch we are not gonna be around for long. Wonder which one will get us first, Global Warming or Rejection by the Earth.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.npr.org/2020/06/22/875961137/the-worrisome-link-between-deforestation-and-disease?utm_source=digg">https://www.npr.org/2020/06/22/875961137/the-worrisome-link-between-deforestation-and-disease?utm_source=digg</a></p>
<div class="storytitle">
<h1>&#8216;Like Poking a Beehive&#8217;: The Worrisome Link Between Deforestation And Disease</h1>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div class="story-tools"></div>
<div id="story-meta" class="story-meta has-byline">
<div class="story-meta__one">
<div class="dateblock"><time datetime="2020-06-22T05:00:18-04:00"> <span class="date">June 22, 2020</span><span class="time">5:00 AM ET</span> </time></div>
</div>
<div class="story-meta__two">
<div id="storybyline" class="storybyline-wrap linkLocation">
<div id="res875961225" class="bucketwrap byline">
<div class="byline-container--block">
<div class="byline byline--block byline--has-link" aria-label="Byline">
<div class="byline__photo"><a href="https://www.npr.org/people/348779465/nathan-rott" rel="author" data-metrics="{&quot;action&quot;:&quot;Click Byline&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;Story Metadata&quot;}"> <img decoding="async" class="img" src="https://media.npr.org/assets/img/2018/11/13/npr_44975465_sq-38e71694e1e3718c8ba65398a1aeb229704f3c09-s100-c85.jpg" alt="Nathan Rott at NPR headquarters in Washington, D.C., September 27, 2018. (photo by Allison Shelley)" /> </a></div>
<p class="byline__name byline__name--block"><a href="https://www.npr.org/people/348779465/nathan-rott" rel="author" data-metrics="{&quot;action&quot;:&quot;Click Byline&quot;,&quot;category&quot;:&quot;Story Metadata&quot;}"> Nathan Rott </a></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>In 2013, an 18-month-old boy got sick after playing near a hollow tree in his backyard in a remote West African village. He developed a fever and started vomiting. His stool turned black. Two days later, he died.</p>
<p>Two years and more than 11,000 deaths later, the World Health Organization put out a <a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/goatsandsoda/2015/01/15/377517132/14-takeaways-from-the-14-part-who-report-on-ebola">report</a> saying the Ebola outbreak that likely emanated from that hollow tree may have been caused in part by deforestation led by &#8220;foreign mining and timber operations.&#8221;</p>
<p>The tree the boy played near was infested with insectivorous bats — bats that may have been pushed into the boy&#8217;s village because upward of 80% of their natural habitat had been destroyed.</p>
<p>&#8220;When you disturb a forest, it actually upsets, if you want, the balance of nature, the balance between pathogens and people,&#8221; says John E. Fa, a professor of biodiversity and human development at Manchester Metropolitan University, who was part of a team of researchers that <a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41598-017-14727-9">linked recent forest loss to 25 Ebola outbreaks</a> that have occurred since 1976.</p>
<p>A finding, he says, that showed a strong correlation between recent deforestation and disease outbreaks.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and Pray.  More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/bad-health-effects/habitat-destruction-squeezes-diseases-out-of-mammals-then-they-invade-humans-and-kill-us/">Habitat Destruction Squeezes Diseases Out Of Mammals &#8211; Then they invade humans and kill us</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/bad-health-effects/habitat-destruction-squeezes-diseases-out-of-mammals-then-they-invade-humans-and-kill-us/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>I WILL SAVE COAL &#8211; Shouted Donnie the Cheeto Burito from the roof tops</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/coal/i-will-save-coal-shouted-donnie-the-cheeto-burito-from-the-roof-tops/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/coal/i-will-save-coal-shouted-donnie-the-cheeto-burito-from-the-roof-tops/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 16:22:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[aquifer damage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bad health effects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big coal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burning behavior]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[industry apologists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[masters of the universe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smoke]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stupid old men]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=8139</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Donald J. Trump is the worst energy President of all time. That takes a lot of doing. Jimmie Carter was real bad on Nuclear Power. George Bush was seriously bad on natural gas and oil. But this alleged policy maker &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/coal/i-will-save-coal-shouted-donnie-the-cheeto-burito-from-the-roof-tops/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/coal/i-will-save-coal-shouted-donnie-the-cheeto-burito-from-the-roof-tops/">I WILL SAVE COAL &#8211; Shouted Donnie the Cheeto Burito from the roof tops</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Donald J. Trump is the worst energy President of all time. That takes a lot of doing. Jimmie Carter was real bad on Nuclear Power. George Bush was seriously bad on natural gas and oil. But this alleged policy maker pledged, during the the 2016 campaign, that he would SAVE coal. Under his Presidency the Coal Market has plummeted as has its usage. Even though foreign markets were promised, they have plunged too. Oil futures at one point were trading in negative territory for the first time ever and Nuclear Power Plants are closing. He is opposed to Wind and Solar as they <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wFHh0Rs34v0">spread across the land</a>. I have a wind turbine within 15 minutes of my house in Riverton and I have a house with total roof solar panels around the corner from me. That says to me that the Cheeto Burito is about to lose office. We shall see.</p>
<p><a href="https://thesouthern.com/news/local/southern-illinois-power-co-op-plans-to-shutter-its-largest-coal-fired-unit-this-fall/article_7ec9c134-48db-5448-953c-4a435aeddcd5.html?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=twitter&amp;utm_campaign=user-share">https://thesouthern.com/news/local/southern-illinois-power-co-op-plans-to-shutter-its-largest-coal-fired-unit-this-fall/article_7ec9c134-48db-5448-953c-4a435aeddcd5.html?utm_medium=social&amp;utm_source=twitter&amp;utm_campaign=user-share</a></p>
<h1 class="headline">Southern Illinois Power Co-op plans to shutter its largest coal-fired unit this fall</h1>
<div class="meta">
<ul class="list-inline">
<li><span id="author-105c3ed8-3ec6-11e4-9975-eb3b9e23621e-asset-7ec9c134-48db-5448-953c-4a435aeddcd5" class="tnt-byline asset-byline"> <a href="https://thesouthern.com/users/profile/mollyjaneparker"> Molly Parker </a> </span></li>
<li class="hidden-print"><time class="tnt-date asset-date text-muted" datetime="2020-06-08T16:48:00-05:00"> Jun 8, 2020 </time><span class="text-muted">Updated </span><time class="tnt-date asset-date text-muted" datetime="2020-06-10T16:08:08-05:00">17 hrs ago</time></li>
</ul>
</div>
<div class="lee-article-text first-p">
<p>MARION — Southern Illinois Power Cooperative plans to retire its largest coal-fired generator as early as this fall, a move that is expected to save $125 million over a decade.</p>
</div>
<div class="lee-article-text">
<p>President and CEO Don Gulley said the tentative decision is the result of analysis and negotiations that have been ongoing since late 2019. Gulley said SIPC utilized outside consultants to help it perform a comprehensive review of operations and determine the best path forward. The decision to close Unit 4, as it is known, was based on two primary factors, he said: sustained low energy prices in the wholesale power market, and increasingly costly environmental regulations for coal-fired generators.</p>
</div>
<div class="asset-breakout-container "></div>
<div class="inline-asset inline-article  p402_hide subscriber-only tnt-inline-asset tnt-inline-relcontent tnt-inline-article tnt-inline-relation-sibling tnt-inline-presentation-headline tnt-inline-alignment-right tnt-inline-width-half">
<h5 class="tnt-headline "></h5>
</div>
<div class="inline-asset inline-article  p402_hide subscriber-only tnt-inline-asset tnt-inline-relcontent tnt-inline-article tnt-inline-relation-sibling tnt-inline-presentation-headline tnt-inline-alignment-right tnt-inline-width-half">
<h5 class="tnt-headline "><a class="tnt-asset-link" href="https://thesouthern.com/news/local/govt-and-politics/perspectives-on-progress-illinois-rep-la-shawn-ford-shares-thoughts-on-crisis-in-black-communities/article_6d1f5ad7-f46c-5d6a-9a8b-fbf90f4b8d33.html"> Perspectives on Progress: Illinois Rep. La Shawn Ford shares thoughts on ‘crisis’ in black communities</a></h5>
</div>
<div class="lee-article-text">
<p>As a result, up to 26 of the plant’s 82 employees are expected to face layoffs. Those employees are to receive a severance package under the terms of an agreement ratified by the IBEW Local 702, which represents workers, Gulley said.</p>
</div>
<div class="lee-article-text">
<p>SIPC is a generation and transmission cooperative located on the shores of Lake of Egypt that provides wholesale electric power to seven member distribution cooperatives, and the city of McLeansboro. It is jointly owned and governed by the distribution cooperatives, which are: Egyptian Electric Cooperative Association; Clinton County Electric Cooperative, Inc.; Monroe County Electric Co-Operative, Inc.; SouthEastern Illinois Electric Cooperative, Inc.; Southern Illinois Electric Cooperative; Tri-County Electric Cooperative, Inc.; and Clay Electric Co-operative, Inc.</p>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/coal/i-will-save-coal-shouted-donnie-the-cheeto-burito-from-the-roof-tops/">I WILL SAVE COAL &#8211; Shouted Donnie the Cheeto Burito from the roof tops</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/coal/i-will-save-coal-shouted-donnie-the-cheeto-burito-from-the-roof-tops/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>I Am So Excited To Be Posting On Earth Day &#8211; The 50th Anniversary</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/bad-health-effects/i-am-so-excited-to-be-posting-on-earth-day-the-50th-anniversary/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/bad-health-effects/i-am-so-excited-to-be-posting-on-earth-day-the-50th-anniversary/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 19:09:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[air pollution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aquifer damage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bad health effects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big coal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big oil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burning behavior]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dying planet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evil polluters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[factory farming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[global warming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lies told by energy companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[over population]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self inflicted wounds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water pollution]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=8093</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>That&#8217;s it. That&#8217;s all I can say. Well you know me, that&#8217;s not all I can say. Like the National Geographic Magazine says, they are divided about the results. We have accomplished alot but never enough because the root cause &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/bad-health-effects/i-am-so-excited-to-be-posting-on-earth-day-the-50th-anniversary/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/bad-health-effects/i-am-so-excited-to-be-posting-on-earth-day-the-50th-anniversary/">I Am So Excited To Be Posting On Earth Day &#8211; The 50th Anniversary</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>That&#8217;s it. That&#8217;s all I can say. Well you know me, that&#8217;s not all I can say. Like the National Geographic Magazine says, they are divided about the results. We have accomplished alot but never enough because the root cause of climate change is evil greed, better known as capitalism. As long as we practice those economics, we will continue down the drain. The drain that looks like this:</p>
<p><a href="https://newrepublic.com/article/157078/climate-crisis-will-just-shockingly-abrupt?utm_source=digg">https://newrepublic.com/article/157078/climate-crisis-will-just-shockingly-abrupt?utm_source=digg</a></p>
<div class="article-title" data-reactid="103">
<h1 class="article-headline" data-reactid="104"><span data-reactid="105">The Climate Crisis Will Be Just as Shockingly Abrupt</span></h1>
<h2 class="article-subhead" data-reactid="106"><span data-reactid="107">The coronavirus isn’t a reason to put climate policy on hold. It’s a warning of the calamities ahead.</span></h2>
</div>
<div class="article-meta" data-reactid="108">
<div class="author-list author-list-all author-list-inline" data-reactid="110"><span data-reactid="111">By </span><span class="author-list-item" data-reactid="112"><a class="author-melody-schreiber author-link" title="Melody Schreiber" href="https://newrepublic.com/authors/melody-schreiber" data-reactid="113">Melody Schreiber</a></span></div>
<h5 class="article-date" data-reactid="115"><time datetime="2020-03-27" data-reactid="116">March 27, 2020</time></h5>
</div>
<p>As governments around the globe debate how to respond both to the coronavirus itself and the economic chaos it has unleashed, a theme that’s come up over and over is how to prioritize what makes it into spending packages. In the United States, right-left fault lines have emerged over the question of bailing out emissions-heavy industries versus <a href="https://newrepublic.com/article/156903/golden-opportunity-green-stimulus">a greener stimulus</a>. On Thursday, the Environmental Protection Agency <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/03/26/climate/epa-coronavirus-pollution-rules.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">announced</a> a large-scale rollback of environmental regulations as a response to the pandemic—allowing many emitters to police themselves when it comes to pollution.</p>
<p>While <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/s/615338/coronavirus-emissions-climate-change/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">some argue</a> that the oxygen in the climate debate should be taken up by the pandemic instead, the two issues aren’t mutually exclusive, experts say. In a warming climate, <a href="https://newrepublic.com/article/155746/climate-change-already-hurting-kids-health">more diseases are likely to emerge and spread</a>, making climate change action an important part of addressing future health crises. Moreover, the perception that climate change isn’t as urgent as other crises may rely on misunderstandings about how climate-related changes will happen. The rate isn’t constant: Instead, there’s reason to believe everything from Arctic melt to Amazon deforestation might experience what’s known as “tipping points,” where small changes in nature shift into rapid and irreversible damage.</p>
<p>Greenland and Antarctica are melting six times faster than they were in the 1990s, according to a <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/feature/jpl/greenland-antarctica-melting-six-times-faster-than-in-the-1990s" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">new study</a> in the journal <i>Nature.</i> Between 1992 and 2017, Greenland and Antarctica lost 6.4 trillion tons of ice. This falls under the <a href="https://www.ipcc.ch/srocc/chapter/summary-for-policymakers/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">worst-case scenario</a> projected by the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change, and the effects are already being felt in many parts of the world. The IPCC predicts that by the end of the century, 400 million people around the globe could be at risk of coastal flooding every year from sea-level rise alone.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/bad-health-effects/i-am-so-excited-to-be-posting-on-earth-day-the-50th-anniversary/">I Am So Excited To Be Posting On Earth Day &#8211; The 50th Anniversary</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/bad-health-effects/i-am-so-excited-to-be-posting-on-earth-day-the-50th-anniversary/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Climate Change Is Like A Paperclip &#8211; You can bend it however you like</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/burning-behavior/climate-change-is-like-a-paperclip-you-can-bend-it-however-you-like/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/burning-behavior/climate-change-is-like-a-paperclip-you-can-bend-it-however-you-like/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 19:08:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[aquifer damage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big oil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big whoop dee do]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burning behavior]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[global warming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[industry apologists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lies told by energy companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=7997</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>According to the Pipeline Companies and many others in or around the Fossil Fuel Industry, Climate Change is ILL DEFINED. If it hadn&#8217;t happened in Illinois I would be laughing but now I am close to puking. The world is &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/burning-behavior/climate-change-is-like-a-paperclip-you-can-bend-it-however-you-like/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burning-behavior/climate-change-is-like-a-paperclip-you-can-bend-it-however-you-like/">Climate Change Is Like A Paperclip &#8211; You can bend it however you like</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>According to the Pipeline Companies and many others in or around the Fossil Fuel Industry, Climate Change is ILL DEFINED. If it hadn&#8217;t happened in Illinois I would be laughing but now I am close to puking. The world is going to be on fire, literally. They will be saying, &#8220;what fire it&#8217;s just a little warm&#8221;. They said this in front of the Illinois Commerce Commission no less. I think it has become so apparent that the Anthropocene&#8217;s purpose is the death of the planet, that they just don&#8217;t care what they say anymore. We are doomed &#8211; what does it matter. Well it matters to me. They must be held responsible.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/powerpost/paloma/the-energy-202/2019/11/13/the-energy-202-dakota-access-operators-call-climate-change-undefined-vague-and-ambiguous-in-official-filing/5dcaed9f602ff1184c316408/">https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/powerpost/paloma/the-energy-202/2019/11/13/the-energy-202-dakota-access-operators-call-climate-change-undefined-vague-and-ambiguous-in-official-filing/5dcaed9f602ff1184c316408/</a></p>
<section id="top-content" class="col-xs-12 layout">
<div id="fOOCaD19pk7BBr" class="moat-trackable pb-f-theme-normal pb-f-dehydrate-false pb-f-async-false full pb-feature pb-layout-item pb-f-article-article-topper" data-chain-name="no-name" data-feature-name="no-name" data-feature-id="article/article-topper" data-pb-fingerprint="0fu6oNbtApF">
<div class="border-bottom-off border-bottom-">
<div id="article-topper" class="article-topper ">
<div id="topper-headline-wrapper">
<div class="topper-headline">
<h1 data-pb-field="custom.topperDisplayName">The Energy 202: Dakota Access operators call climate change &#8216;undefined, vague, and ambiguous&#8217; in official filing</h1>
</div>
</div>
<div class="clear"></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="pb-container"></div>
</section>
<section id="main-content" class="col-xl-9 col-lg-8 col-md-8 col-sm-12 col-xs-12 col-xs-offset-0 col-sm-offset-0 col-md-offset-0 col-lg-offset-0 layout">
<div id="f0ldW7H9pk7BBr" class="moat-trackable pb-f-theme-normal pb-f-dehydrate-false pb-f-async-false full pb-feature pb-layout-item pb-f-article-article-deck" data-chain-name="no-name" data-feature-name="no-name" data-feature-id="article/article-deck" data-pb-fingerprint="0fIqrDYLJp8"></div>
<div id="f0yb6BA9pk7BBr" class="moat-trackable pb-f-theme-normal pb-f-dehydrate-false pb-f-async-false full pb-feature pb-layout-item pb-f-article-article-body" data-chain-name="no-name" data-feature-name="no-name" data-feature-id="article/article-body" data-pb-fingerprint="0fS6oNbtApp">
<div id="article-body" class="article-body content-format-default">
<div class="author-sig-line-wrapper analysis-story">
<div class="author-headshot"><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/people/dino-grandoni/"> <img decoding="async" class="_1-to-1 hi-res-lazy courtesy-of-the-lazy-loader" src="https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/VNxexgzv8gRn1j8mh7v4cdzMins=/90x90/s3.amazonaws.com/arc-authors/washpost/5d5af932-fb88-40ba-bc26-01198615e878.png" data-hi-res-src="https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/VNxexgzv8gRn1j8mh7v4cdzMins=/90x90/s3.amazonaws.com/arc-authors/washpost/5d5af932-fb88-40ba-bc26-01198615e878.png" data-low-res-src="https://www.washingtonpost.com/resizer/hK4T5Gj2Pq73bEPKrMWyhKsoEGw=/29x29/s3.amazonaws.com/arc-authors/washpost/5d5af932-fb88-40ba-bc26-01198615e878.png" data-raw-src="https://s3.amazonaws.com/arc-authors/washpost/5d5af932-fb88-40ba-bc26-01198615e878.png" data-threshold="29" /> </a></div>
<div class="author-sig-line">
<div class="author-byline-wrapper arrow-left-moved">
<div class="author-byline">By <a class="author-name" href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/people/dino-grandoni/"> Dino Grandoni</a></div>
</div>
<div class="author-wrapper arrow-left-moved" data-authorname="Dino Grandoni"><span class="author-timestamp">November 13</span></div>
</div>
</div>
<article><strong>THE LIGHTBULB</strong></article>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<p dir="ltr">The operators of the Dakota Access pipeline seemed to brush aside concerns about global warming and the effects it may have on their business in an official filing, saying the phrase “climate change” is “undefined, vague, and ambiguous.”</p>
<p dir="ltr">That comment, filed in August with regulators in Illinois, comes as the pipeline’s operators try to more than double the capacity of the crude oil conduit — and as environmentalists still rail against the pipeline that has become a flash point over fossil-fuel infrastructure in the United States. The Obama administration held up the Dakota Access pipeline after months of protests from environmentalists and Native Americans only for President Trump to greenlight the project once taking office in 2017.</p>
<p dir="ltr">The pipeline’s operators are seeking permission from Illinois to add a new pump station to move extra oil in the 1,900-mile pipeline system of which the Dakota Access pipeline is a part.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burning-behavior/climate-change-is-like-a-paperclip-you-can-bend-it-however-you-like/">Climate Change Is Like A Paperclip &#8211; You can bend it however you like</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/burning-behavior/climate-change-is-like-a-paperclip-you-can-bend-it-however-you-like/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pollute Till People Die _ Why does every developing Nation have to go through this</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/burning-behavior/pollute-till-people-die-_-why-does-every-developing-nation-have-to-go-through-this/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/burning-behavior/pollute-till-people-die-_-why-does-every-developing-nation-have-to-go-through-this/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 17:44:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[air pollution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aquifer damage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bad health effects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big coal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big oil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burning behavior]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[coal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dumb ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dying planet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evil polluters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fossil fuels and the United States' Future]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mountain top destruction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[over population]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pollution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smoke]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water pollution]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=7989</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Pollute till rivers catch fire.(like America) Pollute till people die and slums burn down. (like England) Blow up a Nuclear Power Plant. (like the Soviet Union or Japan) Pollute until thousands die. (like India). But does India Come around after &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/burning-behavior/pollute-till-people-die-_-why-does-every-developing-nation-have-to-go-through-this/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burning-behavior/pollute-till-people-die-_-why-does-every-developing-nation-have-to-go-through-this/">Pollute Till People Die _ Why does every developing Nation have to go through this</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Pollute till rivers catch fire.(like America) Pollute till people die and slums burn down. (like England) Blow up a Nuclear Power Plant. (like the Soviet Union or Japan) Pollute until thousands die. (like India). But does India Come around after Bhopal. Hell no!</p>
<p>There is this:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.dw.com/en/new-delhi-schools-closed-as-air-pollution-worsens/a-51235841">https://www.dw.com/en/new-delhi-schools-closed-as-air-pollution-worsens/a-51235841</a></p>
<p>Then there is this:</p>
<h4>DW recommends</h4>
<div class="group">
<div class="lineExtra"></div>
<div class="linkList intern">
<h2>Amitav Ghosh: What the West doesn&#8217;t get about the climate crisis</h2>
<p>The new novel by award-winning Indian author Amitav Ghosh, Gun Island, uses climate change as a backdrop. He tells DW about the different perceptions of the climate crisis in the East and West. (06.11.2019)</p>
</div>
<div class="linkList intern">
<h2>India: Delhi restricts car use as toxic smog covers city</h2>
<p>Vehicle restrictions have been introduced in and around the Indian capital, New Delhi, as part of an effort to cut soaring levels of air pollution. Private cars will be allowed on the roads on alternate days. (04.11.2019)</p>
</div>
<div class="linkList intern">
<h2>India pollution: How a farming revolution could solve stubble burning</h2>
<p>Pollution in Delhi has hit record-breaking levels and a farming method, known as stubble burning, was a major contributor. DW&#8217;s Catherine Davison went to the countryside to check out what&#8217;s being done to stop this trend. (08.11.2019)</p>
</div>
<div class="linkList overlayIcon">
<h2>New Delhi chokes under blanket of smog</h2>
<p>Indian authorities have imposed new restrictions on private cars in the capital to try and bring down pollution levels. The blanket of smog led Delhi&#8217;s chief minister to compare the city to a gas chamber. (04</p>
</div>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read and read and read. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burning-behavior/pollute-till-people-die-_-why-does-every-developing-nation-have-to-go-through-this/">Pollute Till People Die _ Why does every developing Nation have to go through this</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/burning-behavior/pollute-till-people-die-_-why-does-every-developing-nation-have-to-go-through-this/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
