<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>airforce Archives - Community Energy Systems</title>
	<atom:link href="/censys/category/blog/airforce/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/censys/category/blog/airforce/</link>
	<description>Censys.org</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 19:38:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Commercial Airplanes Are A Huge Cause Of Global Warming &#8211; People say no way</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/commercial-airplanes-are-a-huge-cause-of-global-warming-people-say-no-way/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/commercial-airplanes-are-a-huge-cause-of-global-warming-people-say-no-way/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 16:01:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[advanced energy structures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[batteries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burn free generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cool sites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electricity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environmentalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transportation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=7914</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Her is why I say that Airplanes are the prime culprits of Global Warming. First: They Fly High. While fossil fueled Power Plants and Surface Transport Fleets emit huge green house gases many of them are mitigated before they can &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/commercial-airplanes-are-a-huge-cause-of-global-warming-people-say-no-way/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/commercial-airplanes-are-a-huge-cause-of-global-warming-people-say-no-way/">Commercial Airplanes Are A Huge Cause Of Global Warming &#8211; People say no way</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Her is why I say that Airplanes are the prime culprits of Global Warming. First: They Fly High. While fossil fueled Power Plants and Surface Transport Fleets emit huge green house gases many of them are mitigated before they can have much of a green house effect. But most jets fly right up there. I mean even some prop planes do too.</p>
<p>Second: The Fuel. Especially military flight fuel is bloody near kerosene.</p>
<p>Third: There are so many. It may be a myth but after 911 when so many planes were grounded the tempeture dropped a degree.</p>
<p>So this is kinda cool. Maybe we should call them personal air taxi&#8217;s or something. Yes they will be expensive. So what.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.vox.com/2019/5/14/18535971/electric-airplane-aircraft-aviation-clean-energy">https://www.vox.com/2019/5/14/18535971/electric-airplane-aircraft-aviation-clean-energy</a></p>
<div class="c-entry-hero__header-wrap">
<h1 class="c-page-title">Aircraft fuel is notoriously dirty. This airline is betting on clean electricity.</h1>
</div>
<p class="c-entry-summary p-dek">Harbour Air wants to become the world’s first all-electric airline and start flying passengers by 2022.</p>
<div class="c-byline">By <span class="c-byline__item"> <a href="https://www.vox.com/authors/umair-irfan">Umair Irfan</a> </span> <span class="c-byline__item"> <time class="c-byline__item" datetime="2019-05-14T16:30:00+00:00" data-ui="timestamp"> May 14, 2019, 12:30pm EDT </time></span></div>
<p id="khu5UD">It’s becoming increasingly difficult to ignore the fact that air travel is a massive and growing problem for the global climate.</p>
<p id="e0cf0M">In the US, transportation is now the largest source of greenhouse gas emissions, and aircraft account for <a href="https://www.epa.gov/regulations-emissions-vehicles-and-engines/regulations-greenhouse-gas-emissions-aircraft">12 percent</a> of transportation emissions. <a href="https://www.bts.dot.gov/newsroom/2018-traffic-data-us-airlines-and-foreign-airlines-us-flights">US air travel</a> reached a record high last year, pushing up overall <a href="https://www.vox.com/2019/1/8/18174082/us-carbon-emissions-2018">emissions</a> even while the power sector saw a decline.</p>
<p id="P7RqPM">To make matters worse, demand for flights is growing. Emissions from air travel are poised to spike up to <a href="https://ec.europa.eu/clima/policies/transport/aviation_en">sevenfold</a> globally by 2050 if nothing else changes.</p>
<p id="w6PQSS">That’s why it’s so urgent to decarbonize air travel. Yet the technical challenges are immense. Alternatives like carbon-neutral biofuels remain far too costly. And the stodgy rules in the heavily regulated, risk-averse aviation sector lag far behind advances in electric drivetrains.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>They are currently flying small electric planes on a regional basis.</p>
<p>Go there and see the future. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/commercial-airplanes-are-a-huge-cause-of-global-warming-people-say-no-way/">Commercial Airplanes Are A Huge Cause Of Global Warming &#8211; People say no way</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/commercial-airplanes-are-a-huge-cause-of-global-warming-people-say-no-way/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Solar That Comes With Batteries &#8211; What a thought</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/solar-that-comes-with-batteries-what-a-thought/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/solar-that-comes-with-batteries-what-a-thought/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 20:18:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[airforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big whoop dee do]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burn free generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electricity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy Tough Love Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flying high]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[masters of the universe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[military]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[penetrating ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scarcity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[socialism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar power]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=5885</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Let me say, right off the bat, there are other better storage mechanisms then batteries. But if this becomes a market trend, well then whatever. http://energy.sandia.gov/installation-of-new-englands-largest-battery-energy-storage-system-is-underway/ Installation of New England’s Largest Battery Energy Storage System is Underway NEC Energy Solutions &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/solar-that-comes-with-batteries-what-a-thought/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/solar-that-comes-with-batteries-what-a-thought/">Solar That Comes With Batteries &#8211; What a thought</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Let me say, right off the bat, there are other better storage mechanisms then batteries. But if this becomes a market trend, well then whatever.</p>
<p>http://energy.sandia.gov/installation-of-new-englands-largest-battery-energy-storage-system-is-underway/</p>
<div class="fusion-flexslider flexslider post-slideshow fusion-post-slideshow"></div>
<h2 class="entry-title fusion-post-title" data-fontsize="18" data-lineheight="27">Installation of New England’s Largest Battery Energy Storage System is Underway</h2>
<div class="post-content">
<p>NEC Energy Solutions has begun the installation and commissioning of a 2 MW, 3.9MWh GSS® grid energy storage solution for the Sterling Municipal Light Department (SMLD) in Sterling, Massachusetts. Once complete in December 2016, it will be the largest system of its kind installed in New England and the first utility scale project in the State. In the event of an extended grid outage due to a natural disaster, this utility scale Battery Energy Storage System (BESS) can be used to power local emergency response facilities using power generated from two nearby solar plants. The system will also provide enhanced clean energy usage and cost savings to the town of Sterling.</p>
<p>Sandia provided SMLD with analysis to identify the optimal deployment site, amount, and installation type of energy storage within budgetary limits. Sandia also assisted with crafting a Request for Proposals (RFP) for the BESS system, vetting bids, and installing and dispatching the system. “Sandia was instrumental in helping us pull that together. We had developed a minor RFP and they brought in the technical support that we needed to get this done right. Working with Dan Borneo and Ray Byrne on this project has been very valuable to us,” said Sean Hamilton, General Manager of SMLD.</p>
<p>Going forward, Sandia will help SMLD oversee the operation of the BESS to optimally maximize economic returns while safeguarding SMLD’s ability to provide resilient power; monitor BESS operations; and collect operational data for one-year post-commissioning. The data will be used to further the U.S. Department of Energy’s/Sandia’s understanding of the benefits and applications of battery storage in the utility context and provide a number of important battery use cases in resiliency, cost savings, and revenues that can be adopted by numerous municipal utilities and vertically integrated utilities.</p>
</div>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read. But there ain&#8217;t much more. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/solar-that-comes-with-batteries-what-a-thought/">Solar That Comes With Batteries &#8211; What a thought</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/solar-that-comes-with-batteries-what-a-thought/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>If the whole world used these &#8211; Global warming would go away</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/if-the-whole-world-used-these-global-warming-would-go-away/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/if-the-whole-world-used-these-global-warming-would-go-away/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 17:53:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[air pollution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burn free generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy blogs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy Tough Love Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environmental blogs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[global warming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green airplanes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[masters of the universe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[penetrating ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wind power]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=4343</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>It is my firm belief that most of the global warming occurring is the direct result of world wide aircraft activity: military, commercial and personal. While it is true that the carbon uptake systems world wide have been compromised or &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/if-the-whole-world-used-these-global-warming-would-go-away/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/if-the-whole-world-used-these-global-warming-would-go-away/">If the whole world used these &#8211; Global warming would go away</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It is my firm belief that most of the global warming occurring is the direct result of world wide aircraft activity: military, commercial and personal. While it is true that the carbon uptake systems world wide have been compromised or broken by our general production of carbon, it is the relentless daily flights through the atmosphere using combustion engines that are doing the bulk of the atmospheric damage.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20120921-lighter-than-air-craft-rises">http://www.bbc.com/future/story/20120921-lighter-than-air-craft-rises</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.bbc.com/future/columns/hyperdrive">HyperDrive</a> | 24 September 2012</p>
<h1>Lighter-than-air craft rise again</h1>
<div>Jon Stewart</div>
<p>f you like the idea of cruising on a ship in laid-back luxury, but prefer the speed and convenience of air travel, there may soon be a solution. Drawing their inspiration from the airships of yesteryear, a new generation of airship-like vehicles could soon be making their way across our skies.</p>
<p>In a hangar outside Tustin in California, engineers are preparing one of the most radical designs for testing.  The Aeroscraft, as it is known, is the brainchild of Igor Pasternak and has been made possible by advances in materials and computer control systems.</p>
<p>“We are resurrecting [the airship] with new composite fabric structures, that are stronger, lighter, more versatile” says Fred Edworthy, of <a href="http://www.aeroscraft.com/">Aeros</a>, the company building the lighter-than-air vehicle.</p>
<p>The airship in the hangar is being built to test various key components of a design that could one day contain a hotel, casino or spa. However, the company believes one of its biggest markets could be transporting freight from hard-to-reach locations or, for example, carrying wind turbine blades. Currently blades are as large as they can be to be transported on a truck.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read. More tomorrow.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/if-the-whole-world-used-these-global-warming-would-go-away/">If the whole world used these &#8211; Global warming would go away</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/if-the-whole-world-used-these-global-warming-would-go-away/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Curiosity Lands On Mars &#8211; Sometimes reality intrudes on this blog</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/burning-behavior/curiosity-lands-on-mars-sometimes-reality-intrudes-on-this-blog/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/burning-behavior/curiosity-lands-on-mars-sometimes-reality-intrudes-on-this-blog/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 15:58:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[airforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big whoop dee do]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burning behavior]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dying planet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy Tough Love Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environmentalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[masters of the universe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mission in Space]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[playing hooky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spirituality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stewardship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=4212</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Sometimes there are things that are just as important as energy distribution/consumption and the environment in general. Sometimes an event is so large that you have to at least acknowledge that it happened. Such was the case of the death &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/burning-behavior/curiosity-lands-on-mars-sometimes-reality-intrudes-on-this-blog/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burning-behavior/curiosity-lands-on-mars-sometimes-reality-intrudes-on-this-blog/">Curiosity Lands On Mars &#8211; Sometimes reality intrudes on this blog</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sometimes there are things that are just as important as energy distribution/consumption and the environment in general. Sometimes an event is so large that you have to at least acknowledge that it happened. Such was the case of the death of Princess Dianah or Hurricane Katrina. So it is with the landing of the Curiosity MARs Probe. It is nuclear powered and this blog does not care for that. It extends capitalism&#8217;s mythology that humans have unlimited capacity to expand, thus unlimited markets to exploit. Still there is so much to learn and so little time as our planet heats up. So while this is just a little text. It is so much more than that.</p>
<p><a href="http://news.yahoo.com/photos/nasa-s-newest-mars-rover-slideshow/">http://news.yahoo.com/photos/nasa-s-newest-mars-rover-slideshow/</a></p>
<div>
<ol>
<li id="yui-gen45">
<div>
<h2>
<div>This  image released on Tuesday Aug. 7,2012 by NASA shows the first color  view of the north wall and rim of Gale Crater where NASA&#8217;s rover  Curiosity landed Sunday night. The picture was taken by the rover&#8217;s  camera at the end of its stowed robotic arm and appears fuzzy because of  dust on the camera&#8217;s cover. (AP Photo/NASA)</div>
</h2>
</div>
</li>
<li id="yui-gen40">
<div>
<h2>
<div>NASA&#8217;s  Mars rover Curiosity snapped this picture of Mount Sharp with its front  Hazard Avoidance camera, or Hazcam. The photo was released by NASA on  Aug. 6, 2012.</div>
</h2>
</div>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
<div id="yui_3_5_1_1_1344354968136_574">
<div id="yui_3_5_1_1_1344354968136_434">
<div id="spotlight-related">
<div>
<ol>
<li id="yui-gen41">
<div>
<div id="sptlgt-meta-related">
<ul>
<li>
<h3>Related Article</h3>
<p><a href="http://news.yahoo.com/mars-rover-curiosity-snaps-photo-craters-mysterious-mountain-005531743.html">Mars Rover Curiosity Snaps Photo of Crater&#8217;s Mysterious Mountain</a></li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and see all the pretty pictures. I know I did. More tomorrow.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burning-behavior/curiosity-lands-on-mars-sometimes-reality-intrudes-on-this-blog/">Curiosity Lands On Mars &#8211; Sometimes reality intrudes on this blog</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/burning-behavior/curiosity-lands-on-mars-sometimes-reality-intrudes-on-this-blog/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Electric Airplanes &#8211; Yes they almost can</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/funny/electric-airplanes-yes-they-almost-can/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/funny/electric-airplanes-yes-they-almost-can/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2012 15:48:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[airforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electricity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy Tough Love Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flying high]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green airplanes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[masters of the universe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[physics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spirituality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stewardship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water conservation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wind power]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=4080</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>They are small and slow, but they don&#8217;t go far. Still it is an interesting development. I mean I do not see electric 707s anytime in the future, but for enthusiasts like with the ultra lights, it has to be &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/funny/electric-airplanes-yes-they-almost-can/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/funny/electric-airplanes-yes-they-almost-can/">Electric Airplanes &#8211; Yes they almost can</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>They are small and slow, but they don&#8217;t go far. Still it is an interesting development. I mean I do not see electric 707s anytime in the future, but for enthusiasts like with the ultra lights, it has to be an exciting time. Did I mention you have to have a fairly good sized body of water to take off and land?</p>
<p><a href="http://digg.com/newsbar/topnews/it_s_an_airplane_it_s_a_jet_ski_it_s_the_electric_flynano">http://digg.com/newsbar/topnews/it_s_an_airplane_it_s_a_jet_ski_it_s_the_electric_flynano</a></p>
<h1>It’s an Airplane, It’s a Jet Ski, It’s the Electric FlyNano</h1>
<ul>
<li>By <a href="http://www.wired.com/autopia/author/jasonpaur/">Jason Paur</a></li>
<li><a title="Email the Author" href="mailto:paurjason@gmail.com%3C/a%3E">Email Author</a></li>
<li> June 21, 2012 |</li>
<li> 6:15 am</li>
</ul>
<p>The newest electric airplane to make its first flight is squarely  aimed at recreational fliers, even those without a pilot’s license. The  FlyNano turned some heads at last year’s Aero Friedrichshafen aviation  trade show in Germany thanks to <a href="http://www.wired.com/autopia/2011/04/flynano-personal-aircraft/">its interesting design</a>. The FlyNano is a miniature electric flying boat, making it essentially an airborne jet ski.</p>
<p>The original airplane was going to have a gas engine powerplant, but  the Finnish company says the ever-improving electric motors and  batteries means FlyNano will be an all-electric airplane moving forward.</p>
<p>The first flight was a very short one, just a handful of seconds. And the airplane didn’t really get out of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ground_effect_%28aircraft%29">ground effect</a>.  The wing area looks rather small for an electric airplane compared to  other models we’ve seen, which tend to have the efficient,  higher-aspect-ratio wings typical of sailplanes.</p>
<p>The designer claims a 10,000-foot ceiling for the airplane, but that  might be a bit optimistic with the current setup. FlyNano says it will  continue flight testing throughout the summer. We’re looking forward to  seeing longer and higher flights, though the FlyNano could be fun as an  aircraft designed to fly in ground effect.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/funny/electric-airplanes-yes-they-almost-can/">Electric Airplanes &#8211; Yes they almost can</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/funny/electric-airplanes-yes-they-almost-can/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Military Understands Peak Oil And Global Warming &#8211; But conservatives not so much</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/global-warming/the-military-understands-peak-oil-and-global-warming-but-conservatives-not-so-much/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/global-warming/the-military-understands-peak-oil-and-global-warming-but-conservatives-not-so-much/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2012 17:31:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[advanced energy structures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biofuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy conservation measures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy Tough Love Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flying high]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[global warming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[masters of the universe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[military]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[military polluters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pollution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar power]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[useless energy use]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water pollution]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=3979</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I am only going to post a little bit of this article. This is so in part because I have serious trouble calling killers of humans environmentalists. Still the point is that if all the militaries in the world just &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/global-warming/the-military-understands-peak-oil-and-global-warming-but-conservatives-not-so-much/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/global-warming/the-military-understands-peak-oil-and-global-warming-but-conservatives-not-so-much/">The Military Understands Peak Oil And Global Warming &#8211; But conservatives not so much</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am only going to post a little bit of this article. This is so in part because I have serious trouble calling killers of humans environmentalists. Still the point is that if all the militaries in the world just quit using any fuel tomorrow the price of all those fuels would crash and stay very low in price for a very long time. So here is a very little bit of a very good article. I mean really anything that gets Inhofe to pound on his table is a very good thing indeed.</p>
<h1>The Real Reason the Military is Going Green</h1>
<div>Big Oil is a big risk for national security. Can our military—the world&#8217;s No. 1 oil guzzler—change the politics of climate change?</div>
<div></div>
<div>by <a href="http://www.yesmagazine.org/@@also-by?author=Natalie+Pompilio">Natalie Pompilio</a></div>
<div>posted Jun 04, 2012</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Retired Brig. Gen. Steven Anderson calls himself  “an accidental environmentalist.”</p>
<p>His epiphany about climate change started with a tactical problem. In 2006 and 2007, when he served as the military’s chief logistician in Iraq, he coordinated the transport of millions of gallons of fuel across the country to power everything from vehicles to the large compressors used to cool individual tents—or, as Anderson puts it, for “air conditioning the desert.” He was taking one casualty for every 24 fuel convoys, and he was doing 18 convoys a day. That’s one casualty every other day. He needed to get the trucks off the road. He needed to find a way to reduce the military’s fuel use.</p>
<div>The question remains, can the weight and pragmatism of military leadership sway political leaders in Washington?</div>
<p>“There’s a direct relationship between energy and the military. The more energy consumed, the less effective you are militarily because you’re more vulnerable,” said Anderson, who reported to General David Petraeus. “They love to take out our field trucks. They make a big boom when they do.”</p>
<p>Since then, Anderson, like many military leaders, has realized that guzzling oil makes the United States vulnerable in other ways. “I’m a soldier,” Anderson said. “Why should I be concerned about climate change? Climate change brings about global instability. That makes the world more vulnerable and it’s more likely that soldiers like myself will have to fight and die somewhere.”</p>
<p>Never mind D.C. conservatives who claim to be tough on defense and suspicious of climate science: The Department of Defense isn’t denying that climate change is a major national security threat. “The change is happening. It’s just a reality,” said retired Marine Col. Mark Mykleby, a former strategy assistant to the Joint Chiefs of Staff. “Science tells us it’s coming our way.”</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read the whole thing. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/global-warming/the-military-understands-peak-oil-and-global-warming-but-conservatives-not-so-much/">The Military Understands Peak Oil And Global Warming &#8211; But conservatives not so much</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/global-warming/the-military-understands-peak-oil-and-global-warming-but-conservatives-not-so-much/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Military Sheds Its Dependence On OIL &#8211; Shouldn&#8217;t we be doing the same thing</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/the-military-sheds-its-dependence-on-oil-shouldnt-we-be-doing-the-same-thing/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/the-military-sheds-its-dependence-on-oil-shouldnt-we-be-doing-the-same-thing/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2012 16:29:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[airforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burn free generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electricity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy blogs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy conservation measures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy Tough Love Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[military]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[military polluters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photovoltaic panels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar power]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar water heat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waste]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=3913</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I know this week and next week, maybe all summer, may look like a chaotic mish mash of subjects but to rejuvenate my sense of purpose I am only blogging about stuff that I find interesting today. I find the &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/the-military-sheds-its-dependence-on-oil-shouldnt-we-be-doing-the-same-thing/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/the-military-sheds-its-dependence-on-oil-shouldnt-we-be-doing-the-same-thing/">The Military Sheds Its Dependence On OIL &#8211; Shouldn&#8217;t we be doing the same thing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I know this week and next week, maybe all summer, may look like a chaotic mish mash of subjects but to rejuvenate my sense of purpose I am only blogging about stuff that I find interesting today. I find the military&#8217;s attitude towards peak oil to be much more pragmatic then the capitalists they serve.</p>
<p><a href="http://grist.org/renewable-energy/u-s-military-kicks-more-ass-by-using-less-fossil-fuel-energy/?fb_ref=.T7uRMi_E9bl.like&amp;fb_source=home_multiline">http://grist.org/renewable-energy/u-s-military-kicks-more-ass-by-using-less-fossil-fuel-energy/?fb_ref=.T7uRMi_E9bl.like&amp;fb_source=home_multiline</a></p>
<div><a title="Posts by David Roberts" href="http://grist.org/author/david-roberts/"> <img decoding="async" loading="lazy" title="david_roberts_120" src="http://grist.files.wordpress.com/2012/01/david_roberts_120.png?w=120&amp;h=120&amp;crop=1" alt="david_roberts_120" width="120" height="120" /> </a></div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h1>David Roberts</h1>
<h2>Energy, politics, and more</h2>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<h1>U.S. military kicks more ass by using less fossil-fuel energy</h1>
<p>By <a title="Posts by David Roberts" href="http://grist.org/author/david-roberts/">David Roberts</a></p>
<p><em>This is my contribution to a <a href="http://energy.nationaljournal.com/2012/05/powering-our-military-whats-th.php">dialogue on the military and clean energy</a> being hosted by </em>National Journal<em>.</em></p>
<p>To understand the promise of renewable energy for the U.S. military, it helps to start as far from Washington, D.C., as possible. (This is true for most forms of understanding.) Start far from the politicians, even from the military brass, far from the rooms where big-money decisions are made, far out on the leading edge of the conflict, with a small company of Marines in Afghanistan’s Sangin River Valley</p>
<p>Not long ago, for a three-day mission out of a forward operating base in Afghanistan, each Marine would have humped between 20 and 35 pounds of batteries. One of the reasons Marines are so lethal in such small numbers today is that they are constantly connected by radios and computers. But radios and computers require a constant supply of batteries, brought by convoy over some of the deadliest roads on earth and then piled on the backs of Marines in highly kinetic environments.</p>
<p>In late 2010, India Company, from the 3rd Battalion, 5th Marine Regiment, tried something new. They packed Solar Portable Alternative Communications Energy Systems, or SPACES — flexible solar panels, 64 square inches, that weigh about 2.5 pounds each. One 1st Lieutenant from India 3/5 later boasted that his patrol shed 700 pounds.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read. This guy writes well. More tomorrow.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/the-military-sheds-its-dependence-on-oil-shouldnt-we-be-doing-the-same-thing/">The Military Sheds Its Dependence On OIL &#8211; Shouldn&#8217;t we be doing the same thing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/the-military-sheds-its-dependence-on-oil-shouldnt-we-be-doing-the-same-thing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>To All The Veterans Past And Present &#8211; Salute</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/burning-behavior/to-all-the-veterans-past-and-present-salute/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/burning-behavior/to-all-the-veterans-past-and-present-salute/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2011 20:43:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[airforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burning behavior]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy Tough Love Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gone pecan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[happy holidays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[military]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[military polluters]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=3383</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>It is true that I have picked on the militaries around the world as the biggest polluters ever. They will probably be the first ones to change, because they have to. http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wupsPg5H6aE :} More next week. :}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burning-behavior/to-all-the-veterans-past-and-present-salute/">To All The Veterans Past And Present &#8211; Salute</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It is true that I have picked on the militaries around the world as the biggest polluters ever. They will probably be the first ones to change, because they have to.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wupsPg5H6aE">http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wupsPg5H6aE</a></p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burning-behavior/to-all-the-veterans-past-and-present-salute/">To All The Veterans Past And Present &#8211; Salute</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/burning-behavior/to-all-the-veterans-past-and-present-salute/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Flying Car Approved &#8211; The future is here</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/burning-behavior/flying-car-approved-the-future-is-here/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/burning-behavior/flying-car-approved-the-future-is-here/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2011 14:51:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[airforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burning behavior]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy Tough Love Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environmental blogs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[public transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[useless energy use]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wind power]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=3056</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>So what? You can drive yourself to the airport and then take off? http://www.tgdaily.com/hardware-features/57051-flying-car-cleared-for-use-on-us-roads Flying car cleared for use on US roads Posted on Jul 6th 2011 by Emma Woollacott / / The Terrafugia flying car is now legal for &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/burning-behavior/flying-car-approved-the-future-is-here/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burning-behavior/flying-car-approved-the-future-is-here/">Flying Car Approved &#8211; The future is here</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So what? You can drive yourself to the airport and then take off?</p>
<p><a href="http://www.tgdaily.com/hardware-features/57051-flying-car-cleared-for-use-on-us-roads">http://www.tgdaily.com/hardware-features/57051-flying-car-cleared-for-use-on-us-roads</a></p>
<div>
<h3>Flying car cleared for use on US roads</h3>
</div>
<div>Posted on Jul 6th 2011 by     	  	    Emma Woollacott</div>
<div>/</div>
<div>/</div>
<div>
<p>The Terrafugia flying <a id="KonaLink0" href="http://www.tgdaily.com/hardware-features/57051-flying-car-cleared-for-use-on-us-roads#"><span style="color: #346200;">car</span></a> is now legal for use on the roads, following a grant of special exemptions by the National Highway <a id="KonaLink1" href="http://www.tgdaily.com/hardware-features/57051-flying-car-cleared-for-use-on-us-roads#"><span style="color: #346200;">Traffic Safety</span></a> Administration (NHTSA).</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="http://www.tgdaily.com/sites/default/files/stock/450teaser/aviation/terrafugia_gtransition.jpg" alt="" width="450" height="200" align="middle" /></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>One  exemption allows the Transition to use tires that are appropriately  rated for highway speeds and vehicle weight, but which aren&#8217;t normally  permitted on for multi-purpose vehicles. It means the vehicle can have  the same <a id="KonaLink2" href="http://www.tgdaily.com/hardware-features/57051-flying-car-cleared-for-use-on-us-roads#"><span style="color: #346200;">tires</span></a> as were used successfully in flight and drive tests in 2009.</p>
<p>The vehicle&#8217;s also allowed to have its own type of windscreen, with Terrafugia arguing that traditional laminated <a id="KonaLink3" href="http://www.tgdaily.com/hardware-features/57051-flying-car-cleared-for-use-on-us-roads#"><span style="color: #346200;">automotive</span></a> safety glass could fracture in such a way as to obscure the vision of the pilot in the event of a bird impact.</p>
<p>Instead, it&#8217;s allowed to use polycarbonate materials which are just as protective, it says, but which won&#8217;t shatter or craze.</p>
<p>Last summer, the Transition was given<a href="http://www.tgdaily.com/general-sciences-features/50419-flying-car-wins-initial-faa-approval" target="_blank" rel="noopener"> initial approval </a>by the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), and  granted an additional 110 pounds weight allowance.</p>
<p>The company says all it needs to do now is carry out a testing  program before the Transition starts shipping. It&#8217;s planning extensive  analysis and crash testing to make sure it reaches safety standards.</p>
<p>After that, it says, the Transition could be available as early as  the end of this year, costing around $200,000. You can reserve one for a  deposit of $10,000, <a href="http://%20http//www.terrafugia.com/order.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">here</a>.</p>
<p>:}</p>
</div>
<p><a href="http://www.terrafugia.com/">http://www.terrafugia.com/</a></p>
<p>Kind of looks like the batmobile when its wings are folded up.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>More tomorrow.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burning-behavior/flying-car-approved-the-future-is-here/">Flying Car Approved &#8211; The future is here</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/burning-behavior/flying-car-approved-the-future-is-here/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Militaries Waste Huge Amounts Of Money &#8211; In everything they do</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/burning-reduction-methods/militaries-waste-huge-amounts-of-money-in-everything-they-do/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/burning-reduction-methods/militaries-waste-huge-amounts-of-money-in-everything-they-do/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 16:06:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[airforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biofuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burning reduction methods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy Tough Love Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environmental blogs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[global warming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[military]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[military polluters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pollution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[synfuels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[useless energy use]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vampires]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[war]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=2935</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Let us put aside the fact militaries themselves are a huge waste of money. It is estimated that for every 1 $$$ the US for instance spends on a bullet they get 75 cents in return. That is just if &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/burning-reduction-methods/militaries-waste-huge-amounts-of-money-in-everything-they-do/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burning-reduction-methods/militaries-waste-huge-amounts-of-money-in-everything-they-do/">Militaries Waste Huge Amounts Of Money &#8211; In everything they do</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Let us put aside the fact militaries themselves are a huge waste of money. It is estimated that for every 1 $$$ the US for instance spends on a bullet they get 75 cents in return. That is just if it sits on the shelf. If it is used of course it is worth nothing. Not to mention that lavishing spending on militaries brought Empires from the Egypt to the Soviet Union&#8217;s down. But the USA&#8217;s Military wastes energy like there is no tomorrow. The worst offenders of course are the Airforce and the Navy. The Airforce in particular spews kerosene byproducts into the upper atmosphere where they do the most harm and the Navy because they burn warm asphalt at sea. Not to mention the nuclear issues both as weapons and power sources. But think about our main battle tank. It is as big as a modest 2 story house and it runs on diesel. So the idea that they want to go to zero energy use is great. But I got my doubts.</p>
<p><a href="http://globalgreenworld.org/?p=736">http://globalgreenworld.org/?p=736</a></p>
<h2>U.S. Army Launches Plan to Make All Military Bases Net Zero</h2>
<p>Posted  by <a title="Posts by Ggw Admin" href="http://globalgreenworld.org/?page_id=169&amp;uid=1">Ggw Admin</a> on Apr 19, 2011 in <a title="View all posts in Blog" rel="category" href="http://globalgreenworld.org/?cat=85">Blog</a> | <a title="Comment on U.S. Army Launches Plan to Make All Military Bases Net Zero" href="http://globalgreenworld.org/?p=736#respond">0 comments</a></p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="http://globalgreenworld.org/wp-content/plugins/rss-poster/cache/7a123_Usmilitary1-537x357.jpg" alt="Army Vision for Net Zero, Fort Bliss, net zero, renewable energy, U.S. Army, U.S. Military, Waste Reduction, water conservation" width="537" height="357" /></p>
<p>Over the past couple of years, the U.S. Army has announced several  initiatives ranging from solar-powered tents for troops to  hydrogen-powered tanks, however this is their most ambitious program  yet. With the help of the U.S. Department of Energy’s National Renewable  Energy  Laboratory (NREL), the U.S. Army is aiming to have all Army  installations across the country be net zero.</p>
<p><a href="http://inhabitat.com/u-s-army-launches-plan-to-make-all-military-bases-net-zero/usmilitary/"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="http://globalgreenworld.org/wp-content/plugins/rss-poster/cache/563ba_USmilitary-75x75.jpg" alt="" width="75" height="75" /></a></p>
<p><a href="http://ads.inhabitat.com/www/delivery/ck.php?n=a0b8f9d" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img decoding="async" src="http://globalgreenworld.org/wp-content/plugins/rss-poster/cache/563ba_avw.php" border="0" alt="" /></a><br />
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="http://globalgreenworld.org/wp-content/plugins/rss-poster/cache/df30c_USmilitary3-537x330.jpg" alt="Army Vision for Net Zero, Fort Bliss, net zero, renewable energy, U.S. Army, U.S. Military, Waste Reduction, water conservation" width="537" height="330" /></p>
<p>With funds from the DOE’s Federal Energy Management Program  (FEMP), the “Army Vision  for Net Zero” program will aim to meet  mandates to reduce energy as a result of  <a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/assets/documents/2009fedleader_eo_rel.pdf">Executive Order 13514</a>.  The order calls for all new  buildings to be net zero energy by 2030,  and it dictates a 30 percent reduction in water use and a 50 percent  reduction in waste that goes to landfills. On top of that, the National  Defense Authorization Act also mandates that the Army produce or acquire  25 percent of its energy from renewables by 2025.</p>
<p>“The first priority is less,” Assistant Secretary of the Army for   Installations, Energy  Environment Katherine Hammack said. “If you  use  less energy, you don’t have to buy as much – or you don’t have to  make  as much from alternative energy sources or renewable energy  sources. So  if you look at energy, that is a focus on energy efficiency.  If you’re  talking about water, then that’s water conservation. Or even  if you’re  talking about waste, that’s reducing the amount of waste we  have in  the steam.”</p>
<p>The program already has a poster child in the form of Fort Bliss. The  military base boasts solar daylighting in the dining facility,  warehouse and gym, energy-efficient windows, utility monitoring and  control for heating and air-conditioning systems in approximately 70  buildings, and plans to increase the on-site hybrid  waste-to-energy/concentrating solar power plant from 90 to 140  megawatts. The City of El Paso has committed to provide 1 million tons  per year of municipal solid waste, which will be transformed into energy  by the base.</p>
<p>“The Army’s net zero vision is a holistic approach to addressing   energy, water, and waste at Army installations,” Kingery said. “We look   at net zero as a force multiplier for the Army that will help us  steward  our resources and manage our costs.”</p>
<p>Considering that defense is a massive cause of national debt,  the  plan serves two purposes – reduced spending and “greening” national  security. If the military can get on board with renewable energy, it  makes you wonder why other areas of government are having such trouble.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.nrel.gov/features/20110406_army.html"><big>+ U.S Army</big></a></p>
<p><em>Images © <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/usarmyafrica/">US Army</a></em></p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>More tomorrow</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burning-reduction-methods/militaries-waste-huge-amounts-of-money-in-everything-they-do/">Militaries Waste Huge Amounts Of Money &#8211; In everything they do</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/burning-reduction-methods/militaries-waste-huge-amounts-of-money-in-everything-they-do/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
