<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>sustainability Archives - Community Energy Systems</title>
	<atom:link href="/censys/category/blog/sustainability/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/censys/category/blog/sustainability/</link>
	<description>Censys.org</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 17:51:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Energy Independence &#8211; It should be every bodies right</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/advance-energy-structures/energy-independence-it-should-be-every-bodies-right/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/advance-energy-structures/energy-independence-it-should-be-every-bodies-right/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 17:46:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[advanced energy structures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[batteries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burn free generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electricity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Other countries advances]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stewardship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=8646</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>More next Fall. HAHA Took me three extra months to return. Sorry did not EVEN think about posting until now. First, of let me say I am now cancer free. Second, let me say that taking a break away from &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/advance-energy-structures/energy-independence-it-should-be-every-bodies-right/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/advance-energy-structures/energy-independence-it-should-be-every-bodies-right/">Energy Independence &#8211; It should be every bodies right</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>More next Fall. HAHA Took me three extra months to return. Sorry did not EVEN think about posting until now.</p>
<p>First, of let me say I am now cancer free. Second, let me say that taking a break away from posting because of the cancer and the cancer treatment left me fairly lazy, so it is tough getting back to writing these posts. The thought has occurred to me that I might retire at the end of the year. Anyway it is good to be back for now. So without further adieu:</p>
<p><a href="https://springfieldstatejournalregister-il.newsmemory.com/?token=ad88ee2719e187433892376e5ee4084b&amp;cnum=f1ab27f9-ae38-eb11-a0ad-90b11c3d639b&amp;fod=1111111STD-0&amp;selDate=20221001&amp;licenseType=paid_subscriber&amp;for-guid=7b00ad35-cf99-4e2d-8f79-47fcd162e2b9&amp;utm_source=sj-r-DailyBriefing&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=daily_briefing&amp;utm_term=promo&amp;utm_content=NSJR-ILLINOIS-SPRINGFIELD-NLETTER65">https://springfieldstatejournalregister-il.newsmemory.com/?token=ad88ee2719e187433892376e5ee4084b&amp;cnum=f1ab27f9-ae38-eb11-a0ad-90b11c3d639b&amp;fod=1111111STD-0&amp;selDate=20221001&amp;licenseType=paid_subscriber&amp;for-guid=7b00ad35-cf99-4e2d-8f79-47fcd162e2b9&amp;utm_source=sj-r-DailyBriefing&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=daily_briefing&amp;utm_term=promo&amp;utm_content=NSJR-ILLINOIS-SPRINGFIELD-NLETTER65</a></p>
<div class="Component-headline-0-2-32" data-key="card-headline">
<h1 class="Component-heading-0-2-33">In one tiny German town, nobody worries about energy bills</h1>
</div>
<div class="Component-signature-0-2-35"><span class="Component-bylines-0-2-36">By FRANK JORDANS </span><span class="Timestamp Component-root-0-2-38 Component-timestamp-0-2-37" title="2022-09-30 00:42:15 - Thu Sep 29 2022 19:42:15 GMT-0500 (Central Daylight Time)" data-key="timestamp" data-source="2022-09-30T00:42:15Z">yesterday</span></div>
<p class="Component-root-0-2-63 p Component-p-0-2-54">FELDHEIM, Germany (AP) — Europeans are opening their energy bills with trepidation these days, bracing for hefty price hikes as utility companies pass on the <a class="paragraph-link" href="https://apnews.com/article/russia-ukraine-business-germany-prices-financial-crisis-deba9cb23f28e645e7349256126eaae6">surging cost of natural gas</a>, oil and electricity tied to Russia’s war in Ukraine. <a class="paragraph-link" href="https://apnews.com/article/russia-ukraine-germany-prices-cca7e5afd38fbcfc1ad72934e8e59bd9?utm_source=homepage&amp;utm_medium=TopNews&amp;utm_campaign=position_03">Many are trying to conserve</a> by turning down the heat and shutting off lights this winter.</p>
<p class="Component-root-0-2-63 p Component-p-0-2-54">Not so the people of Feldheim, population 130.</p>
<p class="Component-root-0-2-63 p Component-p-0-2-54">Located about an hour and a half south of Berlin, this modest but well-kept village has been energy self-sufficient for more than a decade.</p>
<p class="Component-root-0-2-63 p Component-p-0-2-54">A bold experiment launched in the mid-1990s saw Feldheim erect a handful of wind turbines to provide electricity to the village. Then it built a local grid, solar panels, battery storage and more turbines. A <a class="paragraph-link" href="https://apnews.com/article/russia-ukraine-technology-business-paris-germany-7d70ea772d2822ced45c45c14cc1816e">biogas plant</a> put up to keep piglets warm was expanded, providing extra income to the farmers’ cooperative, which pumps hot water through a village-wide central heating system. A hydrogen production facility is also under construction.</p>
<p>Come on! If a little tiny town can do it, we all can.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/advance-energy-structures/energy-independence-it-should-be-every-bodies-right/">Energy Independence &#8211; It should be every bodies right</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/advance-energy-structures/energy-independence-it-should-be-every-bodies-right/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Upheavals Caused By Clean Energy &#8211; All the tree huggers make it look like pixie dust</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/upheavals-caused-by-clean-energy-all-the-tree-huggers-make-it-look-like-pixie-dust/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/upheavals-caused-by-clean-energy-all-the-tree-huggers-make-it-look-like-pixie-dust/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 20:46:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[batteries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burn free generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cool sites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[penetrating ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=8551</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>By &#8220;pixie dust&#8221; I mean that a lot of environmentalists make it sound like there will be no chaos from fossil fuel use to renewal energy systems and that is not true. Dislodging fossil fuel will result in job loses, &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/upheavals-caused-by-clean-energy-all-the-tree-huggers-make-it-look-like-pixie-dust/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/upheavals-caused-by-clean-energy-all-the-tree-huggers-make-it-look-like-pixie-dust/">Upheavals Caused By Clean Energy &#8211; All the tree huggers make it look like pixie dust</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By &#8220;pixie dust&#8221; I mean that a lot of environmentalists make it sound like there will be no chaos from fossil fuel use to renewal energy systems and that is not true. Dislodging fossil fuel will result in job loses, factories closing and possibly the lack of transportation (for example) for chunks of the population. Especially those not preparing for it now. Lives will be lost. This is the fault of capitalism but it is what we have. Also the reverse is true, as demand for clean energy grows, whole resources will be created from scratch (rare earths for instance). The earth will be scarred, employment will be created with much wrenching and tearing. Lives will be lost. Capitalism will prevail. Just think of what happened when oil and gas took over and from the Luddites. This is a Really Long article about all of that and it only scratches the surface.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/world/2021-11-30/geopolitics-energy-green-upheaval?utm_source=pocket-newtab">https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/world/2021-11-30/geopolitics-energy-green-upheaval?utm_source=pocket-newtab</a></p>
<div class="row article-header--metadata-title">
<div class="col-lg-10 offset-lg-0 col-12 col-md-8 offset-md-2">
<div class="row">
<div class="col-lg-11 article-header--metadata-content">
<h1 class="f-serif ls-0 article-title pt-2" data-drupal-page-title="">Green Upheaval</h1>
<h2 class="f-serif ls-0 article-subtitle ">The New Geopolitics of Energy</h2>
<div class="row no-gutters ls-0 article-byline position-relative">
<h3 class="f-sans m-0 col-12 col-sm-auto mr-sm-4">By <span class="position-relative d-inline-block"><a class="article-byline-author b4-l" href="https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/world/2021-11-30/geopolitics-energy-green-upheaval?utm_source=pocket-newtab#author-info">Jason Bordoff and Meghan L. O’Sullivan</a></span></h3>
<p><span class="article-header--metadata-date align-self-center col-6 col-sm-auto"><a href="https://www.foreignaffairs.com/issues/2022/101/1">January/February 2022</a></span></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>It is not hard to understand why people dream of a future defined by clean energy. As greenhouse gas emissions continue to grow and as extreme weather events become more frequent and harmful, the current efforts to move beyond fossil fuels appear woefully inadequate. Adding to the frustration, the geopolitics of oil and gas are alive and well—and as fraught as ever. Europe is in the throes of a full-fledged energy crisis, with staggering electricity prices forcing businesses across the continent to shutter and energy firms to declare bankruptcy, positioning Russian President Vladimir Putin to take advantage of his neighbors’ struggles by leveraging his country’s natural gas reserves. In September, blackouts reportedly led Chinese Vice Premier Han Zheng to instruct his country’s state-owned energy companies to secure supplies for winter at any cost. And as oil prices surge above $80 per barrel, the United States and other energy-hungry countries are pleading with major producers, including Saudi Arabia, to ramp up their output, giving Riyadh more clout in a newly tense relationship and suggesting the limits of Washington’s energy “independence.”</p>
<p>Proponents of clean energy hope (and sometimes promise) that in addition to mitigating climate change, the energy transition will help make tensions over energy resources a thing of the past. It is true that clean energy will transform geopolitics—just not necessarily in the ways many of its champions expect. The transition will reconfigure many elements of international politics that have shaped the global system since at least World War II, significantly affecting the sources of national power, the process of globalization, relations among the great powers, and the ongoing economic convergence of developed countries and developing ones. The process will be messy at best. And far from fostering comity and cooperation, it will likely produce new forms of competition and confrontation long before a new, more copacetic geopolitics takes shape.</p>
<p>Talk of a smooth transition to clean energy is fanciful: there is no way that the world can avoid major upheavals as it remakes the entire energy system, which is the lifeblood of the global economy and underpins the geopolitical order. Moreover, the conventional wisdom about who will gain and who will lose is frequently off base.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and reeeeaaad. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/upheavals-caused-by-clean-energy-all-the-tree-huggers-make-it-look-like-pixie-dust/">Upheavals Caused By Clean Energy &#8211; All the tree huggers make it look like pixie dust</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/upheavals-caused-by-clean-energy-all-the-tree-huggers-make-it-look-like-pixie-dust/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How We Drained The Largest Lake West Of The Mississippi &#8211; OH My</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/aquifer-damage/how-we-drained-the-largest-lake-west-of-the-mississippi-oh-my/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/aquifer-damage/how-we-drained-the-largest-lake-west-of-the-mississippi-oh-my/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 19:49:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[aquifer damage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burning behavior]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dumb ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[masters of the universe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outdoors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[penetrating ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self inflicted wounds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=8386</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>This is the story of a man named Boswell and Boswell had a very lovely wife (Sorry Brady Bunch) who turned the San Joaquin Valley from a lush river and lake wildlife area into the nation&#8217;s bread basket. Also how &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/aquifer-damage/how-we-drained-the-largest-lake-west-of-the-mississippi-oh-my/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/aquifer-damage/how-we-drained-the-largest-lake-west-of-the-mississippi-oh-my/">How We Drained The Largest Lake West Of The Mississippi &#8211; OH My</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is the story of a man named Boswell and Boswell had a very lovely wife (Sorry Brady Bunch) who turned the San Joaquin Valley from a lush river and lake wildlife area into the nation&#8217;s bread basket. Also how it destroyed a massive habitat This was and is a despicable enterprise. Sort of on the order of a Nuclear Testing site in the desert. Or a Copper Mine for that matter. If you want to hear a video about it. There is This:</p>
<p><a href="https://digg.com/video/heres-why-the-united-states-drained-its-ninth-largest-lake">https://digg.com/video/heres-why-the-united-states-drained-its-ninth-largest-lake</a></p>
<p>If you want to read about it. You can go here:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.tularebasinwildlifepartners.org/history.html">http://www.tularebasinwildlifepartners.org/history.html</a></p>
<h2 class="wsite-content-title">Hydrologic History of the Tulare Basin</h2>
<div></div>
<div class="paragraph">
<p>The Tulare Basin historically supported an amazing complex of wetland habitats, unique in the world. This largely flat and arid region served as the floodplain for water flowing west from the southern Sierra Nevada, north from the Transverse Ranges, as well as from small intermittent arroyos flowing east from the Coast Ranges. Oak woodlands and riparian forests formed green corridors across the broad prairie on the eastern edge of the Tulare Basin. Freshwater tule marshes and alkaline wetlands adorned the slow-moving sloughs and shallow margins of Kern, Buena Vista, Goose, Tulare, and Summit lakes. Emergent marsh vegetation, such as tules and cattails, grew in permanent standing water at the shallow edges of freshwater wetlands. Upslope from the marshes, water intermittently flooded iodine bush scrub and alkali grassland habitats.</p>
<p>This highly-productive, shallow water system supported abundant populations of endemic lake-adapted fishes such that American white pelicans (Pelacanus erythrorhynchos) nested by the thousands on islands in Tulare Lake and Buena Vista Lake. The Tulare Basin&#8217;s extensive wetland habitats historically attracted significant numbers of resident and migratory waterbirds, including grebes, pelicans, cormorants, herons, egrets, ibises, geese, swans, ducks, rails, sandhill cranes, plovers, stilts, avocets, sandpipers, phalaropes, gulls, and terns.</p>
<p>The conversion of this water system to a lake-and-slough wetland to agriculture began in the mid-1800s when European settlers began to build canals and diversion structures to irrigate their crops.  This early irrigation infrastructure upstream from Tulare Lake slowly cut off the lake from its source waters, shrinking the lake&#8217;s footprint.  By 1899 &#8211; less than 50 years after irrigation was initiated &#8211; Tulare Lake went dry for the first time in history.</p>
</div>
<div>FOR STARTERS</div>
<div>:}</div>
<div>Go there and read. More next week.</div>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/aquifer-damage/how-we-drained-the-largest-lake-west-of-the-mississippi-oh-my/">How We Drained The Largest Lake West Of The Mississippi &#8211; OH My</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/aquifer-damage/how-we-drained-the-largest-lake-west-of-the-mississippi-oh-my/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tomorrow * NO Cars &#8211; What then</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/green-cars/tomorrow-no-cars-what-then/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/green-cars/tomorrow-no-cars-what-then/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 20:20:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[burning reduction methods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environmentalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[global warming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water pollution]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=8380</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>If Schumer could pull this off I would be &#8220;dancin in the streets&#8221;. It would not be as good and banning Airline Flights, but heh I will take whatever I can get. It would be really good for the lower &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/green-cars/tomorrow-no-cars-what-then/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/green-cars/tomorrow-no-cars-what-then/">Tomorrow * NO Cars &#8211; What then</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If Schumer could pull this off I would be &#8220;dancin in the streets&#8221;. It would not be as good and banning Airline Flights, but heh I will take whatever I can get. It would be really good for the lower level atmosphere and especially good for bodies of water, whether flowing bodies like rivers or standing bodies like lakes or oceans. Unfortunately, the upper atmosphere is where the real global warming is taking place. Still &#8211; I am not minimizing this. IT be good.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/17/22334634/schumer-electric-vehicle-swap-discount-infrastructure-interview">https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/17/22334634/schumer-electric-vehicle-swap-discount-infrastructure-interview</a></p>
<div class="c-entry-group-labels c-entry-group-labels--feature">
<ul aria-labelledby="heading-label--53fhlluw">
<li class="c-entry-group-labels__item"><a href="https://www.theverge.com/policy"> Policy </a></li>
</ul>
</div>
<h1 class="c-page-title">Chuck Schumer wants to replace every gas car in America with an electric vehicle</h1>
<p class="c-entry-summary p-dek">The Senate majority leader is reviving his plan to give people discounts for swapping their gas car for an electric one</p>
<div class="c-byline"><span class="c-byline-wrapper"> By <span class="c-byline__item"> <a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/andrew-j-hawkins" data-analytics-link="author-name"><span class="c-byline__author-name">Andrew J. Hawkins</span></a><a class="c-byline__twitter-handle" href="https://www.twitter.com/andyjayhawk">@andyjayhawk</a> </span> <span class="c-byline__item"> <time class="c-byline__item" datetime="2021-03-17T15:23:13" data-ui="timestamp"> Mar 17, 2021, 11:23am </time></span></span></div>
<p id="UnXkqU" class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text drop-letter-w"><span role="text"><span class="sr-only"><strong>W</strong>ith</span></span> the $1.9 trillion COVID relief bill signed into law, Senate Majority Leader Chuck Schumer (D-NY) is ready to tackle the next major challenge: President Joe Biden’s call for a massive infrastructure bill. As part of that package, Schumer said he plans to include his ambitious proposal to get every American to swap their gas-guzzling car for an electric one.</p>
<p id="4s4nuu">“It’s a bold new plan designed to accelerate America’s transition to all electric vehicles on the road, to developing a charging infrastructure, and to grow American jobs through clean manufacturing,” Schumer told <em>The Verge</em> in a brief interview this week. “And the ultimate goal is to have every car manufactured in America be electric by 2030, and every car on the road be clean by 2040.”</p>
<p id="9dBBWh">The top-line details of the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/25/20931983/schumer-electric-car-trade-in-gas-discount-proposal-zero-emission">“cash for clunkers’’-style plan</a> haven’t changed much since Schumer first proposed it in <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/10/24/opinion/chuck-schumer-electric-car.html">an op-ed in <em>The</em> <em>New York Times</em> in late 2019</a>. But the political landscape has certainly shifted in favor of the Democrats, breathing new life into the idea. Under the proposal, anyone who trades in their gas car for an electric one would get a “substantial” point-of-sale discount, Schumer says. He wouldn’t say how much of a discount, only that it would be “deep.” A spokesperson later confirmed they are eyeing rebates that are “more generous” than the current $7,500 federal EV tax credit.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/green-cars/tomorrow-no-cars-what-then/">Tomorrow * NO Cars &#8211; What then</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/green-cars/tomorrow-no-cars-what-then/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Solar Street Lights Are Amazing &#8211; Its been awhile since I did nuts and bolts</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/lighting/solar-street-lights-are-amazing-its-been-awhile-since-i-did-nuts-and-bolts/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/lighting/solar-street-lights-are-amazing-its-been-awhile-since-i-did-nuts-and-bolts/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 20:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[burn free generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lighting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar power]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=8340</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I used to detest Streetlights. I know it is weird. I hate waste and after the all night lights at the Stratton Building in downtown Springfield, IL streetlights are the worst. They do not help people drive better and they &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/lighting/solar-street-lights-are-amazing-its-been-awhile-since-i-did-nuts-and-bolts/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/lighting/solar-street-lights-are-amazing-its-been-awhile-since-i-did-nuts-and-bolts/">Solar Street Lights Are Amazing &#8211; Its been awhile since I did nuts and bolts</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I used to detest Streetlights. I know it is weird. I hate waste and after the all night lights at the Stratton Building in downtown Springfield, IL streetlights are the worst. They do not help people drive better and they do not deter most crime. Plus they are immense light polluters that prevent us from seeing the stars. But if they are emission controlled and solar powered, I guess I could at least get mellow on them.</p>
<p><a href="https://cleanenergysummit.org/best-solar-street-lights/">https://cleanenergysummit.org/best-solar-street-lights/</a></p>
<header class="entry-header">
<h1 class="entry-title">The Best Solar Street Lights for 2021</h1>
<div class="entry-meta"><span class="posted-on"><time class="entry-date published" datetime="2021-01-02T01:30:57+00:00">January 2, 2021</time></span> <span class="byline">by <span class="author vcard"><a class="url fn n" title="View all posts by Justin Tucker" href="https://cleanenergysummit.org/author/justin-tucker/" rel="author" data-wpel-link="internal"><span class="author-name">Justin Tucker</span></a></span></span></div>
</header>
<div class="entry-content">
<p>If you’re looking for the best solar street lights, you have come to the right post. Today, your friends at Clean Energy Summit highlights the top picks that have the solid and reliable features as well as the factors to look into when buying these products.</p>
<p>Finding the right one, you’ll be certain of using the right lighting solution you need for places like the parking lots, streets, transits, outdoor areas, civil and military security areas and so many more.</p>
</div>
<p>To help you pick the right one that suits your needs, check out the following for reference. We do hope you could choose your streetlights after reading today’s guide.</p>
<h3><span id="1_TENKOO_LED_Solar_Street_Lights">1. TENKOO LED Solar Street Lights</span></h3>
<ul>
<li>IP65 and waterproof</li>
<li><i class="sui sui-check-circle"></i> Integrated design</li>
<li><i class="sui sui-check-circle"></i> With motion sensor</li>
<li><i class="sui sui-check-circle"></i> Ideal for garden path, patio, gutter and street</li>
<li><i class="sui sui-check-circle"></i> 5-Years after-sale service</li>
</ul>
<p>The TENKOO LED Solar Street Light is the best solar led street light for many users worldwide, and for reasons. The top of the line solar powered lights are energy efficient and solid in performance. If you’re looking to improve lighting in the patio or gutter, you can think of installing the streetlights.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/lighting/solar-street-lights-are-amazing-its-been-awhile-since-i-did-nuts-and-bolts/">Solar Street Lights Are Amazing &#8211; Its been awhile since I did nuts and bolts</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/lighting/solar-street-lights-are-amazing-its-been-awhile-since-i-did-nuts-and-bolts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Improved Better Outstanding Sites &#8211; Or at least that&#8217;s what they say</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/energy-education/new-improved-better-outstanding-sites-or-at-least-thats-what-they-say/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/energy-education/new-improved-better-outstanding-sites-or-at-least-thats-what-they-say/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 17:11:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[burning reduction methods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy conservation measures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outdoors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[penetrating ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water conservation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=8264</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I preface this whole page by saying &#8211; I AM RETIRED. So I have gotten lazy. Periodically I get requests to LINK to other sites, or &#8211; we read your post and would you publish this ARTICLE, and other related &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/energy-education/new-improved-better-outstanding-sites-or-at-least-thats-what-they-say/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/energy-education/new-improved-better-outstanding-sites-or-at-least-thats-what-they-say/">New Improved Better Outstanding Sites &#8211; Or at least that&#8217;s what they say</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I preface this whole page by saying &#8211; I AM RETIRED. So I have gotten lazy. Periodically I get requests to LINK to other sites, or &#8211; we read your post and would you publish this ARTICLE, and other related requests. The best that I can do is everyonce in awhile I post their links in a combined page like this:</p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ztxHpM770t"><p><a href="https://iceblast.com.au/differences-between-commercial-residential-air-conditioning/">40 Differences Between Commercial and Residential Air Conditioning</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;40 Differences Between Commercial and Residential Air Conditioning&#8221; &#8212; Ice Blast Air Conditioning" src="https://iceblast.com.au/differences-between-commercial-residential-air-conditioning/embed/#?secret=ztxHpM770t" data-secret="ztxHpM770t" width="584" height="329" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
<p>&#8230;</p>
<p>Then there is this:</p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="CaHKQc7PrV"><p><a href="https://freshbigbang.com/save-energy/">NO NEED TO BE A HERO TO SAVE ENERGY</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;NO NEED TO BE A HERO TO SAVE ENERGY&#8221; &#8212; Fresh Big Bang" src="https://freshbigbang.com/save-energy/embed/#?secret=CaHKQc7PrV" data-secret="CaHKQc7PrV" width="584" height="329" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
<p>&#8230;</p>
<p>Then there is this:</p>
<p>By the way, I am not sure I think running is good for you but it does save transportation costs. Run Forrest Fun.</p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2pl8TjeqGU"><p><a href="https://fitnessfornonathletes.com/develop-running-habit/">How to Develop a Lasting Running Habit</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How to Develop a Lasting Running Habit&#8221; &#8212; Non-Athlete Fitness" src="https://fitnessfornonathletes.com/develop-running-habit/embed/#?secret=2pl8TjeqGU" data-secret="2pl8TjeqGU" width="584" height="329" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
<p>&#8230;</p>
<p>Or this, which is more on topic:</p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="5VH9de4mon"><p><a href="https://homelivinglab.com/how-to-stop-climate-change-from-the-comfort-of-your-home/">How to stop climate change from the comfort of your home</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How to stop climate change from the comfort of your home&#8221; &#8212; Home Living Lab" src="https://homelivinglab.com/how-to-stop-climate-change-from-the-comfort-of-your-home/embed/#?secret=5VH9de4mon" data-secret="5VH9de4mon" width="584" height="329" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
<p>Finally for today:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.buildingmaterials.co.uk/nuts-and-bolts/resources/how-to-make-your-home-more-energy-efficient/">https://www.buildingmaterials.co.uk/nuts-and-bolts/resources/how-to-make-your-home-more-energy-efficient/</a></p>
<h1>How to make your home more energy efficient in the UK</h1>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and enjoy. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/energy-education/new-improved-better-outstanding-sites-or-at-least-thats-what-they-say/">New Improved Better Outstanding Sites &#8211; Or at least that&#8217;s what they say</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/energy-education/new-improved-better-outstanding-sites-or-at-least-thats-what-they-say/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How To Drive Fossil Fuels Out Of The Economy &#8211; The title is very deceptive</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/how-to-drive-fossil-fuels-out-of-the-economy-the-title-is-very-deceptive/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/how-to-drive-fossil-fuels-out-of-the-economy-the-title-is-very-deceptive/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 16:20:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burn free generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electricity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[playing hooky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=8185</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>While this article is not click bait per se, the first sentence talks about Roosevelt and WWII. You know, the Big One that he used to take over the economy for almost 10 years. Ask yourself, &#8220;Would any USA President &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/how-to-drive-fossil-fuels-out-of-the-economy-the-title-is-very-deceptive/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/how-to-drive-fossil-fuels-out-of-the-economy-the-title-is-very-deceptive/">How To Drive Fossil Fuels Out Of The Economy &#8211; The title is very deceptive</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While this article is not click bait per se, the first sentence talks about Roosevelt and WWII. You know, the Big One that he used to take over the economy for almost 10 years. Ask yourself, &#8220;Would any USA President use emergency powers OR The War Powers Act to purge the economy of fossil fuels&#8221;? The real answer is a resounding NO. Then he proceeds to discuss a &#8220;PLAN&#8221; that is more of a &#8220;thought experiment&#8221; or a model with some &#8220;results&#8221;.</p>
<p>None-the-less it is entertaining. And to be fair possible. But somebody has got to light a really really really large fire. Every pun intended.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.vox.com/energy-and-environment/21349200/climate-change-fossil-fuels-rewiring-america-electrify">https://www.vox.com/energy-and-environment/21349200/climate-change-fossil-fuels-rewiring-america-electrify</a></p>
<div class="c-entry-hero__header-wrap">
<h1 class="c-page-title">How to drive fossil fuels out of the US economy, quickly</h1>
</div>
<p class="c-entry-summary p-dek">The US has everything it needs to decarbonize by 2035.</p>
<div class="c-byline"><span class="c-byline-wrapper"> By <span class="c-byline__item"> <a href="https://www.vox.com/authors/david-roberts" data-analytics-link="author-name"><span class="c-byline__author-name">David Roberts</span></a><a class="c-byline__twitter-handle" href="https://www.twitter.com/drvox">@drvox</a><a title="" href="mailto:david@vox.com">david@vox.com</a> </span> <span class="c-byline__item"> <time class="c-byline__item" datetime="2020-08-06T14:10:00" data-ui="timestamp"> Aug 6, 2020, 10:10am EDT </time> </span> </span></div>
<p id="ZX9Wor">In the runup to World War II, President Franklin Delano Roosevelt enlisted the entire US economy in an effort to scale up production of war material. All of the country’s resources were bent to the task. In 1939, the US had 1,700 aircraft; in 1945, it had 300,000 military aircraft and 18,500 B–24 bombers.</p>
<p id="uRBvdX">By the time the war was won, the economy was up and humming with a massively expanded workforce (drawing in women and African Americans) and turbocharged productive capacity. Investments made during the war mobilization yielded a robust middle class and decades of sustained, broadly shared prosperity.</p>
<p id="SlrMMD">A similar mobilization will be necessary for the US to decarbonize its economy fast enough to avert the worst of climate change. To do its part in limiting global temperature rise to between <a href="https://www.vox.com/2018/10/9/17951924/climate-change-global-warming-un-ipcc-report-takeaways">1.5° and 2° Celsius</a>, the US must reach net-zero carbon emissions by 2050 at the latest. To achieve this, the full resources of the US economy must be bent toward manufacturing the needed clean-energy technology and infrastructure.</p>
<p id="Fyj2J0">FDR began with two questions. First, he asked not what was politically feasible but <em>what was necessary</em> to win the war. He also asked not how much funding was available in the federal budget but how much productive capacity was available in the economy — <em>what was possible</em>.</p>
<p id="ss5u50">Saul Griffith is trying to answer those same questions on climate change: what is necessary, given the trajectory of global warming, and what is possible, given the resources in the US economy.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>It is a Vox long read. So go there and read forever. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/how-to-drive-fossil-fuels-out-of-the-economy-the-title-is-very-deceptive/">How To Drive Fossil Fuels Out Of The Economy &#8211; The title is very deceptive</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/how-to-drive-fossil-fuels-out-of-the-economy-the-title-is-very-deceptive/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joe Biden For President &#8211; There I said it</title>
		<link>/censys/2020-presidential-elections/joe-biden-for-president-there-i-said-it/</link>
					<comments>/censys/2020-presidential-elections/joe-biden-for-president-there-i-said-it/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 18:50:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[2020 election]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[2020 presidential elections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced energy structures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burn free generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[masters of the universe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[presidential candidates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water conservation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=8163</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Trump doesn&#8217;t have a plan for the environment except to degrade it. Donald Trump doesn&#8217;t have a plan for energy consumption but to push coal usage and repeal regulation that encourage the switch to alternative energy sources. Joe Biden has &#8230; <a href="/censys/2020-presidential-elections/joe-biden-for-president-there-i-said-it/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/2020-presidential-elections/joe-biden-for-president-there-i-said-it/">Joe Biden For President &#8211; There I said it</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Trump doesn&#8217;t have a plan for the environment except to degrade it. Donald Trump doesn&#8217;t have a plan for energy consumption but to push coal usage and repeal regulation that encourage the switch to alternative energy sources. Joe Biden has a TRILLION dollar plan that is good for the environment and proposes to be carbon free at some point. We need sanity. We need Joe.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/07/14/joe-biden-unveils-green-jobs-and-infrastructure-plan-during-2020-election.html">https://www.cnbc.com/2020/07/14/joe-biden-unveils-green-jobs-and-infrastructure-plan-during-2020-election.html</a></p>
<p><a href="https://joebiden.com/clean-energy/">https://joebiden.com/clean-energy/</a></p>
<div class="ArticleHeader-wrapperHeroNoImage ArticleHeader-wrapperHero ArticleHeader-wrapper ArticleHeader-wrapperNoImage"><a class="ArticleHeader-eyebrow" href="https://www.cnbc.com/politics/">Politics</a></p>
<div>
<h1 class="ArticleHeader-headline">Joe Biden unveils $2 trillion green infrastructure and jobs plan</h1>
</div>
<div class="ArticleHeader-time"><time data-testid="published-timestamp">Published Tue, Jul 14 20201:23 PM EDT</time><time data-testid="lastpublished-timestamp">Updated Tue, Jul 14 20203:54 PM EDT</time></div>
</div>
<div class="ArticleHeader-authorAndShareInline">
<div class="ArticleHeader-authorContainer">
<div class="ArticleHeader-author">
<div class="Author-author">
<div class="Author-authorInfo">
<div class="Author-authorPortrait"></div>
<div class="Author-authorNameAndSocial"><a class="Author-authorName" href="https://www.cnbc.com/jacob-pramuk/">Jacob Pramuk</a></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>Former Vice President <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/id/10000451">Joe Biden</a> released a sprawling plan Tuesday to revamp American infrastructure and energy to both curb climate change and spur economic growth.</p>
<p>The presumptive Democratic presidential nominee’s proposal aims to achieve carbon-free power generation by 2035. As the coronavirus pandemic leaves the U.S. mired in an economic crisis, Biden said he will set out to create “millions” of union jobs that pay at least $15 per hour as the U.S. overhauls its roads, bridges, trains, auto industry and broadband system.</p>
<div class="BoxInline-container  ">
<div id="BoxInline-ArticleBody-6" class="BoxInline-container" data-module="mps-slot"></div>
</div>
<p>The plan, which comes days after a joint task force formed by the Biden and Sen. <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/bernie-sanders/">Bernie Sanders</a> campaigns outlined a climate change agenda, sets out a more ambitious approach to developing clean energy than the Biden campaign did during the Democratic primary. It calls for $2 trillion in spending over four years, more than the $1.7 trillion the campaign previously proposed to spend over a decade.</p>
<p>“Even if we weren’t facing a pandemic and an economic crisis, we should be making these investments anyway,” Biden said of the plan during remarks in Delaware. He called the investments “critical” for the economy and public health.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read. Read alot. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/2020-presidential-elections/joe-biden-for-president-there-i-said-it/">Joe Biden For President &#8211; There I said it</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/2020-presidential-elections/joe-biden-for-president-there-i-said-it/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Singapore Solves A Serious Energy Issue &#8211; If only Bloomberg would get to it as well</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/air-conditioning/singapore-solves-a-serious-energy-issue-if-only-bloomberg-would-get-to-it-as-well/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/air-conditioning/singapore-solves-a-serious-energy-issue-if-only-bloomberg-would-get-to-it-as-well/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 18 Jun 2020 16:26:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[advanced energy structures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[air conditioning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big whoop dee do]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burn free generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=8141</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Now if the Bloombergs of the world would tackle their issues, maybe the Earth would make some progress. Solving the Global Cooling Problem As air-conditioning sucks up more and more energy, Singapore finds a greener way to keep cool. By Faris &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/air-conditioning/singapore-solves-a-serious-energy-issue-if-only-bloomberg-would-get-to-it-as-well/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/air-conditioning/singapore-solves-a-serious-energy-issue-if-only-bloomberg-would-get-to-it-as-well/">Singapore Solves A Serious Energy Issue &#8211; If only Bloomberg would get to it as well</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Now if the Bloombergs of the world would tackle their issues, maybe the Earth would make some progress.</p>
<h1 class="full-width-image-lede-text-below__hed">Solving the Global Cooling Problem</h1>
<div class="full-width-image-lede-text-below__dek">
<p>As air-conditioning sucks up more and more energy, Singapore finds a greener way to keep cool.</p>
</div>
<div class="full-width-image-lede-text-below__byline">By<a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/authors/AUUYP6FUcC4/faris-mokhtar"> Faris Mokhtar</a></div>
<div class="full-width-image-lede-text-below__times"><time class="article-timestamp" datetime="2020-06-08T21:00:22.255Z" data-type="updated" data-status="localized">June 8, 2020, 4:00 PM CDT</time></div>
<p>In Singapore, close to the Equator, temperatures regularly rise above 32 degrees Celsius (90 Fahrenheit) — but inside the soaring glass greenhouses of Gardens by the Bay, the country’s award-winning botanical park, it’s a pleasant 24 degrees.</p>
<p>The daffodils and tulips of the flower dome, along with two dozen nearby towers that are normally full of bankers, shoppers, residents, hotel guests and gamblers, are chilled by what is probably the world’s largest underground district cooling system. It’s a giant air conditioner that is attempting to solve one of the biggest problems of global warming: How to stay cool.</p>
<p>(moving right along)</p>
<p>That means a massive drain on power — more than a third of the world’s electricity could end up being used to cool buildings and vehicles — with an equivalent jump in carbon emissions if, as is the case now, most of that extra generating capacity relies on fossil fuels.</p>
<p>The rise of global cooling has prompted research and development into ways to make systems more efficient using heat pumps, solar-power, evaporative coolers and other technologies. One of the most effective is to build a system that uses a large central plant that can cool several city blocks.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read a lot. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/air-conditioning/singapore-solves-a-serious-energy-issue-if-only-bloomberg-would-get-to-it-as-well/">Singapore Solves A Serious Energy Issue &#8211; If only Bloomberg would get to it as well</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/air-conditioning/singapore-solves-a-serious-energy-issue-if-only-bloomberg-would-get-to-it-as-well/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>I Never Believed In Godzilla &#8211; You know radioactive monsters</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/sustainability/i-never-believed-in-godzilla-you-know-radioactive-monsters/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/sustainability/i-never-believed-in-godzilla-you-know-radioactive-monsters/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 21:37:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[bad health effects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big whoop dee do]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burning behavior]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children and the environment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environmentalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[international environmental groups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[masters of the universe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[no nukes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nuclear power]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outdoors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[schemes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[science fiction]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self inflicted wounds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wild animals]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=8127</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Chernobyl and Fukushima released a lot of radiation. People died from the severe radiation released just after the accident, but &#8220;mild&#8221; consistent radiation is not dangerous to animals though it may have mild effects on adults and bigger effects on &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/sustainability/i-never-believed-in-godzilla-you-know-radioactive-monsters/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/sustainability/i-never-believed-in-godzilla-you-know-radioactive-monsters/">I Never Believed In Godzilla &#8211; You know radioactive monsters</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Chernobyl and Fukushima released a lot of radiation. People died from the severe radiation released just after the accident, but &#8220;mild&#8221; consistent radiation is not dangerous to animals though it may have mild effects on adults and bigger effects on children. But the idea that a major radiation release would create one eyed giant humans or fire breathing dragons like wadzzilla is really remote. The fear of radiation has done some pretty amazing things for the environment, however.</p>
<p><a href="https://getpocket.com/explore/item/8-facts-about-the-animals-of-chernobyl?utm_source=pocket-newtab">https://getpocket.com/explore/item/8-facts-about-the-animals-of-chernobyl?utm_source=pocket-newtab</a></p>
<div class="p1wsrchy">Pocket worthy Stories to fuel your mind.</div>
<header>
<h1 class="huwp7ir">8 Facts About the Animals of Chernobyl</h1>
<h2 class="dbjv4gk">Researchers thought the site of the 1986 Chernobyl disaster was unable to support life. But a bunch of wolves, deer, wild boars, bears, and foxes disagree.</h2>
</header>
<div class="b12pz0kr">
<p><a href="http://mentalfloss.com/?utm_source=pocket">Mental Floss</a></p>
<ul>
<li>Claudia Dimuro</li>
</ul>
</div>
<p class="body"><a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/78779/12-facts-about-chernobyls-exclusion-zone-30-years-after-disaster" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer">Three decades</a> after the Chernobyl disaster—the world’s worst nuclear accident—signs of life are returning to the exclusion zone. Wild animals in Chernobyl <a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/572589/chernobyl-nuclear-disaster-site-thriving-wildlife" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer">are flourishing</a> within the contaminated region; <a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/571660/chernobyl-disaster-puppies-adopted-in-north-america" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer">puppies</a> roaming the area are capturing the hearts of thousands. <a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/585497/chernobyl-miniseries-prompts-spike-travel-chernobyl-exclusion-zone" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer">Tourists</a> who have watched the critically acclaimed HBO series <em>Chernobyl</em> are <a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/585692/chernobyl-creator-urges-exclusion-zone-visitors-to-behave" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer">taking selfies</a> with the ruins. Once thought to be forever uninhabitable, the Chernobyl Exclusion Zone has become a haven for flora and fauna that prove that life, as they say in <a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/49904/20-things-you-might-not-have-known-about-jurassic-park" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer"><em>Jurassic Park</em></a>, <a href="https://youtu.be/oijEsqT2QKQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">finds a way</a>.</p>
<h2 class="body title">1. The Animals of Chernobyl Survived Against All Odds</h2>
<p class="body">The effects of the radioactive explosion at the Chernobyl nuclear power plant on April 26, 1986 devastated the environment. Around the plant and in the nearby city of Pripyat in Ukraine, the Chernobyl disaster’s radiation caused the leaves of thousands of trees to turn a rust color, giving a new name to the surrounding woods—the <a href="https://www.inverse.com/article/56235-chernobyl-exclusion-zone-33-years-later-wildlife" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Red Forest</a>. Workers eventually bulldozed and buried the radioactive trees. Squads of Soviet conscripts also were ordered to <a href="https://www.bustle.com/p/what-happened-to-the-dogs-of-chernobyl-the-harrowing-events-of-the-tv-series-are-sadly-true-17928470" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">shoot</a> any stray animals within the 1000-square-mile Chernobyl Exclusion Zone. Though experts today believe parts of the zone will remain unsafe for humans for another <a href="https://www.livescience.com/39961-chernobyl.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">20,000 years</a>, numerous animal and plant species not only survived, but thrived.</p>
<h2 class="body title">2. Bears and Wolves Outnumber Humans Around the Chernobyl Disaster Site</h2>
<p class="body">While humans are strictly prohibited from living in the Chernobyl Exclusion Zone, many other species have settled there. Brown bears, wolves, <a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/33677/canada-lynx-ghost-cat-north" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer">lynx</a>, <a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/59248/whats-difference-between-bison-and-buffalo" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer">bison</a>, deer, <a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/59461/10-gigantic-facts-about-moose" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer">moose</a>, beavers, foxes, <a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/64760/10-resourceful-facts-about-badgers" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer">badgers</a>, wild boar, <a href="https://www.mentalfloss.com/article/70797/12-surprising-facts-about-raccoon-dogs" target="_self" rel="noopener noreferrer">raccoon dogs</a>, and more than 200 species of birds have formed their own ecosystem within the Chernobyl disaster area. Along with the larger animals, a variety of amphibians, fish, worms, and bacteria makes the unpopulated environment their home.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/sustainability/i-never-believed-in-godzilla-you-know-radioactive-monsters/">I Never Believed In Godzilla &#8211; You know radioactive monsters</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/sustainability/i-never-believed-in-godzilla-you-know-radioactive-monsters/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
