<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>spain Archives - Community Energy Systems</title>
	<atom:link href="/censys/category/blog/spain/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/censys/category/blog/spain/</link>
	<description>Censys.org</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 19:53:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Happy Columbus Day &#8211; What a guy</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/happy-holidays/happy-columbus-day-what-a-guy/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/happy-holidays/happy-columbus-day-what-a-guy/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2011 15:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[big whoop dee do]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christianity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy Tough Love Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gone pecan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[happy holidays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[playing hooky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vacation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=3297</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Since he never set foot in this country it is a dubious honor, but any excuse for a day off is good. :} Go there and read. More tomorrow. :}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/happy-holidays/happy-columbus-day-what-a-guy/">Happy Columbus Day &#8211; What a guy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Since he never set foot in this country it is a dubious honor, but any excuse for a day off is good.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read. More tomorrow.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/happy-holidays/happy-columbus-day-what-a-guy/">Happy Columbus Day &#8211; What a guy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/happy-holidays/happy-columbus-day-what-a-guy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Wind Offshore When &#8211; Maybe soon, maybe manana</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/wind-offshore-when-maybe-soon-maybe-monana/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/wind-offshore-when-maybe-soon-maybe-monana/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Feb 2011 18:44:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[advanced energy structures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burn free generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy Tough Love Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gaia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[horizontal turbine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[horizontal wind turbine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Other countries advances]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wind power]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=2662</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>This has an interesting storage system however so read the rest of the article. http://www.green-energy-news.com/arch/nrgs2011/20110012.html February 13, 2011 – Vol.15 No.48 OFFSHORE WIND ENERGY MEETS OFFSHORE WIND ENERGY STORAGE. by Bruce Mulliken, Green Energy News Eventually the United States will &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/wind-offshore-when-maybe-soon-maybe-monana/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/wind-offshore-when-maybe-soon-maybe-monana/">Wind Offshore When &#8211; Maybe soon, maybe manana</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This has an interesting storage system however so read the rest of the article.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.green-energy-news.com/arch/nrgs2011/20110012.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">http://www.green-energy-news.com/arch/nrgs2011/20110012.html</a></p>
<table border="0" cellspacing="0" cellpadding="0" width="181">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="1" height="1"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="http://www.green-energy-news.com/Resources/_clear.gif" border="0" alt="" width="1" height="1" /></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>February 13, 2011 – Vol.15  No.48</p>
<p><strong>OFFSHORE WIND ENERGY MEETS OFFSHORE WIND ENERGY STORAGE.</strong><br />
<em>by Bruce Mulliken, Green Energy News </em></p>
<p>Eventually  the United States will get its first offshore wind farm. No one is  taking bets as to when it will go online. There have been many  proposals, but so far resistance onshore has kept those projects from  being built.</p>
<p>Still, wind resources are much better  offshore than on and those windy resources are often near heavily  populated areas that will be able and willing to consume electricity  generated by those reliable ocean breezes.</p>
<p>As with  many relatively expensive technologies it’s not such a bad thing to be a  late adopter. Early adopters make and have to correct mistakes at a  high cost. Early adopters too have only earliest versions of the  technology to work with.  Late adopters, on the other hand, learn from  the mistakes of early adopters and need not repeat them. Late adopters  also get to use newer, more sophisticated versions of the technology in  question.</p>
<p>Offshore wind is one of those relatively expensive technologies that it’s OK to be a late adopter.</p>
<p>When  U.S. offshore wind builders finally get around to planting the first  turbine in the ocean bottom (or perhaps floating turbines in deep water  over the horizon) they’ll have a better idea of the costs, know exactly  how to install them and they’ll have access to far more powerful  turbines than those used in the first offshore wind farms in Europe. The  U.S. will benefit by being slow to adopt offshore wind, but the time  has come to embrace the technology; wind developers know this, so does  the U.S. government.</p>
<p>Even as dollars are being  pinched in Washington, the Department of Energy has put aside $50.5  million for projects that support offshore wind energy development. The  Department of the Interior too, in its Smart for the Start program, has  given a hand to offshore wind development by designating four areas  along the Mid-Atlantic coast to be on the fast track for regulatory  approval.</p>
<p>The funding being offered by DOE can be  used for the development of innovative wind turbine design tools and  hardware to provide the foundation for a cost-competitive and  world-class offshore wind industry in the United States (up to $25  million over 5 years); for baseline studies and targeted environmental  research to characterize key industry sectors and factors limiting the  deployment of offshore wind ( up to $18 million over 3 years); and for  the development and refinement of next-generation designs for wind  turbine drivetrains (up to $7.5 million over 3 years).</p>
<p>The  Department of the Interior has chosen areas on the Outer Continental  Shelf offshore Delaware (122 square nautical miles), Maryland (207), New  Jersey (417), and Virginia (165) to receive early environmental reviews  that will help to lessen the time required for review, leasing and  approval of offshore wind turbine facilities.</p>
<p>Government isn’t alone in seeking to develop offshore wind.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>More manana.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/wind-offshore-when-maybe-soon-maybe-monana/">Wind Offshore When &#8211; Maybe soon, maybe manana</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/wind-offshore-when-maybe-soon-maybe-monana/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chicago Media Shun The Wind Power 2009 Conference &#8211; Oh the bankrupt Tribue ran an op/ed piece about government intervention</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/chicago-media-shun-the-wind-power-2009-conference-oh-the-bankrupt-tribue-ran-an-oped-piece-about-government-intervention/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/chicago-media-shun-the-wind-power-2009-conference-oh-the-bankrupt-tribue-ran-an-oped-piece-about-government-intervention/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2009 16:11:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[advanced energy structures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burn free generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cool sites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electricity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy Tough Love Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fossil fuels and the United States' Future]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gaia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[global warming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[horizontal turbine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[horizontal wind turbine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[penetrating ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spirituality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stewardship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stimulating intercourse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stretching a concept]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vertical turbine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wind power]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=979</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>But you would think that a convention/conference that brings 15,000 participants, represents the future and is in a city with a mayor, Richard Daley, who wants to be the greenest governor in the US, that there would be some coverage &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/chicago-media-shun-the-wind-power-2009-conference-oh-the-bankrupt-tribue-ran-an-oped-piece-about-government-intervention/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/chicago-media-shun-the-wind-power-2009-conference-oh-the-bankrupt-tribue-ran-an-oped-piece-about-government-intervention/">Chicago Media Shun The Wind Power 2009 Conference &#8211; Oh the bankrupt Tribue ran an op/ed piece about government intervention</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>But you would think that a convention/conference that brings 15,000 participants, represents the future and is in a city with a mayor, Richard Daley, who wants to be the greenest governor in the US, that there would be some coverage of &#8220;The Latest In Wind Technologies&#8221; or &#8220;Where Does Chicago Fit Into The New Energy Future&#8221; or at least an address by the Mayor. NADA Zilch Nothing. Other people noticed however:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.businesswire.com/portal/site/google/?ndmViewId=news_view&amp;newsId=20090504006376&amp;newsLang=en">http://www.businesswire.com/portal/site/google/?ndmViewId=news_view&amp;newsId=20090504006376&amp;newsLang=en</a></p>
<p class="story_dateline"> 					 						<a href="http://www.businesswire.com/news/google/20090504006376/en" onclick="return false;" class="permalink" title="To save a permanent link to this news, right-click (Ctl-click on a Mac) and choose the command to copy the link, link location or shortcut."> 					 							May 04, 2009 07:30 PM Eastern Daylight Time  					 						<img decoding="async" src="http://www.businesswire.com/images/icons/icon_permalink.gif" class="icon" /> 						</a></p>
<h1 class="epi-fontLg bwtextaligncenter">       <strong>World Business Chicago Facilitates International Networking at        WINDPOWER 2009 Conference</strong></h1>
<p id="story_subheadline">&nbsp;</p>
<p><!-- GENRE NOTES BEGIN --></p>
<p class="story_genre_notes">WINDPOWER 2009</p>
<p><!-- GENRE NOTES END --> 					  					<!-- start story body -->CHICAGO&#8211;(<a href="http://www.businesswire.com/">BUSINESS WIRE</a>)&#8211;World Business Chicago (WBC) and its Chairman, Mayor Richard M. Daley,        in conjunction with other key public, private and non-profit partners,        tonight hosted a VIP networking reception as part of the American Wind        Energy Association’s (AWEA) WINDPOWER 2009 Conference and Exhibition at        Chicago’s McCormick Place.</p>
<p>The reception, with more than 200 people in attendance, was presented by        a collaboration of organizations including the AWEA (Organizer/Sponsor),        WBC (Organizer/Sponsor), MEGA (Sponsor), the City of Chicago        (Organizer), the State of Illinois (Organizer) and the Illinois Finance        Authority (Organizer).</p>
<p>The wind power industry is a top economic development priority for WBC,        based on the industry’s high growth potential, profitability, job        creation/diversity, and wage levels. Chicago offers wind industry        companies locational advantages including a skilled labor force,        proximity to markets and supplies, natural sources of wind in Illinois        and the Midwest, available real estate, access to airports, rail and        highway systems and strong public sector commitments to wind industry        use and production.</p>
<p>“The WINDPOWER Conference provides World Business Chicago with a        wonderful opportunity to showcase Chicago’s position as a prime location        for wind power companies,” said Rita Athas, executive director of World        Business Chicago. “By hosting this event, we are facilitating dialogue        between visiting and local wind power companies, Chicago area companies        that may do business with them and our local leaders, in order to foster        growth and new opportunities.”</p>
<p>The Chicago area’s locational advantages for the wind industry are        evident in recent additions of notable wind power companies include:</p>
<p><span class="bwunderlinestyle">Area Headquarters</span></p>
<ul>
<li class="bwlistitemmarginbottom">         Acciona N. America HQ</li>
<li class="bwlistitemmarginbottom">         E.ON N. America Climate &amp; Renewables HQ</li>
<li class="bwlistitemmarginbottom">         Nordex USA Inc. HQ</li>
<li class="bwlistitemmarginbottom">         Suzlon Wind Energy Corporation N. American HQ</li>
<li class="bwlistitemmarginbottom">         Invenergy LLC HQ</li>
<li class="bwlistitemmarginbottom">         Midwest Wind Energy LLC HQ</li>
<li class="bwlistitemmarginbottom">         Trintek Energy Consulting HQ</li>
<li class="bwlistitemmarginbottom">         Wind for Illinois HQ</li>
</ul>
<p><span class="bwunderlinestyle">Area Non-Headquarter Offices</span></p>
<ul>
<li class="bwlistitemmarginbottom">         Vestas America</li>
<li class="bwlistitemmarginbottom">         Horizon Wind Energy</li>
<li class="bwlistitemmarginbottom">         Siemens Energy &amp; Automation</li>
<li class="bwlistitemmarginbottom">         Winergy Drive Systems Corporation – subsidiary of Siemens</li>
</ul>
<p>WINDPOWER 2009, the largest annual wind conference and exhibition in the        world, takes place May 4th &#8211; 7th, 2009. The show features more than        18,000 attendees and 1,200 exhibitors and is expected to generate an        economic impact of more than $33.3-million to Chicago, according to the        Chicago Convention and Tourism Bureau (based on the initial estimated        attendance of 14,000). Approximately 80 Illinois companies will exhibit        at the conference.</p>
<p>The 2009 show was originally set for Minneapolis and moved to Chicago to        accommodate a 20% increase over expected attendance, which doubles last        year’s show in Houston. WINDPOWER is one of the 50 fastest-growing shows        in North America according to Trade Show Weekly. Chicago hosted AWEA’s        convention in 2004, when it drew 3,000 attendees.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Everything you need to know to get there:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.renewableenergyworld.com/rea/events/view?id=45803">http://www.renewableenergyworld.com/rea/events/view?id=45803 </a></p>
<h1 class="contentHeader">Siterra Booth 5580 at Wind Power 2009</h1>
<table class="contentIntroTable" cellpadding="0" cellspacing="0">
<tr id="eventCompanyLabel">
<td class="rowLabel">Company:</td>
<td><a href="http://www.renewableenergyworld.com/rea/partner/siterra-corporation;jsessionid=B924ADDCF6BDE9AF848FAB35CDF0AE3E" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Siterra Corporation</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="rowLabel">Start date:</td>
<td>May 4, 2009</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="rowLabel">End date:</td>
<td>May 7, 2009</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="rowLabel">Cost:</td>
<td>see AWEA.com</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="rowLabel">Location:</td>
<td>McCormick Convention Center, Chicago IL</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="rowLabel">Website:</td>
<td><a href="http://www.windpowerexpo.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Visit event website</a></td>
</tr>
</table>
<p>Siterra will have a booth (5580) at the AWEA Wind Power 2009 Expo in Chicago May 4-7.</p>
<p style="margin-bottom: 15px">WINDPOWER 2009 Conference and Exhibition is the largest annual wind conference and exhibition in the world featuring over 15,000 attendees and over 1,200 exhibitors. Each year, wind energy professionals gather at this event to learn about the latest industry developments and technologies, review new products and services in the expansive exhibit hall, and network with leading industry decision makers. Join us for what promises to be another exciting event taking place May 4th &#8211; 7th, 2009, at McCormick Place Convention Center in Chicago, Illinois.<br />
<strong style="color: #333333"> 			Directions: 		</strong><br />
McCormick Place Convention Center</p>
<p>Welcome to Chicago&#8217;s McCormick Place, a premier convention facility in North America. Located just minutes from downtown Chicago, McCormick Place is owned and operated by the Metropolitan Pier and Exposition Authority (MPEA) and attracts close to 3 million visitors each year. McCormick Place is comprised of four state-of-the-art buildings: the North and South Buildings, the West Building and Lakeside Center. Together, they form what many consider to be the economic engine that powers the entire convention and tradeshow industry. McCormick Place is committed to creating a great experience for every person, every time!</p>
<p>For a map of McCormick Place Convention Center:  http://www.mccormickplace.com/floorplans/map_index.html</p>
<p>For more information:  http://www.mccormickplace.com/index.html</p>
<p>Exhibitors: For information on exhibiting in Chicago, FOCUS One utilities, and guidelines and services, visit http://www.mccormickplace.com/exhibitor/exhibitor_01.html.</p>
<p>Guest Services:  Click here to open a .pdf document outlining some of the guest services at McCormick Place Convention Center.</p>
<p>Accessibility Map:  Click here to open a .pdf map showing  the location of all elevators for wheelchair access.<br />
For additional disability services at the convention center, visit http://www.mccormickplace.com/facilities/disabilities.html</p>
<p>Meeting Room Rentals: Interested in renting a meeting room at the convention center or connected Hyatt Regency McCormick Place hotel? Contact Stefanie Brown at sbrown@awea.org to receive additional information and a meeting room request form.</p>
<p>Parking at the McCormick Place Convention Center: There are several parking lots nearby to the McCormick Place facility including, South, North and West Buildings, Lakeside Center, Hyatt Regency McCormick Place, and Soldier Field South Lot. The parking rate is currently $19 per day (one time access). Or exhibitors may order a parking permit that allows for in-and-out privileges for $23.75. Click here to visit the parking &amp; directions part of the McCormick Place website for more information. Please note &#8211; the parking information is subject to change and listed here as helpful information for conference attendees.</p>
<p>Driving Directions and Additional Parking Information for the McCormick Place Convention Center: http://www.mccormickplace.com/maps_direct/maps_dir.html<br />
<strong style="color: #333333"> 			Contact: 		</strong><br />
Barbara Martin<br />
barbara.martin@siterra.com<br />
415-875-7114:}</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/chicago-media-shun-the-wind-power-2009-conference-oh-the-bankrupt-tribue-ran-an-oped-piece-about-government-intervention/">Chicago Media Shun The Wind Power 2009 Conference &#8211; Oh the bankrupt Tribue ran an op/ed piece about government intervention</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/chicago-media-shun-the-wind-power-2009-conference-oh-the-bankrupt-tribue-ran-an-oped-piece-about-government-intervention/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Juche &#8211; a simple name for a nasty idea. Kim Il Sungism</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/burning-behavior/juche-a-simple-name-for-a-nasty-idea-kim-il-sungism/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/burning-behavior/juche-a-simple-name-for-a-nasty-idea-kim-il-sungism/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2008 14:50:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[2008 elections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced energy structures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bali Protocols]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burn free generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burning behavior]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burning reduction methods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cartoons]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[christianity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cool sites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy conservation measures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy Tough Love Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flatulence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fossil fuels and the United States' Future]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fraud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gaia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[garbage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[german engineering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[global warming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[happy birthday to me]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[happy holidays]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hip club hopper]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[horizontal turbine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[international energy groups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[international environmental groups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[local environmentalists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[methane production]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[national organizations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[no nukes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[old tired advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Other countries advances]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[over population]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pollution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[portugal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[presidential candidates]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[religious]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[schemes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[software]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar power]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spirituality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[springfield energy scene]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[state fair]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stewardship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[the bible]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vegan comedian]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vertical turbine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weird bird friday]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[why the U.S. is behind]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wild animals]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wind power]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=425</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Jodie Foster, Pregnant Man, Iran, Prince Philip, Brad Pitt, Angelina Jolie, American Idol, Obama, China, Beyonce, Rolling Stones. (sorry for the deception but please read below) Normally I wouldn&#8217;t bother to cover this but since it&#8217;s on the list I &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/burning-behavior/juche-a-simple-name-for-a-nasty-idea-kim-il-sungism/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burning-behavior/juche-a-simple-name-for-a-nasty-idea-kim-il-sungism/">Juche &#8211; a simple name for a nasty idea. Kim Il Sungism</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Jodie Foster, Pregnant Man, Iran, Prince Philip, Brad Pitt, Angelina Jolie, American Idol, Obama, China, Beyonce, Rolling Stones. (sorry for the deception but please read below)</p>
<p>Normally I wouldn&#8217;t bother to cover this but since it&#8217;s on the list I felt I needed to &#8220;dis&#8221; it as much as I could. I even took the time to get Buzzes top searches for the week to punch it up a bit. I even checked every category Energy Tough Love has to publicize this human indignity. The list of &#8220;Religions&#8221; that I used to start this meditation on the relationship between Religion and the Environment placed Juche well down on the list but with 18 million adherents that still alot of folks. I had never heard of it before and I even asked a couple of people if they had heard of it. Imagine my suprise when I typed it into a search engine and up popped this Prick who claimed he was god:</p>
<p><font size="2" color="#008000"><a href="http://www.dictatorofthemonth.com/">www.dictatorofthemonth.com</a></font></p>
<p><a href="/censys/wp-content/uploads/2008/04/kim.jpg" title="kim.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/censys/wp-content/uploads/2008/04/kim.jpg" alt="kim.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>During his lifetime he forced millions of people in North Korea to worship him. Can you imagine anything more degrading or disgusting then a man who points a loaded gun at your head and demands that you treat him like a god. You must pray to him. Oh most Divine Leader. Makes me want to puke. But then he is followed by this buffoon:</p>
<p><font size="2" color="#008000"><font size="2" color="#008000"><a href="http://www.beconfused.com/">www.beconfused.com</a></font></font></p>
<p><a href="/censys/wp-content/uploads/2008/04/jong.jpg" title="jong.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/censys/wp-content/uploads/2008/04/jong.jpg" alt="jong.jpg" /></a></p>
<p>Now they are &#8220;worshiping&#8221; something no better than a trained monkey. If they had an ENVIRONMENTAL group in North Korea, I wish them the best of luck but I ain&#8217;t gonna publish it. I ain&#8217;t even gona type it into a search engine. If anybody ever deserved to get a nuke shoved up his poop shoot. This would be it.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burning-behavior/juche-a-simple-name-for-a-nasty-idea-kim-il-sungism/">Juche &#8211; a simple name for a nasty idea. Kim Il Sungism</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/burning-behavior/juche-a-simple-name-for-a-nasty-idea-kim-il-sungism/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Do Windsor, Co. and West Branch Ia. Have That Springfield, Il. Doesn&#8217;t</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/what-do-windsor-co-and-west-branch-ia-have-that-springfield-il-doesnt/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/what-do-windsor-co-and-west-branch-ia-have-that-springfield-il-doesnt/#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2008 18:50:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[advanced energy structures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burn free generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy Tough Love Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[global warming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[portugal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spain]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vertical turbine]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wind power]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=376</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>The answer to that is a Wind Turbine Blade manufacturing plant. Poor Galesburg, Illinois (pop. 25,000) must consider itself star crossed.  First it loses manufacturing jobs because plants like Amana close and then it loses Acciona&#8217;s proposal to retrofit a new plant for &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/what-do-windsor-co-and-west-branch-ia-have-that-springfield-il-doesnt/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/what-do-windsor-co-and-west-branch-ia-have-that-springfield-il-doesnt/">What Do Windsor, Co. and West Branch Ia. Have That Springfield, Il. Doesn&#8217;t</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The answer to that is a Wind Turbine Blade manufacturing plant. Poor Galesburg, Illinois (pop. 25,000) must consider itself star crossed.  First it loses manufacturing jobs because plants like Amana close and then it loses Acciona&#8217;s proposal to retrofit a new plant for Blade Production, which could have replaced those jobs. But at least they competed. Where was a town like Springfield when all this was going on? Nowhere to be seen.</p>
<p>West Branch, Ia is a city with a population of 2,500 and boasts to be the birth place of President Herbert Hoover. Winslow, Co. is a town with a  population of 15,000 that doesn&#8217;t boast about much. So what do they have in common? They have seen the Energy Future and it is Green.</p>
<p style="background: white; margin: 0in -165.25pt 0pt 38.15pt" class="MsoNormal"><font size="2" face="Arial">Horizon Wind Energy</font></p>
<p><font size="2"><font face="Arial"> </font></font><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; color: black"><font face="Arial">•</font><span style="font: 7pt 'Times New Roman'">          </span></span><font face="Arial"><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; color: black; letter-spacing: 0.1pt">Corporate<span>     </span>headquarters: </span><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; color: black; letter-spacing: -0.25pt">Houston.The parent company, Ene</span><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; color: black; letter-spacing: -0.1pt">gias de Portugal, is the largest utili­</span><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; color: black; letter-spacing: -0.15pt">ty in Portugal. EDP has more than 1 </span><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; color: black; letter-spacing: -0.05pt">million customers worldwide.</span></font></p>
<p><font face="Arial"><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; color: black; letter-spacing: -0.05pt"></span><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; color: black"></span></font><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; color: black"><font face="Arial">•</font><span style="font: 7pt 'Times New Roman'">          </span></span><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; color: black"><font face="Arial">More than 200 U.S. employees with regional offices in Illinois, <span style="letter-spacing: 0.1pt">California, Oregon,Colorado and </span><span style="letter-spacing: -0.1pt">Minnesota.</span></font></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; color: black"><font face="Arial"><span style="letter-spacing: -0.1pt"></span></font></span><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; color: black"><font face="Arial">•</font><span style="font: 7pt 'Times New Roman'">          </span></span><font face="Arial"><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; color: black; letter-spacing: 0.55pt">Wind farms operating or </span><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; color: black; letter-spacing: -0.15pt">under construction in Illinois, Texas,</span><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; color: black; letter-spacing: -0.25pt">New York, Iowa, Oregon, Pennsylva­</span><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; color: black; letter-spacing: -0.1pt">nia and Minnesota.</span></font></p>
<p><font face="Arial"><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; color: black; letter-spacing: -0.1pt"></span></font></p>
<p><font face="Arial"><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; color: black; letter-spacing: -0.1pt"></span></font><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; color: black"></span></p>
<p><a href="/censys/wp-content/uploads/2008/03/clip_image002.jpg" title="clip_image002.jpg"><img decoding="async" src="/censys/wp-content/uploads/2008/03/clip_image002.jpg" alt="clip_image002.jpg" /></a><span style="font-size: 7.5pt; color: black; letter-spacing: -0.05pt"><font face="Arial"><strong> </strong></font></span></p>
<p><strong><span style="font-size: 7.5pt; color: black; letter-spacing: -0.05pt"><font face="Arial">Jack Dempsey/The Associated Press</font></span></strong></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 9.5pt; color: black; font-family: Arial; letter-spacing: -0.25pt">A wind turbine blade is displayed Wednesday during </span><span style="font-size: 9.5pt; color: black; font-family: Arial; letter-spacing: -0.3pt">the opening of a Vestas factory in Windsor, Colo. The </span><span style="font-size: 9.5pt; color: black; font-family: Arial; letter-spacing: -0.15pt">world&#8217;s largest wind-turbine maker, based in Denmark, opened its first plant in Colorado in 2007.</span><br />
&gt;</p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt" class="MsoNormal"><span style="color: blue"><font face="Times New Roman">Which is about the same time that Acciona announced that they had chosen West Branch as their site to build their plant. See these guys are in a competition to be the next world economic leaders while Springfield continues to sprawl uselessly and gears up to medically treat the aging baby boomers. What happens after the boomers die? Who cares.</font></span></p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt" class="MsoNormal"><span style="color: blue"></span></p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt" class="MsoNormal"><span style="color: blue"></span></p>
<p style="margin: 0in 0in 0pt" class="MsoNormal"><span style="color: blue"></span></p>
<p><a href="http://windintell.blogspot.com/2008/01/usa-manufacturing-begins-for-spains.html">http://windintell.blogspot.com/2008/01/usa-manufacturing-begins-for-spains.html</a></p>
<h1 style="margin-top: 0px" class="head">Acciona Windpower&#8217;s</h1>
<h1 style="margin-top: 0px" class="head">West Branch plant in</h1>
<h1 style="margin-top: 0px" class="head"> production</h1>
<p id="Byline">By David DeWitte<br />
The Gazette</p>
<p>WEST BRANCH — Iowa Gov. Chet Culver got a look at Acciona Windpower&#8217;s first American-made wind turbine and an invitation to the running of the bulls in Pamplona, Spain, here Thursday.</p>
<p>The new wind turbine plant turned out its first AW-1500 wind turbine last month, less than seven months after work on the company&#8217;s first North American factory here began.</p>
<p>At a dedication ceremony Thursday, Acciona Windpower Director General Pedro Ruiz said the plant&#8217;s ability to meet its rapid startup timetable &#8220;gives us great confidence for the future.&#8221;</p>
<p>Ruiz also discussed the company&#8217;s plans for a second round of investment in the plant after it reaches full production. The company plans to use the 36-acre West Branch site to begin assembling its larger 3-megawatt AW-3000 wind turbines that are now under development. A timetable for launching the product has not been announced.</p>
<p>The plant is the fourth worldwide production facility for Acciona Windpower, a division of Pamplona, Spain-based Acciona Energy. It is scheduled to turn out 200 turbines in 2008, and 400 units at full capacity.</p>
<p>&gt;</p>
<p><span style="color: blue"><font face="Times New Roman">The thing that continues to frustrate me is that they erect those wind farms here in Illinois. So why can&#8217;t they build the parts here as well? Oh the 2 winning town have another thing in common, the two companies are from the Spanish Pennsula, that is Portugal and Spain. Where are Commonwealth Edison and Ameren when you need them?</font></span></p>
<p><span style="color: blue"><font face="Times New Roman">I have posted Acciona&#8217;s website and what I could about their North American affiliate before but not for Horizon or Energias de Portugal:</font></span><br />
&gt;<br />
About Horizon Wind Energy</p>
<p>Horizon Wind Energy develops, constructs, owns and operates wind farms throughout<br />
the United States. Based in Houston, Texas with regional offices in New York, Oregon,<br />
Illinois, California, Denver and Minnesota, Horizon has developed more than 2000 MW<br />
and owns over 1300 MW of operating wind farms. Horizon is currently developing a<br />
portfolio of more than 10,500 MW in over a dozen states. Horizon is owned by Energias<br />
de Portugal (EDP), the largest Portuguese utility. For more information, please visit<br />
<a href="http://www.horizonwind.com/">www.horizonwind.com</a></p>
<p><a href="http://www.edp.pt/EDPI/Internet/EN/Group/AboutEDP/default.htm">http://www.edp.pt/EDPI/Internet/EN/Group/AboutEDP/default.htm</a><br />
&gt;</p>
<p>Their motto &#8211; Feel our energy</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/what-do-windsor-co-and-west-branch-ia-have-that-springfield-il-doesnt/">What Do Windsor, Co. and West Branch Ia. Have That Springfield, Il. Doesn&#8217;t</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/what-do-windsor-co-and-west-branch-ia-have-that-springfield-il-doesnt/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
