<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>energy conservation measures Archives - Community Energy Systems</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/blog/energy-conservation-measures/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/category/blog/energy-conservation-measures/</link>
	<description>Censys.org</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 18:59:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Advice On Saving Energy At Home &#8211; Not from me mind you, someone who creates content for CIELOWiggle</title>
		<link>/blog/residential-energy-efficiency/advice-on-saving-energy-at-home-not-from-me-mind-you-someone-who-creates-content-for-cielo/</link>
					<comments>/blog/residential-energy-efficiency/advice-on-saving-energy-at-home-not-from-me-mind-you-someone-who-creates-content-for-cielo/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 16:21:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[air conditioning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burning reduction methods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[efficient refrigerators]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy conservation measures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[radiant barriers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[residential energy efficiency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[roofs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar power]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water efficiency]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=8493</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I know it has been awhile since I did a residential post. I know this started out as a blog about residential energy needs and services. You know, energy efficient roofs, HVAC equipment and other such stuff. But years ago, &#8230; <a href="/blog/residential-energy-efficiency/advice-on-saving-energy-at-home-not-from-me-mind-you-someone-who-creates-content-for-cielo/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/blog/residential-energy-efficiency/advice-on-saving-energy-at-home-not-from-me-mind-you-someone-who-creates-content-for-cielo/">Advice On Saving Energy At Home &#8211; Not from me mind you, someone who creates content for CIELOWiggle</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I know it has been awhile since I did a residential post. I know this started out as a blog about residential energy needs and services. You know, energy efficient roofs, HVAC equipment and other such stuff. But years ago, I got off on energy related environmental stuff and then eventually Global Warming. Then anti-Nuclear stuff. Finally just raw Environmental stuff like obnoxious polluting and horrible deaths. Well today a gentleman named Chris Winters reached out and touched me so I am touching him back, so to speak. As always, I can vouch for his tips because they are somewhat general, but anything specific he is pitching I can not (For instance AC controllers &#8211; which his company sells). Also I may have put up this as an addenda to any earlier piece, so if i did forgive me.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.cielowigle.com/blog/energy-saving-tips/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://www.cielowigle.com/blog/energy-saving-tips/</a></p>
<p>No matter what the season, energy usage tends to increase one way or another. With long running air conditioning and increased wash cycles of sweaty laundry in summer, to high heating usage and wash cycles of bulkier laundry in winter, we simply cannot operate without electricity.</p>
<p>We can be extremely energy efficient and follow energy saving tips and tricks to ingrain some environmentally friendly habits.</p>
<p>Following energy saving tips is essential to lower your costs, but it is also important to decrease your ecological footprint.</p>
<p>With <a href="https://www.capgemini.com/2020/08/generation-green-is-leading-the-sustainability-agenda/">millennials and Gen Z nicknamed “generation green”</a>, there is a strong focus on energy saving, and rightly so. However, global warming is rising more rapidly than ever, and the term ‘climate emergency’ is being used rather than climate change to highlight the situation’s intensity.</p>
<p>All industries such as <a href="https://www.cielowigle.com/blog/climate-change/">HVAC are revolutionizing their technology to act on climate change</a>. Since home appliances and devices are a major contributor to our energy consumption, utilizing smart devices such as smart thermostats or <a href="https://www.cielowigle.com/">smart controllers for air conditioners</a> can make a huge difference on your bills!</p>
<p>Let’s get right to it. Here are 21 energy saving tips that can easily help you decrease your energy consumption:</p>
<h2 id="h-1-use-energy-efficient-appliances">1. Use Energy Efficient Appliances</h2>
<p>Energy efficient appliances are specially designed to consume minimum energy to complete the same tasks that you’d perform with normal appliances.  In addition, some</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Good there and read. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/blog/residential-energy-efficiency/advice-on-saving-energy-at-home-not-from-me-mind-you-someone-who-creates-content-for-cielo/">Advice On Saving Energy At Home &#8211; Not from me mind you, someone who creates content for CIELOWiggle</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/blog/residential-energy-efficiency/advice-on-saving-energy-at-home-not-from-me-mind-you-someone-who-creates-content-for-cielo/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tankless Water Heaters Are Grand &#8211; This piece goes to great lengths to prove it</title>
		<link>/blog/residential-energy-efficiency/tankless-water-heaters-are-grand-this-piece-goes-to-great-lengths-to-prove/</link>
					<comments>/blog/residential-energy-efficiency/tankless-water-heaters-are-grand-this-piece-goes-to-great-lengths-to-prove/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 19:03:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burning reduction methods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy conservation measures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[residential energy efficiency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water conservation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water efficiency]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=8424</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>First off, spell check does not like the word tankless. You would think by now that the people at WORD Press would have gotten over that spelling by now. Second off (to be consistent) this is not and article that &#8230; <a href="/blog/residential-energy-efficiency/tankless-water-heaters-are-grand-this-piece-goes-to-great-lengths-to-prove/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/blog/residential-energy-efficiency/tankless-water-heaters-are-grand-this-piece-goes-to-great-lengths-to-prove/">Tankless Water Heaters Are Grand &#8211; This piece goes to great lengths to prove it</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>First off, spell check does not like the word tankless. You would think by now that the people at WORD Press would have gotten over that spelling by now. Second off (to be consistent) this is not and article that CES can defend or debate. It is an article generated by another site so &#8220;Buyer Beware&#8221;. The articles has a lot of extraneous Ads and unnecessary clutter. Please feel free to ignore all of that. I have read the article and for the most part it is factual, and more extensive then most. So with out further ado:</p>
<p><a href="https://happydiyhome.com/tankless-water-heater-cost/">https://happydiyhome.com/tankless-water-heater-cost/</a></p>
<header class="entry-header">
<h1 class="entry-title">Tankless Water Heater Cost &amp; Pros and Cons – Are They Worth It?</h1>
<div class="entry-meta"><span class="posted-on"><a title="12:26 pm" href="https://happydiyhome.com/tankless-water-heater-cost/" rel="bookmark"><time class="updated" datetime="2020-12-31T14:01:31+00:00">December 31, 2020</time><time class="entry-date published" datetime="2020-12-31T12:26:25+00:00">December 31, 2020</time></a></span> <span class="byline">by <span class="author vcard"><a class="url fn n" title="View all posts by HappyDIYHome Staff" href="https://happydiyhome.com/author/wpx_jenrevie/" rel="author"><span class="author-name">HappyDIYHome Staff</span></a></span></span></div>
</header>
<div class="entry-content">
<p>Water heaters are extremely important to your <a href="https://happydiyhome.com/best-drain-cleaner/">plumbing system</a>, and this goes for both residential buildings and commercial spaces. Many people are turning to newer options, and this can lead you to wonder what a tankless water heater costs because this style of water heater will only heat up the water you use. Traditionally, water heaters heated and stored water on a continuous basis, and this can be expensive if you use a lot of water. As long as they get installed and connected correctly, it’s easy to control your tankless water heater cost for years at a time.</p>
<p>You get the choice of a single point unit or whole house units. A single point unit is slightly more inexpensive to buy and install because you put them right next to a water source. Whole house units cost more to install, but they are powerful enough to heat all of the water in your home at one time. The tankless water heater cost has a slightly wider price range due to a variety of the factors, and it starts at $2,000 and goes up to around $4,500 from start to finish.</p>
<p>The average cost is right around $2,800 for a whole house gas unit. The tankless water heater cost has fluctuating labor rates too. The flow rate, brand, and type will also influence your tankless water heater cost, and this is why you want to get a few estimates before you settle on one company to perform the installation. This can help ensure that you get a fair price with professional-quality results.</p>
</div>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read this very long article. But if you just want to know the pros and cons go to the end. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/blog/residential-energy-efficiency/tankless-water-heaters-are-grand-this-piece-goes-to-great-lengths-to-prove/">Tankless Water Heaters Are Grand &#8211; This piece goes to great lengths to prove it</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/blog/residential-energy-efficiency/tankless-water-heaters-are-grand-this-piece-goes-to-great-lengths-to-prove/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hydrogen May Save The Day &#8211; At least this guy is seriously dedicated to it</title>
		<link>/blog/green-economy/hydrogen-may-save-the-day-at-least-this-guy-is-seriously-dedicated-to-it/</link>
					<comments>/blog/green-economy/hydrogen-may-save-the-day-at-least-this-guy-is-seriously-dedicated-to-it/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 22:08:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[burn free generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy conservation measures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environmentalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stewardship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=8327</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I hope you all have had a happy and SAFE Holiday season. I am not a big fan of hydrogen as an energy source. It can be difficult to handle and it requires a new infrastructure even though some of &#8230; <a href="/blog/green-economy/hydrogen-may-save-the-day-at-least-this-guy-is-seriously-dedicated-to-it/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/blog/green-economy/hydrogen-may-save-the-day-at-least-this-guy-is-seriously-dedicated-to-it/">Hydrogen May Save The Day &#8211; At least this guy is seriously dedicated to it</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I hope you all have had a happy and SAFE Holiday season. I am not a big fan of hydrogen as an energy source. It can be difficult to handle and it requires a new infrastructure even though some of it support don&#8217;t think so. I favor the brute forces of large wind and solar projects because we have a huge electrical infrastructure already in place. With persistence though i think it could come along. California is a big fan however and sometimes, as goes California so goes the nation.</p>
<p>www.nytimes.com/2020/12/28/business/hydrogen-power-cars.html?utm_source=pocket-newtab</p>
<p>(please note you must ad http: to the above address to get to the location. I had to strip it off so the website would not intrude.)</p>
<div class="css-186x18t">
<p class="css-tsacue e6idgb70">Wheels</p>
</div>
<div class="css-1vkm6nb ehdk2mb0">
<h1 id="link-3c763b25" class="css-hzs6w4 e1h9rw200" data-test-id="headline">The Gospel of Hydrogen Power</h1>
</div>
<p id="article-summary" class="css-w6ymp8 e1wiw3jv0">Mike Strizki powers his house and cars with hydrogen he home-brews. He is using his retirement to evangelize for the planet-saving advantages of hydrogen batteries.</p>
<div class="css-1aweabf">
<div class="css-1oommtz">
<div class="css-d8bdto" role="toolbar" aria-label="Social Media Share buttons, Save button, and Comments Panel with current comment count" data-testid="share-tools"></div>
</div>
</div>
<div>
<header class="css-c58brx euiyums1">
<div class="css-18e8msd">
<div class="css-vp77d3 epjyd6m0">
<div class="css-1baulvz">
<p class="css-4z5zii e1jsehar1"><span class="byline-prefix">By </span><span class="css-1baulvz last-byline">Roy Furchgott</span></p>
</div>
</div>
<ul class="css-1u1psjv epjyd6m3">
<li class="css-ccw2r3 epjyd6m1"><time class="css-ld3wwf e16638kd2" datetime="2020-12-28T05:00:24-05:00"><span class="css-1sbuyqj e16638kd3">Dec. 28, 2020</span></time></li>
</ul>
</div>
</header>
</div>
<section class="meteredContent css-1r7ky0e">
<div class="css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn">
<div class="css-53u6y8">
<p class="css-axufdj evys1bk0">In December, the California Fuel Cell Partnership tallied 8,890 electric cars and 48 electric buses running on hydrogen batteries, which are refillable in minutes at any of 42 stations there. On the East Coast, the number of people who own and drive a hydrogen electric car is somewhat lower. In fact, there’s just one. His name is Mike Strizki. He is so devoted to hydrogen fuel-cell energy that he drives a Toyota Mirai even though it requires him to refine hydrogen fuel in his yard himself.</p>
<p class="css-axufdj evys1bk0">“Yeah, I love it,” Mr. Strizki said of his 2017 Mirai. “This car is powerful, there’s no shifting, plus I’m not carrying all of that weight of the batteries,” he said in a not-so-subtle swipe at the world’s most notable hydrogen naysayer, Elon Musk.</p>
<p class="css-axufdj evys1bk0">Mr. Strizki favors fuel-cell cars for the same reasons as most proponents. You can make fuel using water and solar power, as he does. The byproduct of making hydrogen is oxygen, and the byproduct of burning it is water. Hydrogen is among the most plentiful elements on earth, so you don’t have to go to adversarial countries or engage in environmentally destructive extraction to get it. The car is as quiet to drive as any other electric, it requires little maintenance, and because it doesn’t carry 1,200 pounds of batteries, it has a performance edge.</p>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<p>His infatuation with hydrogen began with cars, but it didn’t end there. In 2006 he made the first house in the United States to be <a class="css-1g7m0tk" title="" href="https://www.hydrogenhouseproject.org/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">powered entirely by hydrogen</a> produced on site using solar power. Nine years later he made the second. He says he has built hydrogen-power home systems for conservationists and celebrities — one of his systems reportedly powers Johnny Depp’s private island in the Bahamas.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go There And Read. More Next Week.</p>
<p>}</p>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="The Gospel of Hydrogen Power" src="https://www.nytimes.com/svc/oembed/html/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nytimes.com%2F2020%2F12%2F28%2Fbusiness%2Fhydrogen-power-cars.html#?secret=jjheluQZtV" data-secret="jjheluQZtV" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/blog/green-economy/hydrogen-may-save-the-day-at-least-this-guy-is-seriously-dedicated-to-it/">Hydrogen May Save The Day &#8211; At least this guy is seriously dedicated to it</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/blog/green-economy/hydrogen-may-save-the-day-at-least-this-guy-is-seriously-dedicated-to-it/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>New Improved Better Outstanding Sites &#8211; Or at least that&#8217;s what they say</title>
		<link>/blog/energy-education/new-improved-better-outstanding-sites-or-at-least-thats-what-they-say/</link>
					<comments>/blog/energy-education/new-improved-better-outstanding-sites-or-at-least-thats-what-they-say/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2020 17:11:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[burning reduction methods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy conservation measures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outdoors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[penetrating ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water conservation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=8264</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I preface this whole page by saying &#8211; I AM RETIRED. So I have gotten lazy. Periodically I get requests to LINK to other sites, or &#8211; we read your post and would you publish this ARTICLE, and other related &#8230; <a href="/blog/energy-education/new-improved-better-outstanding-sites-or-at-least-thats-what-they-say/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/blog/energy-education/new-improved-better-outstanding-sites-or-at-least-thats-what-they-say/">New Improved Better Outstanding Sites &#8211; Or at least that&#8217;s what they say</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I preface this whole page by saying &#8211; I AM RETIRED. So I have gotten lazy. Periodically I get requests to LINK to other sites, or &#8211; we read your post and would you publish this ARTICLE, and other related requests. The best that I can do is everyonce in awhile I post their links in a combined page like this:</p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="ztxHpM770t"><p><a href="https://iceblast.com.au/differences-between-commercial-residential-air-conditioning/">40 Differences Between Commercial and Residential Air Conditioning</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;40 Differences Between Commercial and Residential Air Conditioning&#8221; &#8212; Ice Blast Air Conditioning" src="https://iceblast.com.au/differences-between-commercial-residential-air-conditioning/embed/#?secret=ztxHpM770t" data-secret="ztxHpM770t" width="584" height="329" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
<p>&#8230;</p>
<p>Then there is this:</p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="CaHKQc7PrV"><p><a href="https://freshbigbang.com/save-energy/">NO NEED TO BE A HERO TO SAVE ENERGY</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;NO NEED TO BE A HERO TO SAVE ENERGY&#8221; &#8212; Fresh Big Bang" src="https://freshbigbang.com/save-energy/embed/#?secret=CaHKQc7PrV" data-secret="CaHKQc7PrV" width="584" height="329" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
<p>&#8230;</p>
<p>Then there is this:</p>
<p>By the way, I am not sure I think running is good for you but it does save transportation costs. Run Forrest Fun.</p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="2pl8TjeqGU"><p><a href="https://fitnessfornonathletes.com/develop-running-habit/">How to Develop a Lasting Running Habit</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How to Develop a Lasting Running Habit&#8221; &#8212; Non-Athlete Fitness" src="https://fitnessfornonathletes.com/develop-running-habit/embed/#?secret=2pl8TjeqGU" data-secret="2pl8TjeqGU" width="584" height="329" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
<p>&#8230;</p>
<p>Or this, which is more on topic:</p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="5VH9de4mon"><p><a href="https://homelivinglab.com/how-to-stop-climate-change-from-the-comfort-of-your-home/">How to stop climate change from the comfort of your home</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="&#8220;How to stop climate change from the comfort of your home&#8221; &#8212; Home Living Lab" src="https://homelivinglab.com/how-to-stop-climate-change-from-the-comfort-of-your-home/embed/#?secret=5VH9de4mon" data-secret="5VH9de4mon" width="584" height="329" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
<p>Finally for today:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.buildingmaterials.co.uk/nuts-and-bolts/resources/how-to-make-your-home-more-energy-efficient/">https://www.buildingmaterials.co.uk/nuts-and-bolts/resources/how-to-make-your-home-more-energy-efficient/</a></p>
<h1>How to make your home more energy efficient in the UK</h1>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and enjoy. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/blog/energy-education/new-improved-better-outstanding-sites-or-at-least-thats-what-they-say/">New Improved Better Outstanding Sites &#8211; Or at least that&#8217;s what they say</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/blog/energy-education/new-improved-better-outstanding-sites-or-at-least-thats-what-they-say/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>We Can Make A Change &#8211; If we all pull together we can make big change</title>
		<link>/blog/penetrating-ideas/we-can-make-a-change-if-we-all-pull-together-we-can-make-big-change/</link>
					<comments>/blog/penetrating-ideas/we-can-make-a-change-if-we-all-pull-together-we-can-make-big-change/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 20:07:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[burning reduction methods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children and the environment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cool sites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy conservation measures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environmentalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[penetrating ideas]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=8117</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Periodically I try to be up beat. With the Pandemic and all the doom coming out of the environmental community I thought I would say, &#8220;We can do things together&#8221;! The place to start is small. Ride your bike. Recycle &#8230; <a href="/blog/penetrating-ideas/we-can-make-a-change-if-we-all-pull-together-we-can-make-big-change/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/blog/penetrating-ideas/we-can-make-a-change-if-we-all-pull-together-we-can-make-big-change/">We Can Make A Change &#8211; If we all pull together we can make big change</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Periodically I try to be up beat. With the Pandemic and all the doom coming out of the environmental community I thought I would say, &#8220;We can do things together&#8221;! The place to start is small. Ride your bike. Recycle and reduce your garbage. Compost. Walk places when you can. Take the steps not the elevator. I do all of those things and everyday I try to think of more things I can do. Anyway, here are some thoughts on the things we can achieve. Stay safe out there.</p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Rm6kbf7CwU"><p><a href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/climate-change-actions-reduce-carbon-footprint">What lifestyle changes will shrink your carbon footprint the most?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe title="&#8220;What lifestyle changes will shrink your carbon footprint the most?&#8221; &#8212; Science News" class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" style="position: absolute; clip: rect(1px, 1px, 1px, 1px);" src="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/climate-change-actions-reduce-carbon-footprint/embed#?secret=Rm6kbf7CwU" data-secret="Rm6kbf7CwU" width="584" height="329" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
<div class="byline__wrapper___4FOTC">
<div class="byline-inner">
<p class="byline__authors___2KZu0">By <span class="byline author vcard"><a class="byline-link url fn n" href="https://www.sciencenews.org/author/christie-aschwanden">Christie Aschwanden</a></span></p>
<p class="byline__published___3GjAo"><time class="date entry-date byline__published___3GjAo" datetime="2020-05-14T06:00:00-04:00">May 14, 2020 at 6:00 am</time></p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="single__body___XFYC7">
<div class="content">
<div class="rich-text single__rich-text___BlzVF" data-component="video-embed">
<p class="has-drop-cap">Three years ago, Kim Cobb was feeling “completely overwhelmed” by the problem of climate change. Cobb spends her days studying climate change as director of the Global Change Program at Georgia Tech in Atlanta, but she felt paralyzed over how to be part of the solution in her personal life. The barriers felt immense.</p>
<p>She decided to start small. On January 1, 2017, she made a personal climate resolution: She would walk her kids to school and bicycle to work two days a week. That change didn’t represent a lot in terms of carbon emissions, she says, “but it was a huge lesson in daily engagement.”</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>In the beginning, her modest goal seemed daunting, but she quickly discovered that the two simple activities nourished her physical and mental well-being. She wanted to do them every day. “It’s no longer for the carbon — it’s for the fact that I genuinely love riding my bike and walking my kids to school,” she says. And that made her wonder: What other steps was she thinking of as sacrifices that might actually enrich her life?</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/blog/penetrating-ideas/we-can-make-a-change-if-we-all-pull-together-we-can-make-big-change/">We Can Make A Change &#8211; If we all pull together we can make big change</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/blog/penetrating-ideas/we-can-make-a-change-if-we-all-pull-together-we-can-make-big-change/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Paradise Coal Plant Closed Down &#8211; Is it ok to dance on somebody&#8217;s grave</title>
		<link>/blog/big-coal/paradise-coal-plant-closed-down-is-it-ok-to-dance-on-somebodys-grave/</link>
					<comments>/blog/big-coal/paradise-coal-plant-closed-down-is-it-ok-to-dance-on-somebodys-grave/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 21:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[big coal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big whoop dee do]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burning reduction methods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy conservation measures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gaia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[penetrating ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self inflicted wounds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Speculators]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water pollution]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=8077</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>My answer to that is YES! I know in this time of Covid-19 that we are not supposed to wish people ill. Or in general, in the METOO moment say harsh things about the down and OUT! Trust me, this &#8230; <a href="/blog/big-coal/paradise-coal-plant-closed-down-is-it-ok-to-dance-on-somebodys-grave/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/blog/big-coal/paradise-coal-plant-closed-down-is-it-ok-to-dance-on-somebodys-grave/">Paradise Coal Plant Closed Down &#8211; Is it ok to dance on somebody&#8217;s grave</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My answer to that is YES! I know in this time of Covid-19 that we are not supposed to wish people ill. Or in general, in the METOO moment say harsh things about the down and OUT! Trust me, this is more exclamation points then I have used in 10 years. The fact that it happens in McConnell&#8217;s state and against The Cheeto Burrito&#8217;s wishes is just wonderful to me.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.yahoo.com/news/iconic-plants-end-spells-doom-051246740.html">https://www.yahoo.com/news/iconic-plants-end-spells-doom-051246740.html</a></p>
<div data-reactid="22">
<div id="mrt-node-Lead-1-HeadComponentTitle" data-locator="subtree-root">
<div id="Lead-1-HeadComponentTitle-Proxy" data-reactroot="" data-reactid="1" data-react-checksum="791654392">
<div data-reactid="2">
<header id="Lead-1-HeadComponentTitle" class="canvas-header" data-yaft-module="tdv2-applet-CommonHeader" data-reactid="3">
<h1 class="Lh(1.15) Fz(40px) Fz(36px)--modalMinWidth Mb(14px) Ff($ff-primary) Lts($lspacing-md) Fw($fweight) Fsm($fsmoothing) Fsmw($fsmoothing) Fsmm($fsmoothing) Wow(bw)" data-reactid="4">Iconic plant&#8217;s end spells doom for struggling coal industry</h1>
</header>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div data-reactid="23">
<div id="mrt-node-Lead-2-HeadComponentAttribution" data-locator="subtree-root">
<div id="Lead-2-HeadComponentAttribution-Proxy" data-reactroot="" data-reactid="1" data-react-checksum="148473937">
<div id="Lead-2-HeadComponentAttribution" class="auth-attr W(100%) Mb(12px) Pos(r) Mah(75px) Mb(15px)" data-yaft-module="tdv2-applet-CommonAttribution" data-reactid="2">
<div class="auth-prov-logos D(tbc) Va(t) Pos(r) Mah(40px) Maw(70px)" data-reactid="3">
<div class="provider-logo Va(m) Pend(10px) Pos(a) Lh(25px)" data-reactid="4"></div>
</div>
<div class="auth-prov-soc Mend(4px) Va(m) D(tbc) Mah(45px) Mah(40px)--sm Maw(650px) Start(80px) Pos(r) Lh(36px) Fz(12px)" data-reactid="7">
<div class="author Mb(4px) D(ib) " data-reactid="8">
<div class="author-name Lh(18px) Td(n) Fw(b) Fz(12px) C(#000)" data-reactid="9">DYLAN LOVAN<span class="attrib-sep Mend(5px) Fx(13px)" aria-hidden="true" data-reactid="10">,</span></div>
</div>
<div class="D(ib)" data-reactid="11"><span class="provider Mb(4px)" data-reactid="12"><span class="provider-link" data-reactid="13"><a class="Fz(13px) C($c-fuji-grey-l)" href="http://www.ap.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer nofollow" data-reactid="14">Associated Press</a></span></span><i class="Mx(5px) C(#9ea2af)" aria-hidden="true" data-reactid="16">•</i><time class="date Fz(11px) Mb(4px) Fz(13px) C(#9ea2af)" datetime="2020-03-24T11:04:52.000Z" data-reactid="17">March 24, 2020</time></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>DRAKESBORO, Ky. (AP) — President Donald Trump tried to stop it from happening. The top Republican in the Senate, Mitch McConnell, did too.</p>
<p>Despite their best efforts to make good on Trump’s campaign promise to save the beleaguered coal industry, including an eleventh-hour pressure campaign, the Tennessee Valley Authority power plant at Paradise burned its last load of coal last month.</p>
<p>The plant&#8217;s closure — in a county that once mined more coal than any other in the nation — is emblematic of the industry&#8217;s decadeslong decline due to tougher environmental regulations, a major push toward renewable energy and a rise in the extraction of natural gas. The shuttering of businesses nationwide and a reduced need for energy amid the global <a class="link rapid-noclick-resp" href="https://apnews.com/d1ddda5b644a9cdd6b844a196377b88e" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" data-ylk="slk:coronavirus">coronavirus </a>pandemic threatens to deal coal yet another devastating blow.</p>
<p>“It’s not just one 1,000-megawatt unit closing; they’re going down all over the place,” said John Rogers, a former mine owner who lives in western Kentucky near the Paradise plant, located in Muhlenberg County.</p>
<p>When coal-burning plants close, coal mining loses its best customer. Since 2010, 500 coal-burning units, or boilers, at power plants have been shut down and nearly half the nation&#8217;s coal mines have closed. No U.S. energy company, big or small, is building a new coal-burning plant.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and YIPPEE. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/blog/big-coal/paradise-coal-plant-closed-down-is-it-ok-to-dance-on-somebodys-grave/">Paradise Coal Plant Closed Down &#8211; Is it ok to dance on somebody&#8217;s grave</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/blog/big-coal/paradise-coal-plant-closed-down-is-it-ok-to-dance-on-somebodys-grave/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Americans Would Not Know Good Design If It Bit Them ON The Ass</title>
		<link>/blog/green-economy/americans-would-not-know-good-design-if-it-bit-them-on-the-ass/</link>
					<comments>/blog/green-economy/americans-would-not-know-good-design-if-it-bit-them-on-the-ass/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 15:50:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burn free generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cool sites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy conservation measures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environmentalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gaia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Other countries advances]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[serious artist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stewardship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water efficiency]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=8068</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>These people have been conserving massive amounts of energy for years. Americans, Russians and Chinese, NOt So MucH. You know &#8211; energy exuberance and all that poppycock. https://www.cnbc.com/2020/03/12/a-design-concept-is-transforming-the-energy-efficiency-of-buildings.html?utm_source=digg IOT: Powering the digital economy How a decades-old design concept is transforming &#8230; <a href="/blog/green-economy/americans-would-not-know-good-design-if-it-bit-them-on-the-ass/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/blog/green-economy/americans-would-not-know-good-design-if-it-bit-them-on-the-ass/">Americans Would Not Know Good Design If It Bit Them ON The Ass</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>These people have been conserving massive amounts of energy for years. Americans, Russians and Chinese, NOt So MucH. You know &#8211; energy exuberance and all that poppycock.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/03/12/a-design-concept-is-transforming-the-energy-efficiency-of-buildings.html?utm_source=digg">https://www.cnbc.com/2020/03/12/a-design-concept-is-transforming-the-energy-efficiency-of-buildings.html?utm_source=digg</a></p>
<div class="ArticleHeader-wrapperHeroNoImage ArticleHeader-wrapperHero ArticleHeader-wrapper ArticleHeader-wrapperNoImage"><a class="ArticleHeader-eyebrow" href="https://www.cnbc.com/iot/">IOT: Powering the digital economy</a></div>
<div></div>
<div class="ArticleHeader-wrapperHeroNoImage ArticleHeader-wrapperHero ArticleHeader-wrapper ArticleHeader-wrapperNoImage">
<div>
<h1 class="ArticleHeader-headline">How a decades-old design concept is transforming the energy efficiency of buildings</h1>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
</div>
<div class="ArticleHeader-time"><time data-testid="published-timestamp">Published Thu, Mar 12 20209:33 AM EDT</time></div>
<div></div>
</div>
<div class="ArticleHeader-authorAndShareInline">
<div class="ArticleHeader-authorContainer">
<div class="ArticleHeader-author">
<div class="Author-author">
<div class="Author-authorInfo">
<div class="Author-authorNameAndSocial"><a class="Author-authorName" href="https://www.cnbc.com/anmar-frangoul-profile--cnbc/">Anmar Frangoul</a></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div id="SpecialReportArticle-KeyPoints-5" class="RenderKeyPoints-keyPoints">
<div class="RenderKeyPoints-wrapper">
<div class="RenderKeyPoints-header">Key Points</div>
<div class="RenderKeyPoints-list">
<div>
<div class="group">
<ul>
<li>The buildings we live and work in have to meet a wide range of needs.</li>
<li>Could a shift in the way they are designed make them more energy efficient?</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div id="SpecialReportArticle-ArticleBody-6" class="ArticleBody-articleBody" data-module="ArticleBody">
<div id="ArticleBody-InlineImage-106438318" class="InlineImage-imageEmbed hasBkg">
<div class="InlineImage-wrapper">
<div class="InlineImage-imagePlaceholder">
<div>
<div class="InlineImage-imageContainer" tabindex="-1" role="button"><picture><source srcset="https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/106438318-1584002256432goldsmithstreet_5593timcrocker.jpg?v=1584002694&amp;w=740&amp;h=416" media="(min-width: 1340px)" /><source srcset="https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/106438318-1584002256432goldsmithstreet_5593timcrocker.jpg?v=1584002694&amp;w=630&amp;h=354" media="(min-width: 1020px)" /><source srcset="https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/106438318-1584002256432goldsmithstreet_5593timcrocker.jpg?v=1584002694&amp;w=900&amp;h=506" media="(min-width: 760px)" /><img decoding="async" class="" src="https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/106438318-1584002256432goldsmithstreet_5593timcrocker.jpg?v=1584002694&amp;w=678&amp;h=381" alt="H/O - Goldsmith Street Norwich" /></picture></div>
</div>
</div>
<div>
<div class="InlineImage-imageEmbedCaption">Goldsmith Street, in the English city of Norwich, won the RIBA Stirling Prize for 2019.</div>
<div class="InlineImage-imageEmbedCredit">Tim Crocker</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="group">
<p>The buildings we live and work in have to meet a wide range of needs, whether it’s an office block in the middle of the city or a small house in the suburbs.</p>
<p>Think of a building’s temperature: It can be regulated by radiators, fans and air conditioning systems, while basic actions such as opening and closing a window or door can also be effective. Today, smart technology allows many of these appliances to be controlled remotely using smartphones.</p>
</div>
</div>
<p>You only need to look at your monthly utility bill to know that living in a building — be it large or small — costs money.</p>
<p>The impact of buildings on the environment is also a concern. According to the IEA, final energy use in buildings hit approximately 3,060 million tons of oil equivalent (Mtoe) in 2018, up from 2,820 Mtoe in 2010.</p>
<p>Fossil fuels’ share in buildings’ energy use was at 36% in 2018, the IEA says, a small drop compared to 38% in 2010.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read. Its all you&#8217;ve got to do, right? More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/blog/green-economy/americans-would-not-know-good-design-if-it-bit-them-on-the-ass/">Americans Would Not Know Good Design If It Bit Them ON The Ass</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/blog/green-economy/americans-would-not-know-good-design-if-it-bit-them-on-the-ass/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Mist Showers Conserve An Amazing Amount Of Water And Energy &#8211; How come I never heard of it</title>
		<link>/blog/burning-reduction-methods/mist-showers-conserve-an-amazing-amount-of-water-and-energy-how-come-i-never-heard-of-it/</link>
					<comments>/blog/burning-reduction-methods/mist-showers-conserve-an-amazing-amount-of-water-and-energy-how-come-i-never-heard-of-it/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 21:05:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[advanced energy structures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burning reduction methods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy conservation measures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[residential energy efficiency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water conservation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water efficiency]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7985</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I am embarrassed to say that I have never heard of a mist shower. So I am putting this up as a very very long public service announcement. But if everything it says is true, I gotta get me one. &#8230; <a href="/blog/burning-reduction-methods/mist-showers-conserve-an-amazing-amount-of-water-and-energy-how-come-i-never-heard-of-it/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/blog/burning-reduction-methods/mist-showers-conserve-an-amazing-amount-of-water-and-energy-how-come-i-never-heard-of-it/">Mist Showers Conserve An Amazing Amount Of Water And Energy &#8211; How come I never heard of it</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I am embarrassed to say that I have never heard of a mist shower. So I am putting this up as a very very long public service announcement. But if everything it says is true, I gotta get me one. It should be amazing.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.lowtechmagazine.com/2019/10/mist-showers-sustainable-decadence.html">https://www.lowtechmagazine.com/2019/10/mist-showers-sustainable-decadence.html</a></p>
<p class="content-nav"><a class="content-nav-prev" href="https://www.lowtechmagazine.com/2019/06/wooden-wind-turbines.html">« How to Make Wind Power Sustainable Again</a> | <a class="content-nav-main" href="https://www.lowtechmagazine.com/">Main</a></p>
<div id="entry-6a00e0099229e888330240a4ba2fc3200d" class="entry-category-cover_story entry-category-diy entry-category-energy_consumption entry-category-infrastructures entry-category-lowtech_solutions entry-category-water entry-author-kris_de_decker entry-type-post entry">
<div class="entry-inner">
<h3 class="entry-header">Mist Showers: Sustainable Decadence?</h3>
<div class="entry-content">
<div class="entry-body">
<p>The daily shower would be hard to sustain in a world without fossil fuels. The mist shower, a satisfying but forgotten technology which uses very little water and energy, could be a solution. Designer Jonas Görgen developed a do-it-yourself kit to convert almost any shower into a mist shower and sent me one to try out.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" src="https://krisdedecker.typepad.com/.a/6a00e0099229e888330240a4be94e0200d-700wi" alt="Mist-shower-hack-kit" /></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<h2><strong>The Carbon Footprint of the Daily Shower</strong></h2>
<p>The shower doesn’t get much attention in the context of climate change. However, like <a href="https://www.lowtechmagazine.com/2010/09/piston-powered-aircraft-as-fuel-efficient-as-current-average-jet.html">airplanes</a>, <a href="https://www.lowtechmagazine.com/2008/06/citroen-2cv.html">cars</a>, and <a href="https://www.lowtechmagazine.com/2015/02/heating-people-not-spaces.html">heating systems</a>, it has become a very wasteful and carbon-intensive way to provide for a basic need: washing the body. Each day, many of us pour roughly 70 litres of hot water over our bodies in order to be “clean”.</p>
<p>This practice requires two scarce resources: water and energy. More attention is given to the showers&#8217; high water consumption, but energy use is just as problematic. Hot water production accounts for the second most significant use of energy in many homes (after heating), and much of it is used for showering. Water treatment and distribution also use lots of energy.</p>
<p>In contrast to the energy used for space heating, which has decreased during the last decades, the energy used for hot water in households has been steadily growing. One of the reasons is that people are showering longer and more frequently, and using increasingly powerful shower heads. For example, in the Netherlands from 1992 to 2016, shower frequency increased from 0.69 to 0.72 showers per day, shower duration increased from 8.2 to 8.9 minutes, and the average water flow increased from 7.5 to 8.6 litres per minute. [1]</p>
<blockquote><p>In many industrial societies it&#8217;s now common to shower at least once per day</p></blockquote>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read and read and read. I may never take a shower again. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/blog/burning-reduction-methods/mist-showers-conserve-an-amazing-amount-of-water-and-energy-how-come-i-never-heard-of-it/">Mist Showers Conserve An Amazing Amount Of Water And Energy &#8211; How come I never heard of it</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/blog/burning-reduction-methods/mist-showers-conserve-an-amazing-amount-of-water-and-energy-how-come-i-never-heard-of-it/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Energy Efficiency In The Home &#8211; A fan sends me an excellent guide</title>
		<link>/blog/burning-reduction-methods/energy-efficiency-in-the-home-a-fan-sends-me-an-excellent-guide/</link>
					<comments>/blog/burning-reduction-methods/energy-efficiency-in-the-home-a-fan-sends-me-an-excellent-guide/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 19:14:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[big whoop dee do]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burning reduction methods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cool sites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[efficient refrigerators]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy conservation measures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy Tough Love Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environmentalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[masters of the universe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[radiant barriers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[residential energy efficiency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self inflicted wounds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stewardship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weatherization]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7921</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I know it has been a while since I have put anything up about Residential Energy  Use, which is where this BLOG started out but we get requests from organizations to get a plug and so here you go. Tyler &#60;tyler@greenteensclub.org&#62; &#8230; <a href="/blog/burning-reduction-methods/energy-efficiency-in-the-home-a-fan-sends-me-an-excellent-guide/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/blog/burning-reduction-methods/energy-efficiency-in-the-home-a-fan-sends-me-an-excellent-guide/">Energy Efficiency In The Home &#8211; A fan sends me an excellent guide</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I know it has been a while since I have put anything up about Residential Energy  Use, which is where this BLOG started out but we get requests from organizations to get a plug and so here you go.</p>
<div class="D_F ac_FT ab_CI en_0"></div>
<div class="o_h D_F em_0 E_fq7 ek_BB" data-test-id="address-info">
<div class="D_F en_0"><span class="u_b en_0 C4_Z2aVTcY" data-test-id="message-from"><span class="D_F rtlI_rtlI_dz_sSg " data-test-id="email-pill">Tyler<span class="u_N C_Z1VRpVF"> &lt;tyler@greenteensclub.org&gt;</span></span></span></div>
<div class="d_6FIA i_6FIA D_F eo_HB"><span class="u_b E_eo6 C_Z1TsNWR">To:</span><span class="D_F rtlI_rtlI_dz_sSg " data-test-id="email-pill"><span class="C4_Z2aVTcY" title="info@censys.org" data-test-id="message-to">info@censys.org</span></span></div>
</div>
<div class="en_0 s_6Fd5 H_6Fd5 M_3gJOe cdPFi_Z281SGl O_cMr O4_cMu"></div>
<div class="D_F en_0 M_3gJOe A_6Eb4 C_Z1VRpVF" data-test-id="message-date">Aug 7 at 1:01 PM</div>
<div class="D_F ab_CI Y_68F4 en_0 cdPFi_ZpQYvz H_6MGW W_6MGW lv_1IWXzk h_Z13pql2 h4_2d9T5e"></div>
<div class="I_52qC D_FY W_6D6F" data-test-id="message-view-body">
<div class="X_6MGW"></div>
<div class="msg-body P_wpofO iy_A mq_AS" data-test-id="message-view-body-content">
<div class="jb_0 X_6MGW N_6Fd5">
<div>
<div id="yiv5534073119">
<p>Hi there,</p>
<p>My name is Tyler and I&#8217;m a member of GreenTeensClub. We&#8217;re spreading resources that help make our planet a little healthier, like this home energy efficiency guide: https://www.basementguides.com/basement-and-home-energy/</p>
<p>I think your site is a great place to share this resource: /date/2015/05</p>
<p>The page includes the biggest culprits of energy waste in a home, tips for locating the source of energy-waste issues, and how to lower your bills while reducing your footprint.</p>
<p>Please help us spread awareness of the importance of making homes more energy efficient. Even if we only get a few people to make minor changes, then we&#8217;ve made a huge difference.</p>
<p>Thanks!<br />
Tyler</p>
<p>GreenTeensClub</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="S02cDynZVE"><p><a href="https://www.basementguides.com/basement-and-home-energy/">Basement And Home Energy</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe title="&#8220;Basement And Home Energy&#8221; &#8212; Basement Guides" class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" style="position: absolute; clip: rect(1px, 1px, 1px, 1px);" src="https://www.basementguides.com/basement-and-home-energy/embed/#?secret=S02cDynZVE" data-secret="S02cDynZVE" width="584" height="329" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/blog/burning-reduction-methods/energy-efficiency-in-the-home-a-fan-sends-me-an-excellent-guide/">Energy Efficiency In The Home &#8211; A fan sends me an excellent guide</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/blog/burning-reduction-methods/energy-efficiency-in-the-home-a-fan-sends-me-an-excellent-guide/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Want To Save The Planet &#8211; Block the sun</title>
		<link>/blog/burning-reduction-methods/want-to-save-the-planet-block-the-sun/</link>
					<comments>/blog/burning-reduction-methods/want-to-save-the-planet-block-the-sun/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 18:34:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[advanced energy structures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[air conditioning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big whoop dee do]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burning reduction methods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy conservation measures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[penetrating ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[radiant barriers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[residential energy efficiency]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7763</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>It is a short article. So I will be brief. This is a film that reduces solar absorption by 10%. Combine that with a white roof and you got some major savings. Plus you dampen green house gases at the &#8230; <a href="/blog/burning-reduction-methods/want-to-save-the-planet-block-the-sun/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/blog/burning-reduction-methods/want-to-save-the-planet-block-the-sun/">Want To Save The Planet &#8211; Block the sun</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It is a short article. So I will be brief. This is a film that reduces solar absorption by 10%. Combine that with a white roof and you got some major savings. Plus you dampen green house gases at the same time. HAPPY THANKSGIVING EVERYONE!</p>
<p><a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018/11/12/heat-rejecting-film-reduce-air-conditioning/">https://www.engadget.com/2018/11/12/heat-rejecting-film-reduce-air-conditioning/</a></p>
<div class="o-title_mark@tp+ bc-gray-1 col-10-of-12@tl+">
<h1 class="t-h4@m- t-h1-b@tp t-h1@tl+ mt-20 mt-15@tp mt-0@m-">Heat-rejecting film could reduce air conditioning costs</h1>
<div class="t-d7@m- t-d4@tp t-d3-b@tl t-d2@d mt-15 mt-25@tp c-gray-3 c-gray-6@m-">It blocks 70 percent of incoming solar heat.</div>
</div>
<section id="engadget-article-meta-bar" class="o-meta_bar@tl+ mt-35 mt-20@m-" data-ylk="sec:articlemetabar;itc:0;">
<div class="grid@tl+">
<div class="grid@tl+__cell col-12-of-12@tp col-5-of-12@tl+ vm">
<div class="o-article_meta_bar__avatar left mr-20 mr-10@s o-avatar_offset">
<div class="w-45@m+ h-45@m+ o-h w-30@s h-30@s"><a href="https://www.engadget.com/about/editors/steve-dent/" data-ylk="slk:Steve%20Dent;pos:1;cpos:1;elm:img;subsec:author;itc:0;" data-rapid_p="1" data-v9y="1"> <img decoding="async" class="inline-block vm circle-mask" src="https://o.aolcdn.com/images/dims?thumbnail=45%2C45&amp;quality=80&amp;image_uri=https%3A%2F%2Fs.blogcdn.com%2Fwww.engadget.com%2Fmedia%2F2017%2F07%2Fsteve-headshot-05440x350.jpg&amp;client=amp-blogside-v2&amp;signature=54151afc52d094cb72b5ffe9610788589fe07cdf" /> </a></div>
</div>
<div class="t-meta-small@s t-meta@m+">
<p><a class="th-meta" href="https://www.engadget.com/about/editors/steve-dent/" data-ylk="slk:Steve%20Dent;pos:1;cpos:1;elm:hdln;subsec:author;" data-rapid_p="2" data-v9y="1">Steve Dent</a><span class="hide@s th-meta">, <a class="th-meta" href="https://twitter.com/stevetdent" data-ylk="slk:twitter;pos:2;cpos:1;elm:hdln;itc:0;" data-rapid_p="3" data-v9y="1">@stevetdent</a></span></p>
<div class="th-meta">11.12.18 in <a class="th-topic" href="https://www.engadget.com/tags/green/" data-ylk="slk:Green;pos:3;cpos:1;elm:hdln;itc:0;" data-rapid_p="4" data-v9y="1">Green</a></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<div id="engadget-post-contents" class="o-article_block pb-15 pb-5@m- o-subtle_divider" data-ylk="sec:postcontents;slk:Heat-rejecting%20film%20could%20reduce%20air%20conditioning%20costs;elm:hdln;itc:0;">
<div class="grid@tl+">
<div class="grid@tl+__cell col-8-of-12@tl+">
<div class="article-text c-gray-1">
<p>Climate change can be a <a href="https://www.engadget.com/2018/10/08/major-un-report-climate-change-worse/" data-rapid_p="1" data-v9y="1">vicious cycle</a> when folks crank up the air conditioning during heat waves and add even more CO2 to the atmosphere. Scientists from MIT and the University of Hong Kong have <a href="http://news.mit.edu/2018/see-through-film-rejects-incoming-solar-heat-1108" data-rapid_p="2" data-v9y="1">developed</a> a new type of window coating that could curb that trend. It remains highly transparent up to 89 degrees F (32 degrees Celsius), but beyond that, it becomes translucent like frosted glass. As a result, it reflects back up to 70 percent of the sun&#8217;s incoming heat, reducing interior temperatures and the load on your air conditioner.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="js-notMobileReferredByFbTw">
<div class="o-article_block pb-15 pb-5@m- mt-n35 mt-n25@m mt-n15@s">
<div class="grid@tl+">
<div class="full-width@tp- grid@tl+__cell col-8-of-12@tl+">
<div class="article-text c-gray-1 no-review">
<p>To maximize heat blocking, the researchers inserted tiny water-filled spheres into a standard poly material. At temperatures starting around 85 degree F, the spheres start to shrink, squeezing out the liquid and forcing the poly fibers closer together. That gives the glass a frosted appearance, blocking 70 percent of the incoming heat while still letting a lot of visible light through.</p>
<p>Such films have been tried before but didn&#8217;t block heat that well. The MIT and Hong Kong teams realized that the water filled spheres needed to match the wavelength of infrared light responsible for most solar heating. After expanding the bubble size to 500 nanometers, the film became a much more effective heat-blocker.</p>
<p><img decoding="async" src="https://o.aolcdn.com/images/dims?crop=948%2C500%2C0%2C68&amp;quality=85&amp;format=jpg&amp;resize=1600%2C844&amp;image_uri=https%3A%2F%2Fs.yimg.com%2Fos%2Fcreatr-uploaded-images%2F2018-11%2F0f217760-e64a-11e8-afc5-937ff80d3c37&amp;client=a1acac3e1b3290917d92&amp;signature=37fe5e3956dc97669765ce1d23c0761b494e890d" alt="MIT heat-rejecting film" data-caption="MIT heat-rejecting film" data-credit="Engadget" data-credit-link-back="" data-dam-provider="Engadget" data-local-id="local-2-882768-1542006706729" data-media-id="686ef722-9048-3187-b6e3-a8828b9d683a" data-original-url="https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2018-11/0f217760-e64a-11e8-afc5-937ff80d3c37" data-title="MIT heat-rejecting film" /></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Google this if you want extra. Go there and reat the uplinks. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/blog/burning-reduction-methods/want-to-save-the-planet-block-the-sun/">Want To Save The Planet &#8211; Block the sun</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/blog/burning-reduction-methods/want-to-save-the-planet-block-the-sun/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
