<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>economics Archives - Community Energy Systems</title>
	<atom:link href="/censys/category/blog/economics/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/censys/category/blog/economics/</link>
	<description>Censys.org</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 19:54:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>I Say To Putin &#8211; Bring IT ON! &#8211; I will pay $5 or $6 a gallon for gasoline</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/gasoline-claims/i-say-to-putin-bring-it-on-i-will-pay-5-or-6-a-gallon-for-gasoline/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/gasoline-claims/i-say-to-putin-bring-it-on-i-will-pay-5-or-6-a-gallon-for-gasoline/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Mar 2022 19:28:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[big oil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gasoline claims]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=8604</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>If it means kicking Putin out of Ukraine then I am willing to pay whatever at the pump. Seriously I have advocated for dropping a Tactical Nuke on Chernobyl for a while. Ever since this current conflict begin. This for &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/gasoline-claims/i-say-to-putin-bring-it-on-i-will-pay-5-or-6-a-gallon-for-gasoline/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/gasoline-claims/i-say-to-putin-bring-it-on-i-will-pay-5-or-6-a-gallon-for-gasoline/">I Say To Putin &#8211; Bring IT ON! &#8211; I will pay $5 or $6 a gallon for gasoline</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If it means kicking Putin out of Ukraine then I am willing to pay whatever at the pump. Seriously I have advocated for dropping a Tactical Nuke on Chernobyl for a while. Ever since this current conflict begin. This for two reasons. One, it would clean out the radioactive mess there and turn out the lights on southern Russian. Two it would get Putin&#8217;s attention and maybe even get him thrown from power. Is it radical? HELL yes, but tough times require tough decisions. NUKE em I say.</p>
<h1><a href="https://www.caranddriver.com/news/a39338671/us-gas-prices-skyrocketing-future/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://www.caranddriver.com/news/a39338671/us-gas-prices-skyrocketing-future/</a></h1>
<h1 class="content-hed standard-hed"><span class="">U.S. Gas Prices Are Skyrocketing—How Much Worse Will It Get?</span></h1>
<div class="content-dek standard-dek">
<p>The average U.S. gas price is now $4.17, the highest ever, and in some places, it&#8217;s already well into the $5 and even $6 range.</p>
</div>
<div class="byline-with-image">
<div class="content-info-byline-image" aria-hidden="true"><img decoding="async" class="lazyimage lazyautosizes lazyloaded" title="" src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/rover/profile_photos/4d9afe9d-d2e5-4a30-8559-31de55b5441f_1564432922.file?fill=1:1&amp;resize=80:*" sizes="40px" alt="" data-src="https://hips.hearstapps.com/rover/profile_photos/4d9afe9d-d2e5-4a30-8559-31de55b5441f_1564432922.file?fill=1:1&amp;resize=80:*" data-sizes="auto" data-srcset="" /></div>
<div class="byline "><span class=""> By <a class="byline-name" href="https://www.caranddriver.com/author/223337/sebastian-blanco/" data-vars-ga-ux-element="Byline" data-vars-ga-call-to-action="Sebastian Blanco"><span class="byline-name">Sebastian Blanco</span></a> </span></div>
</div>
<p><time class="content-info-date" datetime="2022-03-08T15:19:00Z"> Mar 8, 2022 </time></p>
<ul class="body-ul">
<li><strong>Geopolitical tensions, inflation, and the COVID-19 pandemic have converged to push the average U.S. price for a gallon of gasoline above $4 for the first time since 2008, as calculated by the price-monitoring app GasBuddy.</strong></li>
<li><strong>In some cities, including Los Angeles and San Francisco, average gas prices have hit $5 for regular fuel—the photo above was taken in Santa Ana, California, on March 6—and there are even some stations selling premium for over $7 a gallon. On the <a href="https://gasprices.aaa.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">AAA Gas Prices website</a>, you can look at the averages in the state where you live. </strong></li>
<li><strong>Unless something drastic changes soon, <a href="https://www.gasbuddy.com/newsroom/pressrelease/2022/03/05/1103" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GasBuddy</a> is predicting a national average price of $4.25 by Memorial Day. The current record is $4.10. </strong></li>
</ul>
<p class="body-text"><strong><em>UPDATE 3/8/2022: </em></strong><em><a href="https://gasprices.aaa.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">AAA said</a> the average U.S. price for a gallon of gasoline has hit $4.173, which is the most expensive ever. That&#8217;s up 10 cents per gallon since yesterday and up 63 cents since February 24 (the date on which Russia began its invasion of Ukraine).</em></p>
<p class="body-text">The news everybody already seems to know is that gas prices are headed up. This weekend, the national average price for a gallon of gasoline went above $4 a gallon in the U.S for only the second time ever. The last time this happened was in 2008.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/gasoline-claims/i-say-to-putin-bring-it-on-i-will-pay-5-or-6-a-gallon-for-gasoline/">I Say To Putin &#8211; Bring IT ON! &#8211; I will pay $5 or $6 a gallon for gasoline</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/gasoline-claims/i-say-to-putin-bring-it-on-i-will-pay-5-or-6-a-gallon-for-gasoline/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Home Solar Power Is Cheap And Effective &#8211; Go for it now</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/burning-reduction-methods/home-solar-power-is-cheap-and-effective-go-for-it-now/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/burning-reduction-methods/home-solar-power-is-cheap-and-effective-go-for-it-now/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 20:56:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[burning reduction methods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gaia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar power]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=8564</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>First off. This piece claims to be all you need to know about Home Solar Electric. It is not. But when you do all the things they TELL you to and THEN put them together. Then you are nearly there. &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/burning-reduction-methods/home-solar-power-is-cheap-and-effective-go-for-it-now/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burning-reduction-methods/home-solar-power-is-cheap-and-effective-go-for-it-now/">Home Solar Power Is Cheap And Effective &#8211; Go for it now</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>First off. This piece claims to be all you need to know about Home Solar Electric. It is not. But when you do all the things they TELL you to and THEN put them together. Then you are nearly there. BUT they do not include all the research you have to do on equipment manufacturers, convertors and batteries. Sigh. But they get A&#8217;s for optimism.</p>
<p><a href="https://getpocket.com/explore/item/what-you-need-to-know-about-converting-your-home-to-solar?utm_source=pocket-newtab">https://getpocket.com/explore/item/what-you-need-to-know-about-converting-your-home-to-solar?utm_source=pocket-newtab</a></p>
<h1 class="hmjyd8t" data-cy="parsed-headline">What You Need to Know About Converting Your Home to Solar</h1>
<p>Let us be your guiding light.</p>
<p><cite class="b1yvsvix"><a href="https://www.popsci.com/?utm_source=pocket" data-cy="author-url">Popular Science</a></cite></p>
<ul>
<li data-cy="author">Whitson Gordon</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p class="body">If you live in an area with abundant sunlight—hello, fellow southern Californians—you’ve probably thought about installing solar panels on your roof to save on your electric bill. But with so much information, it can be hard to know where to start.</p>
<h2 class="body title">Look no further—start here</h2>
<p class="body">Between the different types of panels, financing, inverters, and other jargon, researching solar energy can feel overwhelming at first. That’s why I recommend starting at a solar quote comparison site like <a href="https://www.energysage.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">EnergySage</a>, <a href="https://www.solar-estimate.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Solar-Estimate</a>, or <a href="https://www.solarreviews.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">SolarReviews</a> (the latter two are run by the same people).</p>
<p class="body">Both EnergySage and Solar-Estimate act as educational resources and comparison shopping tools to help you field bids. I’ve been using EnergySage, which is chock-full of articles explaining the technology involved. You can also watch videos, look at their buyer’s guide, or start getting quotes. Their <a href="https://www.energysage.com/solar/101/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Solar 101</a> series of articles will help you understand the basics, and when you’re done, scroll through the site’s “Learn About Solar” sidebar to read even more articles that’ll give you a feel for the process.</p>
<p class="body">To understand what your home requires, though, you’ll need to look up how much electricity you use. If your bill tells you the average amount of electricity you use each month, make a note of that, or calculate a quick and dirty average yourself. The more information you have on your usage, the more accurate an estimate you can get from installers.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read so much. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burning-reduction-methods/home-solar-power-is-cheap-and-effective-go-for-it-now/">Home Solar Power Is Cheap And Effective &#8211; Go for it now</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/burning-reduction-methods/home-solar-power-is-cheap-and-effective-go-for-it-now/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Upheavals Caused By Clean Energy &#8211; All the tree huggers make it look like pixie dust</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/upheavals-caused-by-clean-energy-all-the-tree-huggers-make-it-look-like-pixie-dust/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/upheavals-caused-by-clean-energy-all-the-tree-huggers-make-it-look-like-pixie-dust/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 20:46:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[batteries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burn free generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cool sites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[penetrating ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=8551</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>By &#8220;pixie dust&#8221; I mean that a lot of environmentalists make it sound like there will be no chaos from fossil fuel use to renewal energy systems and that is not true. Dislodging fossil fuel will result in job loses, &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/upheavals-caused-by-clean-energy-all-the-tree-huggers-make-it-look-like-pixie-dust/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/upheavals-caused-by-clean-energy-all-the-tree-huggers-make-it-look-like-pixie-dust/">Upheavals Caused By Clean Energy &#8211; All the tree huggers make it look like pixie dust</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By &#8220;pixie dust&#8221; I mean that a lot of environmentalists make it sound like there will be no chaos from fossil fuel use to renewal energy systems and that is not true. Dislodging fossil fuel will result in job loses, factories closing and possibly the lack of transportation (for example) for chunks of the population. Especially those not preparing for it now. Lives will be lost. This is the fault of capitalism but it is what we have. Also the reverse is true, as demand for clean energy grows, whole resources will be created from scratch (rare earths for instance). The earth will be scarred, employment will be created with much wrenching and tearing. Lives will be lost. Capitalism will prevail. Just think of what happened when oil and gas took over and from the Luddites. This is a Really Long article about all of that and it only scratches the surface.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/world/2021-11-30/geopolitics-energy-green-upheaval?utm_source=pocket-newtab">https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/world/2021-11-30/geopolitics-energy-green-upheaval?utm_source=pocket-newtab</a></p>
<div class="row article-header--metadata-title">
<div class="col-lg-10 offset-lg-0 col-12 col-md-8 offset-md-2">
<div class="row">
<div class="col-lg-11 article-header--metadata-content">
<h1 class="f-serif ls-0 article-title pt-2" data-drupal-page-title="">Green Upheaval</h1>
<h2 class="f-serif ls-0 article-subtitle ">The New Geopolitics of Energy</h2>
<div class="row no-gutters ls-0 article-byline position-relative">
<h3 class="f-sans m-0 col-12 col-sm-auto mr-sm-4">By <span class="position-relative d-inline-block"><a class="article-byline-author b4-l" href="https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/world/2021-11-30/geopolitics-energy-green-upheaval?utm_source=pocket-newtab#author-info">Jason Bordoff and Meghan L. O’Sullivan</a></span></h3>
<p><span class="article-header--metadata-date align-self-center col-6 col-sm-auto"><a href="https://www.foreignaffairs.com/issues/2022/101/1">January/February 2022</a></span></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>It is not hard to understand why people dream of a future defined by clean energy. As greenhouse gas emissions continue to grow and as extreme weather events become more frequent and harmful, the current efforts to move beyond fossil fuels appear woefully inadequate. Adding to the frustration, the geopolitics of oil and gas are alive and well—and as fraught as ever. Europe is in the throes of a full-fledged energy crisis, with staggering electricity prices forcing businesses across the continent to shutter and energy firms to declare bankruptcy, positioning Russian President Vladimir Putin to take advantage of his neighbors’ struggles by leveraging his country’s natural gas reserves. In September, blackouts reportedly led Chinese Vice Premier Han Zheng to instruct his country’s state-owned energy companies to secure supplies for winter at any cost. And as oil prices surge above $80 per barrel, the United States and other energy-hungry countries are pleading with major producers, including Saudi Arabia, to ramp up their output, giving Riyadh more clout in a newly tense relationship and suggesting the limits of Washington’s energy “independence.”</p>
<p>Proponents of clean energy hope (and sometimes promise) that in addition to mitigating climate change, the energy transition will help make tensions over energy resources a thing of the past. It is true that clean energy will transform geopolitics—just not necessarily in the ways many of its champions expect. The transition will reconfigure many elements of international politics that have shaped the global system since at least World War II, significantly affecting the sources of national power, the process of globalization, relations among the great powers, and the ongoing economic convergence of developed countries and developing ones. The process will be messy at best. And far from fostering comity and cooperation, it will likely produce new forms of competition and confrontation long before a new, more copacetic geopolitics takes shape.</p>
<p>Talk of a smooth transition to clean energy is fanciful: there is no way that the world can avoid major upheavals as it remakes the entire energy system, which is the lifeblood of the global economy and underpins the geopolitical order. Moreover, the conventional wisdom about who will gain and who will lose is frequently off base.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and reeeeaaad. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/upheavals-caused-by-clean-energy-all-the-tree-huggers-make-it-look-like-pixie-dust/">Upheavals Caused By Clean Energy &#8211; All the tree huggers make it look like pixie dust</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/upheavals-caused-by-clean-energy-all-the-tree-huggers-make-it-look-like-pixie-dust/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>We Don&#8217;t Need No Stinkin Baseload &#8211; What we need is more storage</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/lies-told-by-energy-companies/we-dont-need-no-stinkin-baseload-what-we-need-is-more-storage/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/lies-told-by-energy-companies/we-dont-need-no-stinkin-baseload-what-we-need-is-more-storage/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 17:22:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[burning behavior]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dumb ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green wash. corporate cover ups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lies told by energy companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[no nukes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=8529</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>By more storage I do not mean Batteries. I mean things like gas and liquid Compression, or liquid transportation. There are other possibilities that are well known like winding springs, etc. The idea of Baseload is in fact obsolete but &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/lies-told-by-energy-companies/we-dont-need-no-stinkin-baseload-what-we-need-is-more-storage/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/lies-told-by-energy-companies/we-dont-need-no-stinkin-baseload-what-we-need-is-more-storage/">We Don&#8217;t Need No Stinkin Baseload &#8211; What we need is more storage</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By more storage I do not mean Batteries. I mean things like gas and liquid Compression, or liquid transportation. There are other possibilities that are well known like winding springs, etc. The idea of Baseload is in fact obsolete but you can&#8217;t tell. She locked into the past when she gushes about building a small Nuke next to an OLD coal plant. She just wants to &#8220;substitute&#8221; one source for another not write the Future. This administration is so OLD it is frightening. (quick aside &#8211; like for the last 100 yrs &#8211; how do get rid of the waste?)</p>
<p><a href="https://news.yahoo.com/us-very-bullish-on-new-nuclear-technology-granholm-says-110016617.html">https://news.yahoo.com/us-very-bullish-on-new-nuclear-technology-granholm-says-110016617.html</a></p>
<div class="caas-content-wrapper">
<header class="caas-header">
<div class="caas-logo"><a class="link rapid-noclick-resp caas-attr-provider-logo" title="" href="https://news.yahoo.com/" data-ylk="sec:logo-provider;elm:logo;slk:Yahoo News;g:"><img decoding="async" class="caas-img" src="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/ZJRncbJyfKWbnufNMwbHDQ--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTE2ODtoPTQwO2NmPXdlYnA-/https://s.yimg.com/cv/apiv2/hlogos/yahoo_NEWS_Light.png" alt="Yahoo News" data-src="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/ZJRncbJyfKWbnufNMwbHDQ--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTE2ODtoPTQwO2NmPXdlYnA-/https://s.yimg.com/cv/apiv2/hlogos/yahoo_NEWS_Light.png" /></a></div>
<header class="caas-title-wrapper">
<h1 data-test-locator="headline">U.S. &#8216;very bullish&#8217; on new nuclear technology, Granholm says</h1>
</header>
</header>
<div>
<div class="caas-attr author">
<p><a class="link rapid-noclick-resp caas-attr-logo" title="" href="https://www.yahoo.com/author/ben-adler" data-ylk="elm:icon;slk:Ben Adler"><img decoding="async" class="caas-img" src="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/6th1tq4IZP4keb6G8tSZsQ--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTgwO2g9ODA7Y2Y9d2VicA--/https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/a81d6bb0-11a1-11ec-add7-bc6677aed915" alt="Ben Adler" data-src="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/6th1tq4IZP4keb6G8tSZsQ--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTgwO2g9ODA7Y2Y9d2VicA--/https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-09/a81d6bb0-11a1-11ec-add7-bc6677aed915" /></a></p>
<div class="caas-attr-meta">
<div class="caas-attr-item-author">
<p><span class="caas-author-byline-collapse" data-id="m-0"><a class="link rapid-noclick-resp" title="" href="https://www.yahoo.com/author/ben-adler" data-ylk="elm:author;slk:Ben Adler">Ben Adler</a></span></p>
<div class="caas-attr-item"><span class="caas-attr-meta-separator">·</span>Senior Climate Editor</div>
</div>
<div class="caas-attr-time-style"><time class="" datetime="2021-11-06T10:05:50.000Z">Sat, November 6, 2021, 5:05 AM</time><span class="caas-attr-meta-separator">·</span>6 min read</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="caas-content-contain-share">
<div class="caas-attr-separator">
<div class="separator"></div>
<div class="separator-ext"></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="caas-xray-wrapper caas-xray-wrapper-type-cards caas-xray-wrapper-position-top">
<div class="xray-cards-header"></div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="caas-body">
<figure class="caas-figure">
<div>
<div>
<div class="caas-img-container noheight"><a class="link rapid-noclick-resp" title="" href="https://news.yahoo.com/tagged/climate-change/" data-ylk=""><img decoding="async" class="caas-img caas-lazy caas-loaded" src="https://s.yimg.com/ny/api/res/1.2/yXwDqcW.i8eC9k6kPk1.bA--/YXBwaWQ9aGlnaGxhbmRlcjt3PTcwNTtjZj13ZWJw/https://s.yimg.com/os/creatr-uploaded-images/2021-11/f81207c0-3bea-11ec-b9ef-467561b8b81f" alt="" data-caas-lazy-loading-init="1" /></a></div>
</div>
</div>
</figure>
<p>GLASGOW, Scotland — In an interview at the U.N. Climate Change Conference, Secretary of Energy Jennifer Granholm told Yahoo News on Friday that the Biden administration is “very bullish” on building new nuclear reactors in the United States.</p>
<p>“We are very bullish on these advanced nuclear reactors,” she said. “We have, in fact, invested a lot of money in the research and development of those. We are very supportive of that.”</p>
<p>Nuclear energy is controversial among environmental activists and experts because while it does not create the greenhouse gas emissions that cause climate change, it has the potential to trigger dangerous nuclear meltdowns and creates radioactive nuclear waste.</p>
<p>Most of the Biden administration’s effort to reduce reliance on fossil fuels, and almost all the rhetoric at the climate change conference, also known as COP26, is about promoting other clean forms of energy, such as wind and solar power.</p>
</div>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and scream. I mean read. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/lies-told-by-energy-companies/we-dont-need-no-stinkin-baseload-what-we-need-is-more-storage/">We Don&#8217;t Need No Stinkin Baseload &#8211; What we need is more storage</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/lies-told-by-energy-companies/we-dont-need-no-stinkin-baseload-what-we-need-is-more-storage/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Grid Regulation With Alternative Power &#8211; Its almost as important how you turn alternative power off as how you turn it on</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/grid-regulation-with-alternative-power-its-almost-as-important-how-you-turn-alternative-power-off-as-how-you-turn-it-on/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/grid-regulation-with-alternative-power-its-almost-as-important-how-you-turn-alternative-power-off-as-how-you-turn-it-on/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 21:15:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[batteries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burn free generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Other countries advances]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stewardship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=8507</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Can the Grid run only on Alternative Power? Yes. Can we store enough Alternative Energy to run the Grid smoothly (night and day, whenever)? Yes. Can we turn Alternative Power off if we need to? This video argues, Yes. Again, &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/grid-regulation-with-alternative-power-its-almost-as-important-how-you-turn-alternative-power-off-as-how-you-turn-it-on/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/grid-regulation-with-alternative-power-its-almost-as-important-how-you-turn-alternative-power-off-as-how-you-turn-it-on/">Grid Regulation With Alternative Power &#8211; Its almost as important how you turn alternative power off as how you turn it on</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Can the Grid run only on Alternative Power? Yes. Can we store enough Alternative Energy to run the Grid smoothly (night and day, whenever)? Yes. Can we turn Alternative Power off if we need to? This video argues, Yes. Again, I do not normally do videos because this is a print based blog. But this video says it better than any article I have ever seen. So:</p>
<p><a href="https://digg.com/video/what-happens-when-islands-makes-way-more-power-than-neededs">https://digg.com/video/what-happens-when-islands-makes-way-more-power-than-neededs</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and watch. Its only 6 minutes. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/grid-regulation-with-alternative-power-its-almost-as-important-how-you-turn-alternative-power-off-as-how-you-turn-it-on/">Grid Regulation With Alternative Power &#8211; Its almost as important how you turn alternative power off as how you turn it on</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/grid-regulation-with-alternative-power-its-almost-as-important-how-you-turn-alternative-power-off-as-how-you-turn-it-on/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Unions And Climate Change &#8211; Some of their stances are just bad</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/environmentalism/unions-and-climate-change-some-of-their-stances-are-just-bad/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/environmentalism/unions-and-climate-change-some-of-their-stances-are-just-bad/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 15:52:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[burning behavior]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environmentalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[national organizations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stewardship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=8466</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>As A HUGE disclaimer, my wife are both union members. Our prents were Union members. My great grandfather was a card carrying Socialist and ran for City Alderman in Chicago as such. So I believe in Unions. But when they &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/environmentalism/unions-and-climate-change-some-of-their-stances-are-just-bad/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/environmentalism/unions-and-climate-change-some-of-their-stances-are-just-bad/">Unions And Climate Change &#8211; Some of their stances are just bad</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As A HUGE disclaimer, my wife are both union members. Our prents were Union members. My great grandfather was a card carrying Socialist and ran for City Alderman in Chicago as such. So I believe in Unions. But when they get stuck on saving jobs no matter what. They get a little lost and sometimes real lost. These becomes apparent with police unions &#8211; though appropo to this topic. They protect bad cops for jobs sake. Well, the IBEW and other unions are no better. Instead of saying, &#8220;We will change power plant jobs for better jobs in the green sector&#8221;. They say, &#8220;We will not lose the jobs we have&#8221;. They act like it is heroic when it is pathetic.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.vox.com/2019/5/22/18628299/green-new-deal-labor-union-2020-democrats">https://www.vox.com/2019/5/22/18628299/green-new-deal-labor-union-2020-democrats</a></p>
<div class="c-entry-hero__header-wrap">
<h1 class="c-page-title">The Green New Deal is fracturing a critical base for Democrats: unions</h1>
</div>
<p class="c-entry-summary p-dek">National labor leaders oppose the Green New Deal but some state unions endorse it. That’s a challenge for presidential contenders.</p>
<div class="c-byline"><span class="c-byline-wrapper"> By <span class="c-byline__item"> <a href="https://www.vox.com/authors/umair-irfan" data-analytics-link="author-name"><span class="c-byline__author-name">Umair Irfan</span></a> </span> <span class="c-byline__item"> Updated <time class="c-byline__item" datetime="2019-06-19T13:24:49" data-ui="timestamp"> Jun 19, 2019, 9:24am EDT </time> </span> </span></div>
<p id="opk71z">As a statement of principles and goals, the <a href="https://www.vox.com/energy-and-environment/2018/12/21/18144138/green-new-deal-alexandria-ocasio-cortez">Green New Deal</a> seems to take economic justice and workers’ rights pretty seriously. It calls for a federal jobs guarantee. It says we need workforce retraining, strengthening collective bargaining rights, retirement security, and universal health care.</p>
<p id="u617zM">The <a href="https://www.congress.gov/116/bills/hres109/BILLS-116hres109ih.pdf">resolution</a> decries “antilabor policies” and says it must be fleshed out with input from “frontline and vulnerable communities, labor unions, [and] worker cooperatives,” with the goal of creating “high-quality union jobs.”</p>
<p id="ARigMl">Which is why it was so surprising that the leader of the national AFL-CIO — the largest federation of labor unions in the United States, representing more than 12.5 million workers — recently came out against the proposal.</p>
<p id="bxSEK1">“We weren’t part of the process, so the worker’s interest wasn’t really figured into it,” AFL-CIO president <a href="https://livestream.com/accounts/27531088/events/8651345/videos/190374708">Richard Trumka</a> said in April. “We would want a whole bunch of changes made so that workers and our jobs are protected in the process.”</p>
<p id="X675Sd">(Disclosure: I was on the bargaining committee of the Vox Media Union. We organized with Writers Guild of America, East, which is affiliated with the AFL-CIO.)</p>
<p id="dV1JP7">But this week, Maine Gov. Janet Mills signed her state’s version of a Green New Deal with the backing of labor unions.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read. More next week</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/environmentalism/unions-and-climate-change-some-of-their-stances-are-just-bad/">Unions And Climate Change &#8211; Some of their stances are just bad</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/environmentalism/unions-and-climate-change-some-of-their-stances-are-just-bad/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tankless Water Heaters Are Grand &#8211; This piece goes to great lengths to prove it</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/residential-energy-efficiency/tankless-water-heaters-are-grand-this-piece-goes-to-great-lengths-to-prove/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/residential-energy-efficiency/tankless-water-heaters-are-grand-this-piece-goes-to-great-lengths-to-prove/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 19:03:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burning reduction methods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy conservation measures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[residential energy efficiency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water conservation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water efficiency]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=8424</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>First off, spell check does not like the word tankless. You would think by now that the people at WORD Press would have gotten over that spelling by now. Second off (to be consistent) this is not and article that &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/residential-energy-efficiency/tankless-water-heaters-are-grand-this-piece-goes-to-great-lengths-to-prove/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/residential-energy-efficiency/tankless-water-heaters-are-grand-this-piece-goes-to-great-lengths-to-prove/">Tankless Water Heaters Are Grand &#8211; This piece goes to great lengths to prove it</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>First off, spell check does not like the word tankless. You would think by now that the people at WORD Press would have gotten over that spelling by now. Second off (to be consistent) this is not and article that CES can defend or debate. It is an article generated by another site so &#8220;Buyer Beware&#8221;. The articles has a lot of extraneous Ads and unnecessary clutter. Please feel free to ignore all of that. I have read the article and for the most part it is factual, and more extensive then most. So with out further ado:</p>
<p><a href="https://happydiyhome.com/tankless-water-heater-cost/">https://happydiyhome.com/tankless-water-heater-cost/</a></p>
<header class="entry-header">
<h1 class="entry-title">Tankless Water Heater Cost &amp; Pros and Cons – Are They Worth It?</h1>
<div class="entry-meta"><span class="posted-on"><a title="12:26 pm" href="https://happydiyhome.com/tankless-water-heater-cost/" rel="bookmark"><time class="updated" datetime="2020-12-31T14:01:31+00:00">December 31, 2020</time><time class="entry-date published" datetime="2020-12-31T12:26:25+00:00">December 31, 2020</time></a></span> <span class="byline">by <span class="author vcard"><a class="url fn n" title="View all posts by HappyDIYHome Staff" href="https://happydiyhome.com/author/wpx_jenrevie/" rel="author"><span class="author-name">HappyDIYHome Staff</span></a></span></span></div>
</header>
<div class="entry-content">
<p>Water heaters are extremely important to your <a href="https://happydiyhome.com/best-drain-cleaner/">plumbing system</a>, and this goes for both residential buildings and commercial spaces. Many people are turning to newer options, and this can lead you to wonder what a tankless water heater costs because this style of water heater will only heat up the water you use. Traditionally, water heaters heated and stored water on a continuous basis, and this can be expensive if you use a lot of water. As long as they get installed and connected correctly, it’s easy to control your tankless water heater cost for years at a time.</p>
<p>You get the choice of a single point unit or whole house units. A single point unit is slightly more inexpensive to buy and install because you put them right next to a water source. Whole house units cost more to install, but they are powerful enough to heat all of the water in your home at one time. The tankless water heater cost has a slightly wider price range due to a variety of the factors, and it starts at $2,000 and goes up to around $4,500 from start to finish.</p>
<p>The average cost is right around $2,800 for a whole house gas unit. The tankless water heater cost has fluctuating labor rates too. The flow rate, brand, and type will also influence your tankless water heater cost, and this is why you want to get a few estimates before you settle on one company to perform the installation. This can help ensure that you get a fair price with professional-quality results.</p>
</div>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read this very long article. But if you just want to know the pros and cons go to the end. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/residential-energy-efficiency/tankless-water-heaters-are-grand-this-piece-goes-to-great-lengths-to-prove/">Tankless Water Heaters Are Grand &#8211; This piece goes to great lengths to prove it</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/residential-energy-efficiency/tankless-water-heaters-are-grand-this-piece-goes-to-great-lengths-to-prove/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ban Cars! Ban Cars! Ban Cars! &#8211; We will try anyway</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/bicycling/ban-cars-ban-cars-ban-cars-we-will-try-anyway/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/bicycling/ban-cars-ban-cars-ban-cars-we-will-try-anyway/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 21:19:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[air pollution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bicycling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children and the environment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outdoors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stewardship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=8367</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>It seems really weird that we all started out on bikes after horses and before cars were really affordable. There was a real love affair with bikes in the modern urban environment around the 1900s. Especially women who had never &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/bicycling/ban-cars-ban-cars-ban-cars-we-will-try-anyway/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/bicycling/ban-cars-ban-cars-ban-cars-we-will-try-anyway/">Ban Cars! Ban Cars! Ban Cars! &#8211; We will try anyway</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It seems really weird that we all started out on bikes after horses and before cars were really affordable. There was a real love affair with bikes in the modern urban environment around the 1900s. Especially women who had never been allowed to get about. Bikes came on strong before mores or laws could be erected (so to speak) and women just went bonkers. Now every envirofreak (no offense intended) wants to go back to them. We shall see. We shall see.</p>
<p><iframe class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" title="The City Where Cars Are Not Welcome" src="https://www.nytimes.com/svc/oembed/html/?url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.nytimes.com%2F2021%2F02%2F28%2Fbusiness%2Fheidelberg-cars-environment.html#?secret=DmSVzvpF08" data-secret="DmSVzvpF08" scrolling="no" frameborder="0"></iframe></p>
<div class="css-1vkm6nb ehdk2mb0">
<h1 id="link-1b876da5" class="css-1w1syaa e1h9rw200" data-test-id="headline">The City Where Cars Are Not Welcome</h1>
</div>
<p class="css-1b6a17a e1wiw3jv0">As automakers promise to get rid of internal combustion engines, Heidelberg is trying to get rid of autos.</p>
<div id="fullBleedHeaderContent">
<div class="css-1wx1auc e1gnum311">
<div class="css-18e8msd">
<div class="css-vp77d3 epjyd6m0">
<div class="css-hus3qt ey68jwv0" aria-hidden="true"><a class="css-uwwqev" href="https://www.nytimes.com/by/jack-ewing"><img decoding="async" class="css-1rjmmt7 ey68jwv2" title="Jack Ewing" src="https://static01.nyt.com/images/2018/07/18/multimedia/author-jack-ewing/author-jack-ewing-thumbLarge.png" alt="Jack Ewing" /></a></div>
<div class="css-1baulvz">
<p class="css-4z5zii e1jsehar1"><span class="byline-prefix">By </span><span class="css-1baulvz last-byline"><a class="css-hogf08 e1jsehar0" href="https://www.nytimes.com/by/jack-ewing">Jack Ewing</a></span></p>
</div>
</div>
<ul class="css-1u1psjv epjyd6m3">
<li class="css-ccw2r3 epjyd6m1"><time class="css-ld3wwf e16638kd2" datetime="2021-03-03T15:41:46-05:00"><span class="css-1sbuyqj e16638kd3">Published Feb. 28, 2021</span><span class="css-233int e16638kd4">Updated March 3, 2021</span></time></li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<section class="meteredContent css-1r7ky0e">
<div class="css-1fanzo5 StoryBodyCompanionColumn">
<div class="css-53u6y8">
<p class="css-axufdj evys1bk0">HEIDELBERG, Germany — Eckart Würzner, a mayor on a mission to make his city emission free, is not terribly impressed by promises from <a class="css-1g7m0tk" title="" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/01/29/business/general-motors-electric-cars.html">General Motors</a>, <a class="css-1g7m0tk" title="" href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/02/17/business/ford-says-it-will-phase-out-gasoline-powered-vehicles-in-europe.html">Ford</a> and other big automakers to swear off fossil fuels.</p>
<p class="css-axufdj evys1bk0">Not that Mr. Würzner, the mayor of Heidelberg, is against electric cars. The postcard-perfect city, in southern Germany, gives residents who buy a battery-powered vehicle a bonus of up to 1,000 euros, or $1,200. They get another €1,000 if they install a charging station.</p>
<p class="css-axufdj evys1bk0">But electric cars are low on the list of tools that Mr. Würzner is using to try to cut Heidelberg’s impact on the climate, an effort that has given the city, home to Germany’s oldest university and an 800-year-old castle ruin, a reputation as a pioneer in environmentally conscious urban planning.</p>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go the read &#8211; once you catch your breath. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/bicycling/ban-cars-ban-cars-ban-cars-we-will-try-anyway/">Ban Cars! Ban Cars! Ban Cars! &#8211; We will try anyway</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/bicycling/ban-cars-ban-cars-ban-cars-we-will-try-anyway/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Joe Biden Will Save The World &#8211; Well maybe not but he has a Climate Czar</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/environmentalism/joe-biden-will-save-the-world-well-maybe-not-but-he-has-a-climate-czar/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/environmentalism/joe-biden-will-save-the-world-well-maybe-not-but-he-has-a-climate-czar/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2021 20:42:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[burning reduction methods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environmentalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outdoors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stewardship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=8344</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>My headline here kind of says it ALL. I mean, no one has ever had a Climate Czar before. No one has moved as rapidly to undue the damage done by The Cheeto Burrito. It might now be a horse &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/environmentalism/joe-biden-will-save-the-world-well-maybe-not-but-he-has-a-climate-czar/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/environmentalism/joe-biden-will-save-the-world-well-maybe-not-but-he-has-a-climate-czar/">Joe Biden Will Save The World &#8211; Well maybe not but he has a Climate Czar</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>My headline here kind of says it ALL. I mean, no one has ever had a Climate Czar before. No one has moved as rapidly to undue the damage done by The Cheeto Burrito. It might now be a horse race, instead of a jump over a cliff. But the race will be tight. Still, if we are trying &#8211; we can fail and in the long long run, win.</p>
<p><a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/article/climate-change-after-pandemic.html?utm_source=pocket-newtab">https://nymag.com/intelligencer/article/climate-change-after-pandemic.html?utm_source=pocket-newtab</a></p>
<div class="article-header-section rubric-nav"><a class="rubric rubric-life-after-warming special-feature " href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/tags/life-after-warming/">life after warming</a> <time class="article-timestamp" datetime="2021-01-19T06:00:21.031-05:00" data-editable="publishedDate"> <span class="article-date">Jan. 19, 2021</span> </time></div>
<div></div>
<div class="article-header-section">
<h1 class="headline-primary" data-editable="overrideHeadline">After Alarmism</h1>
<h2 class="display-teaser" data-editable="displayTeaser">The war on climate denial has been won. And that’s not the only good news.</h2>
<div class="bylines"><span class="primary-bylines" data-editable="bylines"> By <span class="author-name"><a class="article-author" href="https://nymag.com/author/david-wallace-wells/" rel="author">David Wallace-Wells</a></span></span></div>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p class="clay-paragraph" data-editable="text" data-uri="nymag.com/intelligencer/_components/clay-paragraph/instances/ckk4aqpn8000t3h6fvykd7gdj@published" data-word-count="20"><em>This article was featured in </em><a href="http://nymag.com/tags/one-great-story/"><em>One Great Story</em></a><em>, </em>New York<em>’s reading recommendation newsletter. </em><a href="http://nymag.com/onegreatstory"><em>Sign up here</em></a><em> to get it nightly.</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p class="clay-paragraph_drop-cap" data-editable="text" data-uri="nymag.com/intelligencer/_components/clay-paragraph/instances/ckk0bmbxs00283h6f5jo5lgiq@published" data-word-count="23"><strong>In the American Southwest,</strong> birds fell dead from the sky by the tens of thousands, succumbing mid-flight to starvation, emaciated by climate change.</p>
<p class="clay-paragraph" data-editable="text" data-uri="nymag.com/intelligencer/_components/clay-paragraph/instances/ckk0bmeiq002h3h6fsjdhhmgo@published" data-word-count="73">Across the horn of Africa swarmed 200 billion locusts, 25 for every human on earth, darkening the sky in clouds as big as whole cities, descending on cropland and chewing through as much food as tens of millions of people eat in a day, eventually dying in such agglomerating mounds they stopped trains in their tracks — all told, 8,000 times as many locusts as could be expected in the absence of warming.</p>
<p class="clay-paragraph" data-editable="text" data-uri="nymag.com/intelligencer/_components/clay-paragraph/instances/ckk0bmeir002i3h6fhay07oy1@published" data-word-count="73">The fires, you know. Or do you? In California in 2020, <a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/2020/09/california-cant-afford-to-wait-for-climate-action.html">twice as much land burned</a> as had ever burned before in any year in the modern history of the state — five of the six biggest fires ever recorded. In Siberia, “zombie fires” smoldered anomalously all through the Arctic winter; in Brazil, a quarter of the Pantanal, the world’s largest wetland, was incinerated; in Australia, flames took the lives of 3?billion animals.</p>
<p class="clay-paragraph" data-editable="text" data-uri="nymag.com/intelligencer/_components/clay-paragraph/instances/ckk0bmeir002j3h6f4ggcgvqb@published" data-word-count="115">All year, a planet transformed by the burning of carbon discharged what would have once been called portents of apocalypse. The people of that planet, as a whole, didn’t take much notice — distracted by the pandemic and trained, both by the accumulating toll of recent disasters and the ever-rising volume of climate alarm, to see what might once have looked like brutal ruptures in lived reality instead as logical developments in a known pattern. Our time has been so stuffed with disasters that it was hard to see the arrival of perhaps the unlikeliest prophecy of all: that the plague year may have marked, for climate change, a turning point, and for the better.</p>
<div class="divider_short" data-uri="nymag.com/intelligencer/_components/divider/instances/ckk0bs5ro004h3h6fjtdvmtph@published" data-editable="settings"></div>
<p class="clay-paragraph_drop-cap" data-editable="text" data-uri="nymag.com/intelligencer/_components/clay-paragraph/instances/ckk0bmeis002k3h6fd5p21za7@published" data-word-count="88"><strong>When trying to</strong> share good news about climate, it pays to be cautious, since so many have looked foolish playing Pollyanna. A turning point isn’t an endgame, or a victory, or a cessation of the need to struggle — for speedier decarbonization, for a sturdier future, for climate justice. Already, a future without profound climate suffering has been almost certainly foreclosed by decades of inaction, which means the burden of managing those impacts equitably will be handed down, generation to generation, into an indefinite and contested climate future.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read (hurrah). More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/environmentalism/joe-biden-will-save-the-world-well-maybe-not-but-he-has-a-climate-czar/">Joe Biden Will Save The World &#8211; Well maybe not but he has a Climate Czar</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/environmentalism/joe-biden-will-save-the-world-well-maybe-not-but-he-has-a-climate-czar/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Cheeto Burrito Seeks To Destroy Tsongass National Forest &#8211; Destruction is his legacy</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/stewardship/the-cheeto-burrito-seeks-to-destroy-tsongas-national-forest-destruction-is-his-legacy/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/stewardship/the-cheeto-burrito-seeks-to-destroy-tsongas-national-forest-destruction-is-his-legacy/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 17:08:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[burning behavior]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dumb ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environmentalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gaia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green wash. corporate cover ups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self inflicted wounds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stewardship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wild animals]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=8296</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>(please note that i use tsongas and tongass interchangeably) Destroy, Destroy, Destroy. That is what this President does because he has bought the general idea of &#8220;Disruption and Replacement&#8221; coming from Silicon Valley as a good thing for society. He &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/stewardship/the-cheeto-burrito-seeks-to-destroy-tsongas-national-forest-destruction-is-his-legacy/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/stewardship/the-cheeto-burrito-seeks-to-destroy-tsongas-national-forest-destruction-is-his-legacy/">The Cheeto Burrito Seeks To Destroy Tsongass National Forest &#8211; Destruction is his legacy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>(please note that i use tsongas and tongass interchangeably)</p>
<p>Destroy, Destroy, Destroy. That is what this President does because he has bought the general idea of &#8220;Disruption and Replacement&#8221; coming from Silicon Valley as a good thing for society. He doesn&#8217;t not understand that Disruption with out planning is BAD for society in general and only makes a few men (and women) rich. Or maybe, he actually does understand and just doesn&#8217;t care. One makes him evil by nature and the other makes him evil by nurture. I&#8217;ll leave it up to you to decide. One thing for sure is that his whole Presidency has been a disaster for the environment and the Earth, and that will be his lasting legacy.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/nation/2020/10/28/tongass-national-forest-alaska-exempt-roadless-rule-usda/6065610002/">https://www.usatoday.com/story/news/nation/2020/10/28/tongass-national-forest-alaska-exempt-roadless-rule-usda/6065610002/</a></p>
<h1>USA Today</h1>
<h1 class="gnt_ar_hl">Feds end road, logging restrictions in Alaska&#8217;s Tongass National Forest, one of the world&#8217;s largest temperate rainforests</h1>
<div class="gnt_ar_by">Becky Bohrer</div>
<div class="gnt_ar_pb">The Associated Press</div>
<div class="gnt_ar_dt" aria-label="Published: 11:09 p.m. ET Oct. 28, 2020 Updated: 11:11 p.m. ET Oct. 28, 2020">Published 11:00 pm Oct 28, 2020</div>
<div aria-label="Published: 11:09 p.m. ET Oct. 28, 2020 Updated: 11:11 p.m. ET Oct. 28, 2020"></div>
<div aria-label="Published: 11:09 p.m. ET Oct. 28, 2020 Updated: 11:11 p.m. ET Oct. 28, 2020">
<p class="gnt_ar_b_p">JUNEAU, Alaska — The federal government announced plans Wednesday to lift restrictions on logging and building roads in the country&#8217;s largest national forest, a pristine rainforest in Alaska that provides habitat for wolves, bears and salmon.</p>
<p class="gnt_ar_b_p">The U.S. Department of Agriculture said it has decided to exempt the Tongass National Forest from the so-called roadless rule, which bans road construction and timber harvests with limited exceptions. It applies to nearly one-quarter of all U.S. Forest Service lands.</p>
<p class="gnt_ar_b_p">Conservation groups vowed to fight the decision, describing it as short-sighted and driven by politics.</p>
<p class="gnt_ar_b_p">“The decision to roll back the roadless rule on the Tongass was made in spite of, not in support of, southeast Alaskans and our communities,” said Meredith Trainor, executive director of the Southeast Alaska Conservation Council. “In making this decision, the Trump administration and the sham rulemaking process they undertook in our region ignored economic realities, environmental imperatives, and worst of all, the will of the people who actually live here.”</p>
<aside class="gnt_m gnt_x gnt_x__lbl gnt_x__al" aria-label="advertisement">
<div id="ad-slot-7103-usatoday-native-article_link-news-national-2" class="gnt_x_sl gnt_x_al" data-g-r="lazy" data-gl-method="lazyLoadX" data-google-query-id="CNOHheeAj-0CFQ-uAQodEGEAnQ">
<div id="google_ads_iframe_7103/usatoday/native-article_link/news/national_0__container__">:}</div>
<div>Go there and read. More next week until mid January at least.</div>
</div>
</aside>
</div>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/stewardship/the-cheeto-burrito-seeks-to-destroy-tsongas-national-forest-destruction-is-his-legacy/">The Cheeto Burrito Seeks To Destroy Tsongass National Forest &#8211; Destruction is his legacy</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/stewardship/the-cheeto-burrito-seeks-to-destroy-tsongas-national-forest-destruction-is-his-legacy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
