<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>factory farming Archives - Community Energy Systems</title>
	<atom:link href="/censys/category/blog/factory-farming/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/censys/category/blog/factory-farming/</link>
	<description>Censys.org</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 19:41:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>I Am So Excited To Be Posting On Earth Day &#8211; The 50th Anniversary</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/bad-health-effects/i-am-so-excited-to-be-posting-on-earth-day-the-50th-anniversary/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/bad-health-effects/i-am-so-excited-to-be-posting-on-earth-day-the-50th-anniversary/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2020 19:09:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[air pollution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[aquifer damage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bad health effects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big coal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big oil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burning behavior]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dying planet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evil polluters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[factory farming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[global warming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lies told by energy companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[over population]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self inflicted wounds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water pollution]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=8093</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>That&#8217;s it. That&#8217;s all I can say. Well you know me, that&#8217;s not all I can say. Like the National Geographic Magazine says, they are divided about the results. We have accomplished alot but never enough because the root cause &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/bad-health-effects/i-am-so-excited-to-be-posting-on-earth-day-the-50th-anniversary/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/bad-health-effects/i-am-so-excited-to-be-posting-on-earth-day-the-50th-anniversary/">I Am So Excited To Be Posting On Earth Day &#8211; The 50th Anniversary</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>That&#8217;s it. That&#8217;s all I can say. Well you know me, that&#8217;s not all I can say. Like the National Geographic Magazine says, they are divided about the results. We have accomplished alot but never enough because the root cause of climate change is evil greed, better known as capitalism. As long as we practice those economics, we will continue down the drain. The drain that looks like this:</p>
<p><a href="https://newrepublic.com/article/157078/climate-crisis-will-just-shockingly-abrupt?utm_source=digg">https://newrepublic.com/article/157078/climate-crisis-will-just-shockingly-abrupt?utm_source=digg</a></p>
<div class="article-title" data-reactid="103">
<h1 class="article-headline" data-reactid="104"><span data-reactid="105">The Climate Crisis Will Be Just as Shockingly Abrupt</span></h1>
<h2 class="article-subhead" data-reactid="106"><span data-reactid="107">The coronavirus isn’t a reason to put climate policy on hold. It’s a warning of the calamities ahead.</span></h2>
</div>
<div class="article-meta" data-reactid="108">
<div class="author-list author-list-all author-list-inline" data-reactid="110"><span data-reactid="111">By </span><span class="author-list-item" data-reactid="112"><a class="author-melody-schreiber author-link" title="Melody Schreiber" href="https://newrepublic.com/authors/melody-schreiber" data-reactid="113">Melody Schreiber</a></span></div>
<h5 class="article-date" data-reactid="115"><time datetime="2020-03-27" data-reactid="116">March 27, 2020</time></h5>
</div>
<p>As governments around the globe debate how to respond both to the coronavirus itself and the economic chaos it has unleashed, a theme that’s come up over and over is how to prioritize what makes it into spending packages. In the United States, right-left fault lines have emerged over the question of bailing out emissions-heavy industries versus <a href="https://newrepublic.com/article/156903/golden-opportunity-green-stimulus">a greener stimulus</a>. On Thursday, the Environmental Protection Agency <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/03/26/climate/epa-coronavirus-pollution-rules.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">announced</a> a large-scale rollback of environmental regulations as a response to the pandemic—allowing many emitters to police themselves when it comes to pollution.</p>
<p>While <a href="https://www.technologyreview.com/s/615338/coronavirus-emissions-climate-change/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">some argue</a> that the oxygen in the climate debate should be taken up by the pandemic instead, the two issues aren’t mutually exclusive, experts say. In a warming climate, <a href="https://newrepublic.com/article/155746/climate-change-already-hurting-kids-health">more diseases are likely to emerge and spread</a>, making climate change action an important part of addressing future health crises. Moreover, the perception that climate change isn’t as urgent as other crises may rely on misunderstandings about how climate-related changes will happen. The rate isn’t constant: Instead, there’s reason to believe everything from Arctic melt to Amazon deforestation might experience what’s known as “tipping points,” where small changes in nature shift into rapid and irreversible damage.</p>
<p>Greenland and Antarctica are melting six times faster than they were in the 1990s, according to a <a href="https://www.nasa.gov/feature/jpl/greenland-antarctica-melting-six-times-faster-than-in-the-1990s" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">new study</a> in the journal <i>Nature.</i> Between 1992 and 2017, Greenland and Antarctica lost 6.4 trillion tons of ice. This falls under the <a href="https://www.ipcc.ch/srocc/chapter/summary-for-policymakers/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer">worst-case scenario</a> projected by the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change, and the effects are already being felt in many parts of the world. The IPCC predicts that by the end of the century, 400 million people around the globe could be at risk of coastal flooding every year from sea-level rise alone.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/bad-health-effects/i-am-so-excited-to-be-posting-on-earth-day-the-50th-anniversary/">I Am So Excited To Be Posting On Earth Day &#8211; The 50th Anniversary</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/bad-health-effects/i-am-so-excited-to-be-posting-on-earth-day-the-50th-anniversary/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>We Waste So Much Energy On Food &#8211; So food poisoning should not even be mentioned</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/burning-behavior/we-waste-so-much-energy-on-so-food-poisoning-should-not-even-mentioned/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/burning-behavior/we-waste-so-much-energy-on-so-food-poisoning-should-not-even-mentioned/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2014 21:06:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[burning behavior]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy Tough Love Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[factory farming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[farm waste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[local food production]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self inflicted wounds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stewardship]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=5236</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>But food poisoning is pretty common. Just think of the energy use on the farm. Huge machines powered by diesel gasoline, and huge energy consumption in fertilizers. We then transport the food huge distances. We sell them in huge stores &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/burning-behavior/we-waste-so-much-energy-on-so-food-poisoning-should-not-even-mentioned/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burning-behavior/we-waste-so-much-energy-on-so-food-poisoning-should-not-even-mentioned/">We Waste So Much Energy On Food &#8211; So food poisoning should not even be mentioned</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>But food poisoning is pretty common. Just think of the energy use on the farm. Huge machines powered by diesel gasoline, and huge energy consumption in fertilizers. We then transport the food huge distances. We sell them in huge stores oh keep the lights on at the local utility companies. Finally those of us in the first world drive it home in our and put it in our always on refrigerator.  So the fact that we let this thing called food sicken us but also kills us is just inexcusable. This on top of what some of us throw away. Well here is a site thate has on the facts. Unfortunately it is done mostly in photographs and this blog has problems with pictures so go there and look.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.health-science-degree.com/food-poisioning/">http://www.health-science-degree.com/food-poisioning/</a></p>
<p><strong>Health-Science-Degree.com</strong></p>
<p>The need to feed billions of people efficiently (and make billions of dollars off it) has given rise to large-scale animal farming operations. But are these mega-operations helping feed us or making us all sick?</p>
<h2>The Rise of the Factory Farm</h2>
<p>Factory farms, more accurately called concentrated animal feed operations (CAFOs), are large-scale industrial agricultural facilities that raise animals (usually at high density and kept in confined spaces) for human consumption.<br />
<strong>5%</strong><br />
Proportion of CAFOs among all U.S. animal farming operations<br />
<strong>50%</strong><br />
Food animals that come from CAFOs<br />
Due in part to these massive factory farms, since 1960 …<br />
… milk production has doubled<br />
… meat production has tripled<br />
… egg production has quadrupled<br />
Such operations also have introduced means to make animals grow heavier more quickly; chickens, for instance, grow twice as large in about half the time:<br />
<em>Decade</em> <em>Growth time</em> <em>Weight</em><br />
1920 16 weeks 2.2 pounds<br />
2013 7 weeks 5 pounds</p>
<h2>The Filthy Truth</h2>
<p>In addition to the moral and ethical problems with keeping animals in tiny pens where their natural behaviors are stunted, there’s the very real problem of what to do with all the waste they produce.<br />
These operations can house upwards of …<br />
1,000+ beef cows<br />
10,000+ chickens<br />
10,000+ hogs<br />
That adds up to tons and tons of — well, poop.<br />
<strong>300 million tons</strong><br />
Annual manure production of animals from CAFOs; that’s 65% of the waste from all animal operations in the U.S. And it’s more than double the amount of waste produced by the entire U.S. human population.<br />
This manure contains a variety of potential contaminants, such as nitrogen, phosphorus, E. coli, growth hormone, antibiotics, animal blood, copper sulfate and more. These contaminants find their way to the groundwater and even pollute the air.<br />
In addition to the manure concern is the possibility that keeping animals in such close quarters encourages infections that are then passed to consumers.</p>
<h2>The Risks of Factory Meat</h2>
<p>CAFOs are susceptible primarily to three pathogens that also make people sick.<br />
<strong><em>E. coli</em></strong><br />
Introduction of a grain-based diet, rather than a grass-based diet, has raised E. coli rates among cows. While E. coli is always present in cows’ stomachs, grain-based diets have given rise to more harmful strains, such as O157:H7, which has found its way into water, produce and meat in recent years.<br />
<strong>16%</strong><br />
Percentage of foodborne illnesses caused by strains of E. coli<br />
<strong><em>MRSA</em></strong><br />
Methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus can be spread by human and animal carriers and has become abundant in our environment. European studies have shown a link between MRSA and factory pig farms.<br />
<strong>80,000</strong><br />
Annual MRSA infections in humans, though many cases occur in hospital settings<br />
<strong><em>Campylobacter and salmonella</em></strong><br />
Campylobacter and salmonella are most commonly found in eggs and poultry, and both pathogens have recently shown signs of drug resistance.<br />
<em>Positive tests for salmonella</em><br />
Farms with caged hens 23.4%<br />
Organic flocks 4.4%<br />
Free-range flocks 6.5%<br />
<strong>62%</strong><br />
Chicken sold in supermarkets contaminated with campylobacter</p>
<h2>The Environmental Effects</h2>
<p>Potential damage to the environment from mismanagement of the tons of waste produced by these massive operations extends to both the air and water.</p>
<ul>
<li>Excess nitrogen and phosphorus in water</li>
<li>Fish kills</li>
<li>Toxic algal blooms</li>
<li>Waste and pathogens in drinking water</li>
<li>Respiratory problems from dust and odors</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="http://www.health-science-degree.com/"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-422" src="http://www.health-science-degree.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/Factory-Farms-FB-290x300.jpg" alt="Factory-Farms-FB" width="290" height="300" /></a></p>
<p><strong>SOURCES:</strong><br />
<a href="http://www.ucsusa.org/">http://www.ucsusa.org/</a><br />
<a href="http://www.cdc.gov/">http://www.cdc.gov/</a><br />
<a href="http://www.organicconsumers.org/">http://www.organicconsumers.org/</a><br />
<a href="http://news.yahoo.com/">http://news.yahoo.com/</a><br />
<a href="http://www.epa.gov/">http://www.epa.gov/</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burning-behavior/we-waste-so-much-energy-on-so-food-poisoning-should-not-even-mentioned/">We Waste So Much Energy On Food &#8211; So food poisoning should not even be mentioned</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/burning-behavior/we-waste-so-much-energy-on-so-food-poisoning-should-not-even-mentioned/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is There A Pandemic Building In China &#8211; Oh God let&#8217;s hope not</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/wild-animals/is-there-a-pandemic-building-in-china-oh-god-lets-hope-not/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/wild-animals/is-there-a-pandemic-building-in-china-oh-god-lets-hope-not/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 17:15:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[children and the environment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dying planet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy Tough Love Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environmentalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evil polluters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[factory farming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[farm waste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gaia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[garbage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[military polluters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[old tired advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outdoors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[over population]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pollution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self inflicted wounds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smoke]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water pollution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wild animals]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=4699</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>There are many things that environmentalists have said over the years. The 2 most consistently true ones are that there are too many people on this planet and the other is that we will pay a price for befouling our &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/wild-animals/is-there-a-pandemic-building-in-china-oh-god-lets-hope-not/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/wild-animals/is-there-a-pandemic-building-in-china-oh-god-lets-hope-not/">Is There A Pandemic Building In China &#8211; Oh God let&#8217;s hope not</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There are many things that environmentalists have said over the years. The 2 most consistently true ones are that there are too many people on this planet and the other is that we will pay a price for befouling our planet. This has led some to talk about the possibility of a human &#8220;die back&#8221;. Is this what the beginning of one might look like?</p>
<p><a href="http://www.foreignpolicy.com/articles/2013/04/01/is_this_a_pandemic_being_born_china_pigs_virus">http://www.foreignpolicy.com/articles/2013/04/01/is_this_a_pandemic_being_born_china_pigs_virus</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div id="art-mast">
<div>
<h1><a title="Is This a Pandemic Being Born?" href="http://www.foreignpolicy.com/articles/2013/04/01/is_this_a_pandemic_being_born_china_pigs_virus">Is This a Pandemic Being Born?</a></h1>
<h2>China&#8217;s mysterious pig, duck, and people deaths could be connected. And that should worry us.</h2>
</div>
<h3>BY LAURIE GARRETT | APRIL 1, 2013</h3>
</div>
<p>Here&#8217;s how it would happen. Children playing along an urban river bank would spot hundreds of grotesque, bloated pig carcasses bobbing downstream. Hundreds of miles away, angry citizens would protest the rising stench from piles of dead ducks and swans, their rotting bodies collecting by the thousands along river banks. And three unrelated individuals would stagger into three different hospitals, gasping for air. Two would quickly die of severe pneumonia and the third would lay in critical condition in an intensive care unit for many days. Government officials would announce that a previously unknown virus had sickened three people, at least, and killed two of them. And while the world was left to wonder how the pigs, ducks, swans, and people might be connected, the World Health Organization would release deliberately terse statements, offering little insight.</p>
<p>It reads like a movie plot &#8212; I should know, as I was a consultant for Steven Soderbergh&#8217;s <em>Contagion</em>. But the facts delineated are all true, and have transpired over the last six weeks in China. The events could, indeed, be unrelated, and the new virus, a form of influenza denoted as H7N9, may have already run its course, infecting just three people and killing two.</p>
<p>Or this could be how pandemics begin.</p>
<p>On March 10, residents of China&#8217;s powerhouse metropolis, Shanghai, noticed some dead pigs floating among garbage flotsam in the city&#8217;s Huangpu River. The vile carcasses appeared in Shanghai&#8217;s most important tributary of the mighty Yangtze, a 71-mile river that is edged by the Bund, the city&#8217;s main tourist area, and serves as the primary source of drinking water and ferry travel for the 23 million residents of the metropolis and its millions of visitors. The vision of a few dead pigs on the surface of the Huangpu was every bit as jarring for local Chinese as porcine carcasses would be for French strolling the Seine, Londoners along the Thames, or New Yorkers looking from the Brooklyn Bridge down on the East River.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/wild-animals/is-there-a-pandemic-building-in-china-oh-god-lets-hope-not/">Is There A Pandemic Building In China &#8211; Oh God let&#8217;s hope not</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/wild-animals/is-there-a-pandemic-building-in-china-oh-god-lets-hope-not/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Green Economy &#8211; It can start with how we farm</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/methane-production/the-green-economy-it-can-start-with-how-we-farm/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/methane-production/the-green-economy-it-can-start-with-how-we-farm/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2012 17:43:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[aquifer damage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biofuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children and the environment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy conservation measures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy Tough Love Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environmental blogs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ethanol]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[factory farming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[farm waste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gardening]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[methane]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[methane production]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outdoors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[recycling]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stewardship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water efficiency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wild animals]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=3734</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Between the nitrogin that they hose around the environment and the methane they spew, we have to change farming if we are going to change the world. http://www.farmingfirst.org/green-economy/ THIS IS THE STORY OF AGRICULTURE GREEN ECONOMY We need to make &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/methane-production/the-green-economy-it-can-start-with-how-we-farm/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/methane-production/the-green-economy-it-can-start-with-how-we-farm/">The Green Economy &#8211; It can start with how we farm</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Between the nitrogin that they hose around the environment and the methane they spew, we have to change farming if we are going to change the world.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.farmingfirst.org/green-economy/">http://www.farmingfirst.org/green-economy/</a></p>
<div>THIS IS THE STORY OF</div>
<div>AGRICULTURE<img decoding="async" src="http://www.farmingfirst.org/wordpress/wp-content/themes/farmingfirst2/greeneconomy/andthe.png" alt="" /> GREEN ECONOMY</div>
<div>We need to make the  global economy green.  Agriculture provides significant opportunities  for growth, investment and jobs to help make this happen.  <img decoding="async" src="http://www.farmingfirst.org/wordpress/wp-content/themes/farmingfirst2/greeneconomy/money.png" alt="" /></div>
<div>Everyone needs agriculture. Agriculture feeds  our entire population and produces fibre for clothing, feed for  livestock and bioenergy. Particularly in the developing world,  agriculture contributes significantly to GDP growth, leads the way in  poverty reduction and accounts for the lion&#8217;s share of employment  opportunities, especially for women.  Agriculture also has one of the  highest potentials for reducing carbon emissions and helping vulnerable  people adapt to climate change.</div>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/methane-production/the-green-economy-it-can-start-with-how-we-farm/">The Green Economy &#8211; It can start with how we farm</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/methane-production/the-green-economy-it-can-start-with-how-we-farm/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Out Of Africa &#8211; Disasters are sometimes seen as a good thing</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/out-of-africa-disasters-are-sometimes-seen-as-a-good-thing/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/out-of-africa-disasters-are-sometimes-seen-as-a-good-thing/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2011 19:44:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[burn free generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children and the environment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy Tough Love Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environmental blogs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environmentalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[factory farming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[farm waste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hydro electric]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[penetrating ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scarcity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stewardship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water efficiency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water pollution]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=3504</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Damming large rivers to generate electricity seemed like a good thing when there were only 1 billion or 2 people on the planet. But now with a planet nearing a human die back at 7 billion people and having stressed &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/out-of-africa-disasters-are-sometimes-seen-as-a-good-thing/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/out-of-africa-disasters-are-sometimes-seen-as-a-good-thing/">Out Of Africa &#8211; Disasters are sometimes seen as a good thing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Damming large rivers to generate electricity seemed like a good thing when there were only 1 billion or 2 people on the planet. But now with a planet nearing a human die back at 7 billion people and having stressed the planet to nearly its bursting point they are causing more problems then they are worth. I only include a couple of paragraphs here but you have to love, &#8220;making America the most damming country&#8221; part. You go girl..</p>
<p><a href="http://www.internationalrivers.org/africa/environmental-impacts-large-dams-african-examples">http://www.internationalrivers.org/africa/environmental-impacts-large-dams-african-examples</a></p>
<h1>Environmental Impacts of Large Dams: African examples</h1>
<div>
<div>
<div>October 1, 1996</div>
</div>
</div>
<div>
<div>
<div>Lori Pottinger</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>Some 40,000 large dams, most of which were built in the past 50 years,  now obstruct the world’s rivers. More than 400,000 square kilometers––an  area larger than Zimbabwe, and 13 times the size of Lesotho––have been  inundated by reservoirs worldwide. The world’s largest impoundment, the  8,500 sq.km. Volta Reservoir behind Ghana’s Akasombo Dam, flooded 4% of  that nation’s land area. In the United States, whose 5,500 large dams  make it the second most dammed country in the world, we have stopped  building large dams, and are now spending great amounts of money trying  to fix the problems created by existing dams.</p>
<p><strong>The Environmental Consequences of Big Dams</strong></p>
<p>Although the impacts of large dams have been well documented for some  time now, in case after case, new ones are proposed whose environmental  impacts are downplayed or even ignored. A 1990 internal survey of World  Bank hydroelectric dam projects showed that 58% were planned and built  without any consideration of downstream impacts, even when these impacts  could be predicted to cause massive coastal erosion, pollution and  other problems.</p>
<p>The following are some of the more serious environmental impacts of dams  on rivers and the life they support. I have concentrated on the kinds  of impacts that might affect the Orange River watershed, leaving out  other major dam–caused problems that have affected rivers under  different ecological circumstances.</p>
<p><strong>Effects on River Systems</strong></p>
<p>Reducing the flow of water from a river changes the landscape it flows  through, which in turn can affect the ecosystem’s flora and fauna. A dam  holds back sediments, especially the heavy gravel and cobbles. The  river, deprived of its sediment load, seeks to recapture it by eroding  the downstream channel and banks, undermining bridges and other  riverbank structures. Riverbeds are typically eroded by several meters  within a decade of first closing a dam; the damage can extend for tens  or even hundreds of kilometers below a dam. Within nine years of closing  Hoover Dam in the US, the riverbed below the dam had lowered by more  than 4 meters. Riverbed deepening will also lower the groundwater table  along a river, threatening vegetation and local wells in the floodplain  and requiring crop irrigation in places where there was previously no  need. The depletion of riverbed gravels reduces habitat for many fish  that spawn in the gravelly river bottom, and for invertebrates such as  insects, molluscs and crustaceans. Changes in the physical habitat and  hydrology of rivers are implicated in 93% of freshwater fauna declines  in North America.</p>
<p>Before the Aswan High Dam, the Nile River carried about 124 million tons  of sediment to the sea each year, depositing nearly 10 million tons on  the floodplain and delta. Today, 98% of that sediment remains behind the  dam. The result has been a drop in soil productivity and depth, among  other serious changes to Egypt’s floodplain agriculture. The Aswan Dam  has also led to serious coastal erosion, another problem stemming from  the loss of sediments in a dammed river. Another example of this problem  is along the mouth of the Volta River in Ghana. Akosombo Dam has cut  off the supply of sediment to the Volta Estuary, affecting also  neighboring Togo and Benin, whose coasts are now being eaten away at a  rate of 10–15 meters per year. A project to strengthen the Togo coast  has cost US$3.5 million for each kilometer protected. The story is the  same on coastline after coastline where dams have stopped a river’s  sediments.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read. More tomorrow.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/out-of-africa-disasters-are-sometimes-seen-as-a-good-thing/">Out Of Africa &#8211; Disasters are sometimes seen as a good thing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/out-of-africa-disasters-are-sometimes-seen-as-a-good-thing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Atrazine Peaks In Illinois Waters In April And May &#8211; Still getting the word out never hurts</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/burning-behavior/atrazine-peaks-in-illinois-waters-in-april-and-may-still-getting-the-word-out-never-hurts/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/burning-behavior/atrazine-peaks-in-illinois-waters-in-april-and-may-still-getting-the-word-out-never-hurts/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2011 18:41:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[burning behavior]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dying planet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy Tough Love Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environmental blogs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environmentalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[factory farming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[farm waste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[industry apologists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[national organizations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pollution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spirituality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stewardship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water pollution]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=3427</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I got this from my buddy Darryl Malek-Wiley. At: https://www.facebook.com/profile.php?id=100001252051472 He has been a very active environmentalist in Southern Louisiana for 30 years. He got it here: http://www.environmentalhealthnews.org/ehs/news/2011/2011-1123atrazine-tied-to-menstrual-irregularities Atrazine in water tied to menstrual irregularities, low hormones Women who drink &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/burning-behavior/atrazine-peaks-in-illinois-waters-in-april-and-may-still-getting-the-word-out-never-hurts/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burning-behavior/atrazine-peaks-in-illinois-waters-in-april-and-may-still-getting-the-word-out-never-hurts/">Atrazine Peaks In Illinois Waters In April And May &#8211; Still getting the word out never hurts</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I got this from my buddy Darryl Malek-Wiley. At:</p>
<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/profile.php?id=100001252051472">https://www.facebook.com/profile.php?id=100001252051472</a></p>
<p>He has been a very active environmentalist in Southern Louisiana for 30 years. He got it here:</p>
<p><a href="http://www.environmentalhealthnews.org/ehs/news/2011/2011-1123atrazine-tied-to-menstrual-irregularities">http://www.environmentalhealthnews.org/ehs/news/2011/2011-1123atrazine-tied-to-menstrual-irregularities</a></p>
<h1>Atrazine in water tied to menstrual irregularities, low hormones</h1>
<p>Women who drink water contaminated with low levels of the  weed-killer atrazine may be more likely to have irregular menstrual  cycles and low estrogen levels, scientists concluded in a new study. The  most widely used herbicide in the United States, atrazine is frequently  detected in surface and ground water, particularly in agricultural  areas of the Midwest. The newest research, which compared women in  Illinois farm towns to women in Vermont, adds to the growing scientific  evidence linking atrazine to altered hormones.</p>
<table width="150px">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="http://www.environmentalhealthnews.org/ehs/images/2011/November/2011-1123atrazine/2011-1129cropspray.jpg" alt="2011-1129cropspray" width="360" height="240" /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/ugacommunications/6253901921/">University of Georgia</a></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>The herbicide atrazine is frequently detected in surface and groundwater, especially near cornfields in the Midwest.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<div>By Lindsey Konkel<br />
Environmental Health News</div>
<div>Nov. 28, 2011</div>
<p>Women who drink water contaminated with low levels of the weed-killer  atrazine may be more likely to have irregular menstrual cycles and low  estrogen levels, scientists concluded in a new study.</p>
<p>The most  widely used herbicide in the United States, atrazine is frequently  detected in surface and ground water, particularly in agricultural areas  of the Midwest. Approximately 75 percent of all U.S. cornfields are  treated with atrazine each year.</p>
<p>The newest <a href="http://ttp//www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed?term=atrazine%20vermont">research</a>,  which compared women in Illinois to women in Vermont, adds to the  growing scientific evidence linking atrazine to altered hormones.</p>
<p>The women from Illinois farm towns were nearly five times more likely  to report irregular periods than the Vermont women, and more than six  times as likely to go more than six weeks between periods. In addition,  the Illinois women had significantly lower levels of estrogen during an  important part of the menstrual cycle.</p>
<p>Tap water in the  Illinois communities had double the concentration of atrazine in the  Vermont communities’ water. Nevertheless, the water in both states was  far below the federal drinking water standard currently enforced by the  U.S. Environmental Protection Agency.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>It is a long article. I stopped at the mention of Illinois. Go there and read. More tomorrow.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burning-behavior/atrazine-peaks-in-illinois-waters-in-april-and-may-still-getting-the-word-out-never-hurts/">Atrazine Peaks In Illinois Waters In April And May &#8211; Still getting the word out never hurts</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/burning-behavior/atrazine-peaks-in-illinois-waters-in-april-and-may-still-getting-the-word-out-never-hurts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Corporate Colonialism &#8211; They are carving up Africa again</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/burning-behavior/corporate-colonialism-they-are-carving-up-africa-again/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/burning-behavior/corporate-colonialism-they-are-carving-up-africa-again/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2011 17:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[burning behavior]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy Tough Love Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[factory farming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[farm waste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flatulence]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[food]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[global warming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green wash. corporate cover ups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[international energy groups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[over population]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scarcity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[schemes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[social crisis]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Speculators]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vampires]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wild animals]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=3379</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>When are the poor countries of the world going to catch a break. First they are conquered by the countries of Europe. Then they are handed over to corrupt and inept &#8220;local&#8221; leadership. Finally they are bought and paid for &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/burning-behavior/corporate-colonialism-they-are-carving-up-africa-again/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burning-behavior/corporate-colonialism-they-are-carving-up-africa-again/">Corporate Colonialism &#8211; They are carving up Africa again</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>When are the poor countries of the world going to catch a break. First they are conquered by the countries of Europe. Then they are handed over to corrupt and inept &#8220;local&#8221; leadership. Finally they are bought and paid for by the new corporate elites. This is just to0 nasty for words. But this is humans finest hour.</p>
<h1><a href="http://allafrica.com/africa/"><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Africa</span>:</a> The New Land Grab in Africa &#8211; An Alarming Scramble for the Continent Is On</h1>
<p>Agazit Abate</p>
<p>3 November 2011</p>
<p><em>Multinational corporations are buying enormous tracts of land in Africa to the detriment of local communities. <strong>Agazit Abate</strong> warns that the land grab puts countries on the path to increased food  insecurity, environmental degradation, increased reliance on aid and  marginalisation of farming and pastoralist communities.</em></p>
<div id="google_inset_a">
<div id="google_ads_div_AllAfrica_Story_InsetA_ad_container"><ins><ins></ins></ins></div>
</div>
<p>The recent phenomenon of land grab, as outlined in the extensive  research of the Oakland Institute, has resulted in the sale of enormous  portions of land throughout Africa. In 2009 alone, nearly 60 million  hectares of land were purchased or leased throughout the continent for  the production and export of food, cut flowers and agrofuel crops.</p>
<p>Land grab was in part spurred by the food and financial crisis of  2008 when international bodies, corporations, investment funds, wealthy  individuals, and governments began to re-focus their attention on  agriculture and food as a profitable commodity. As outlined in the  reports, the consequences of land grab include increased food  insecurity, environmental degradation, community repression and  displacement, and increased reliance on aid.</p>
<p><strong>MEET THE INVESTORS</strong></p>
<p>While media coverage has focused on the role of countries like India  and China in land deals, the Oakland Institute&#8217;s investigation reveals  the role of Western firms, wealthy US and European individuals, and  investment funds with ties to major banks such as Goldman Sachs and JP  Morgan. Investors include alternative investment firms like the  London-based Emergent that works to attract speculators, and various  universities like Harvard, Spelman and Vanderbilt.</p>
<p>Several Texas-based interests are associated with a major 600,000  hectares South Sudan deal which involves Kinyeti Development LLC, an  Austin, Texas-based &#8216;global business development partnership and holding  company&#8217; managed by Howard Eugene Douglas, a former United States  Ambassador at Large and Coordinator for Refugee Affairs. A key player in  the largest land deal in Tanzania is Iowa agribusiness entrepreneur and  Republican Party stalwart, Bruce Rastetter.</p>
<p>US companies are often below the radar, using subsidiaries registered  in other countries, like Petrotech-ffn Agro Mali which is a subsidiary  of Petrotech-ffn USA. Many European countries are also involved, often  with support provided by their governments and embassies in African  countries. For instance, Swedish and German firms have interests in the  production of biofuels in Tanzanian. Addax Bioenergy from Switzerland  and Quifel International Holdings (QIH) from Portugal are major  investors in Sierra Leone. Sierra Leone Agriculture (SLA) is actually a  subsidiary of the UK based Crad-1 (CAPARO Renewable Agriculture  Developments Ltd.), associated with the Tony Blair African Governance  Initiative.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>I just wanted to post the villains. For the rest of the analysis, go there and read that. More tomorrow.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burning-behavior/corporate-colonialism-they-are-carving-up-africa-again/">Corporate Colonialism &#8211; They are carving up Africa again</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/burning-behavior/corporate-colonialism-they-are-carving-up-africa-again/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Food That Is Genetically Modified &#8211; Yuck on a stick</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/burning-behavior/food-that-is-genetically-modified-yuck-on-a-stick/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/burning-behavior/food-that-is-genetically-modified-yuck-on-a-stick/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2011 20:49:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[biofuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burning behavior]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children and the environment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy Tough Love Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environmentalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evil polluters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[factory farming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[farm waste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gaia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green wash. corporate cover ups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[industry apologists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[masters of the universe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outdoors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self inflicted wounds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water pollution]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=2673</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>OK, so I am the first one to admit that humans have tinkered with animal&#8217;s and plant&#8217;s genetics for a 100,000 years before we even knew what genes were. The most famous was the creation or the domestication of wolfs. &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/burning-behavior/food-that-is-genetically-modified-yuck-on-a-stick/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burning-behavior/food-that-is-genetically-modified-yuck-on-a-stick/">Food That Is Genetically Modified &#8211; Yuck on a stick</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>OK, so I am the first one to admit that humans have tinkered with animal&#8217;s and plant&#8217;s genetics for a 100,000 years before we even knew what genes were. The most famous was the creation or the domestication of wolfs. If you feed them and they did not bite you they got to stay. If they bit you, you killed it and got another one. Made sense when a friendly wolf bred with another friendly wolf, the puppies would be more friendlier. Same with cattle. Breed a big cow with another bigger cow and you get bigger stronger cows. But this process many times took 100s of years and you had time to figure out whether it was safe or not. This is now happening in a single year&#8217;s time. There is no telling what we could be unleashing on ourselves. Worse yet, the big players in this area are some of the worst players on the planet. Monsanto, Dow, BSF. Companies known to be rapists of the planet.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.good.is/post/feast-your-eyes-the-atlas-of-genetically-modified-crops1/" target="_self" rel="noopener">http://www.good.is/post/feast-your-eyes-the-atlas-of-genetically-modified-crops1/</a></p>
<h1>Feast Your Eyes: The Atlas of Genetically Modified Crops</h1>
<p><img decoding="async" id="asset_304419" src="http://pre.cloudfront.goodinc.com/posts/full_1298490019GeneticallyModifiedCrops.jpg" alt="" /><br />
Yesterday, the <a href="http://www.isaaa.org/">International Service for the Acquisition of Agri-biotech Applications</a>,  a nonprofit organization funded in large part by the biotech industry,  issued a new report on the status of genetically modified crops around  the world.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.economist.com/blogs/dailychart/2011/02/daily_chart_genetically_modified_crops"><em>The Economist</em></a> has used ISAAA&#8217;s data to make a map showing where in the world GM crops  are grown. As you can see, the United States is by far the leader in  the field, with 165 million acres (66.8 million hectares) of GM crops  under cultivation, an increase of nearly 7 million acres on 2009 levels.</p>
<p>Clive James, ISAAA&#8217;s director and founder, <a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/science-environment-12541465">told the <em>BBC</em></a> that more than 15 million farmers grow GM crops, and that, &#8220;during  2010, the accumulated commercial biotech plantation exceeded one billion  hectares [2.47 billion acres]— that&#8217;s an area larger than the U.S. or  China,&#8221; and equivalent to 10 percent of the world&#8217;s arable land.</p>
<p>Meanwhile, <a href="http://www.economist.com/blogs/dailychart/2011/02/daily_chart_genetically_modified_crops"><em>The Economist</em></a> pointed out an interesting trend:</p>
<blockquote><p>Developing countries are planting GM crops at a more rapid rate than  rich countries. Brazil has added some 10m hectares [24.7 million acres]  since 2008 and overtook Argentina as the second-biggest grower in 2010.  India, too, increased its area by over 10 percent last year. The most  popular crop is soya, while the most common modification is tolerance to  herbicides.</p></blockquote>
<p>With <a href="http://www.upi.com/Science_News/2011/02/22/EU-votes-to-allow-modified-feed-crops/UPI-18101298434573/">the European Union having just voted to allow animal feed imports</a> containing up to 0.1 percent GM seeds (previously shipments found to  contain any trace of non-approved biotech crops were turned away upon  arrival at port), it does indeed seem—for better or for worse—as though  GM crops are here to stay.</p>
<p><em>Chart via </em><a href="http://www.economist.com/blogs/dailychart/2011/02/daily_chart_genetically_modified_crops">The Economist</a>.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burning-behavior/food-that-is-genetically-modified-yuck-on-a-stick/">Food That Is Genetically Modified &#8211; Yuck on a stick</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/burning-behavior/food-that-is-genetically-modified-yuck-on-a-stick/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Global Warming&#8217;s Impact On Illinois &#8211; Slightly warmer wetter Springs,</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/global-warming/global-warmings-impact-on-illinois-slightly-warmer-wetter-springs/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/global-warming/global-warmings-impact-on-illinois-slightly-warmer-wetter-springs/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2010 16:22:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[big whoop dee do]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[biofuel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dying planet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy Tough Love Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[factory farming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[farm waste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[global warming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gone pecan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outdoors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[over population]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scarcity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wild animals]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=1496</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Slightly cooler wetter Summers, and slightly warmer and wetter Falls with earlier first frosts. Oh that sounds so scary. But if you think about it, it is. I have said all along that the biggest early effect of Global Warming &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/global-warming/global-warmings-impact-on-illinois-slightly-warmer-wetter-springs/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/global-warming/global-warmings-impact-on-illinois-slightly-warmer-wetter-springs/">Global Warming&#8217;s Impact On Illinois &#8211; Slightly warmer wetter Springs,</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Slightly cooler wetter Summers, and slightly warmer and wetter Falls with earlier first frosts. Oh that sounds so scary. But if you think about it, it is. I have said all along that the biggest early effect of Global Warming is the disruption in farming. Farmers won&#8217;t know when to plant. They will have replant and they may not be able to harvest&#8230;This will mean that we can feed ourselves but we can&#8217;t feed the world. Food riots have already happened 2 years ago, thought governments were better prepared last year.</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t believe me? Let&#8217;s ask the experts.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.isws.illinois.edu/atmos/statecli/ElNino/elnino.htm" target="_self" rel="noopener">http://www.isws.illinois.edu/atmos/statecli/ElNino/elnino.htm</a></p>
<div>
<h2>El Niño and La Niña in Illinois</h2>
<p>El Niño and La Niña refer to periods when sea-surface temperatures   			along the equator in the Pacific Ocean are either unusually warm (El  Niño)  			or cold (La Niña). These events typically begin in the spring or  summer  			and fade by the following spring. A more complete description of El  Niño and La Niña can be 			found under <a href="http://www.isws.illinois.edu/atmos/statecli/ElNino/elnino.htm#resources">Other  Resources</a> below.</p>
<p>The NOAA Climate Prediction Center has identified 		<a href="http://www.cpc.ncep.noaa.gov/products/analysis_monitoring/enso_advisory/ensodisc.html"> a weak El Niño event</a> in the Pacific Ocean.      	This event is expected to strengthen and last through this winter  (2009-2010).      	Here is a series of maps on the historical  		<a href="http://www.isws.illinois.edu/atmos/statecli/ElNino/elnino.pdf">impacts  of El Niño on monthly temperature and precipitation</a> (pdf). In general, they produced <strong>warmer-than-normal  		temperatures in September and during December-March</strong>. In  		contrast, cooler-than-normal temperatures prevailed in  		August and April-May. The impact on monthly precipitation was both  		weaker and less consistent. Somewhat wetter conditions prevailed in  		August, October, and December while drier conditions were found in  		September.  [posted September 22, 2009]</p>
</div>
<h3><a name="nino"></a>Summary of Impacts of El Niño</h3>
<p>El Niño events vary in size, intensity, and duration. As a  result, the  				impacts can vary from one event to the next. In addition, there may  be other  				factors that influence our weather during these events.</p>
<ul>
<li>Summers tend to be slightly cooler and wetter than average</li>
<li>Falls tend to be wetter and cooler than average</li>
<li>Winters tend to be warmer and drier</li>
<li>Springs tend to be drier than average</li>
<li>Snowfall tends to be 70 to 90 percent of average</li>
<li>Heating degree days tend to be 80 to 90 percent of average.  Lower heating degree days mean lower heating bills.</li>
<li>Tends to reduce tornado activity in the High Plains and Midwest  and increases it in the Sout</li>
</ul>
<p>:}</p>
<p>He wants to blame it on El Nino, but notice later he says they have been getting weaker and weaker&#8230;What happens when they do not come?</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p><a href="http://www.aces.uiuc.edu/news/stories/news4422.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">http://www.aces.uiuc.edu/news/stories/news4422.html</a></p>
<h2>Farmers Who Plant &#8211; Or Replant &#8211; After June 20 May See  Yields Shrink By Half</h2>
<p>Published: Jun. 10, 2008</p>
<p>Source: Emerson Nafziger, 217-333-4424, <a href="mailto:ednaf@illinois.edu">ednaf@illinois.edu</a></p>
<p>CHAMPAIGN, Ill. &#8212; A costly  deadline looms for many growers in the Midwest, as every day of waiting  for the weather to cooperate to plant corn and soybeans reduces  potential yields. Research indicates that Illinois growers who plant  corn or soybeans near the end of June can expect a 50 percent reduction  in crop yield, according to a University of Illinois agriculture expert.</p>
<p>The U.S. Department of Agriculture reports that corn and soybean growers  in several Midwestern states are behind schedule on their planting. A  cooler and wetter-than-average spring has left Illinois and Indiana  furthest behind on planted corn and soybeans. Several other states are  lagging behind their normal planting schedules, but by a lesser margin.</p>
<p>In Illinois, 95 percent of the corn is planted and 88 percent has  emerged, but less than half of that is reported to be in good or  excellent condition. Fully 14 percent of the acres planted are in poor  or very poor condition, with another 38 percent reported as fair. Those  acres in poor or very poor condition may have to be replanted.</p>
<p>In Illinois, the corn was 7 inches high as of June 9, compared to an  average of 17 inches by this time in recent years.  Illinois crop  sciences professor Emerson Nafziger says cool temperatures and the third  wettest January-April since 1895 in Illinois have led to delays that  are undercutting potential yields.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p><a href="http://www.agpowermag.com/articles/articles.php?articleid=408" target="_self" rel="noopener">http://www.agpowermag.com/articles/articles.php?articleid=408</a></p>
<h1>Think Twice Before Tilling Corn Ground This Spring</h1>
<p><img decoding="async" src="http://www.agpowermag.com/articles/page_icon.gif" alt="" align="top" /> <a title="View all headlines in this issue" href="http://www.agpowermag.com/articles/issue.php?issue=1998-05">May, 1998</a></p>
<p>Thinking of taking a disk or field cultivator  to last year&#8217;s no-till field? Agronomists warn that just one tillage  pass is enough to negate many of the long-term benefits of no-till  farming.</p>
<p>&#8220;After two to five years of continuous no-till  farming, we see significant improvements in soil structure and organic  matter levels,&#8221; says Jerry Hatfield, a researcher with the USDA-ARS Soil  Tilth Lab in Ames, Iowa. No-till ground also resists crusting and has a  higher cation exchange capacity, which is the soil&#8217;s ability to hold  onto nutrients. Tillage &#8212; even just one pass &#8211; diminishes those  benefits.</p>
<p>Once you revert back to tillage, you&#8217;re also  giving up more immediate benefits like time, labor, and fuel savings,  points out Mike Plumer, natural resources educator with the University  of Illinois.</p>
<p>Despite these benefits, no-till corn acreage has  leveled off nationally and declined in some eastern Corn Belt states,  according to the Conservation Technology Information Center. Many blame  unseasonably cool and/or wet spring weather. In Iowa, for example, last  April was the coldest April since 1983 and the 16th coldest in 125 years  of state record keeping. Last May was</p>
<p>the seventh coldest May in 125 years.</p>
<p>Under these conditions, no-till soils start out  cooler and can take longer to warm up. That can put a strain on corn  emergence and early growth.</p>
<p>If El Nino brings warm, dry weather to the Corn  Belt this spring, no-till corn acreage could rebound, says Wayne  Pedersen, plant pathologist with the University of Illinois. &#8220;No-till  systems always do well in dry years,&#8221; Pedersen says. &#8220;No-till soils hold  onto moisture better than tilled soils. As a result, no-till corn can  tolerate a lack of rainfall &#8212; without yield loss &#8212; for a much longer  period than conventional till corn.&#8221;</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>I know that is 2008 analysis and comment. but like I said what if it doesn&#8217;t go away? hmmmmmm</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p><a href="http://web.extension.illinois.edu/stephenson/news/news17285.html" target="_self" rel="noopener">http://web.extension.illinois.edu/stephenson/news/news17285.html</a></p>
<h2>Spring Forage Seeding Considerations</h2>
<h4>FOR IMMEDIATE RELEASE<br />
March 15, 2010</h4>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="100%">Mother Nature did not allow many graziers to frost seed red clover  in late February-­early March.  Wet conditions have prompted several  forage producers to ask about seeding.  In the recent Iowa State  University <em>Integrated Crop Management News </em>newsletter, Steve  Barnhart, Extension forage specialist addressed the topic of &#8220;wet spring  forage planting considerations&#8221;.  With some minor modifications for  Illinois, the article follows.</p>
<p><strong>Can spring forage stands still successfully be plant? </strong>The  short answer is – yes, into the first ten days to two weeks of May  (late-summer seedings are more successful in southern Illinois).  The  end of the spring forage planting season is limited by seedling  development and growth into the summer months.  Most forage seedlings  are emerging and growing root systems</p>
<p>into the top one to three inches of the seedbed during the three to  four weeks following germination.<br />
The increasingly dry  and hot soil surfaces in late May and June increase the risk that the  small forage seedlings do not establish.  So, the risk depends on  rainfall and soil temperatures</p>
<p>from here on.  If conditions turn normal or hotter and dryer than  normal, the risk of late planted forage seeding failures increases.  If  late May and early June conditions remain cooler and wetter than normal,  then later-than-desired spring forage seedings may survive very well.<br />
Planting later than desired, adds to vulnerability to  erosion and weed competition.  Keep</p>
<p>cereal companion crop planting rates to half of a full seeding rate  or less, and mow or clip new</p>
<p>seedings several times during the early seedling development months  to allow sunlight to reach small developing legume and grass seedlings.   Also scout for and manage potato leafhoppers in new alfalfa seedings.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>:}</p>
<p>More tomorrow&#8230;</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/global-warming/global-warmings-impact-on-illinois-slightly-warmer-wetter-springs/">Global Warming&#8217;s Impact On Illinois &#8211; Slightly warmer wetter Springs,</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/global-warming/global-warmings-impact-on-illinois-slightly-warmer-wetter-springs/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Marc Morano &#8211; There is a name that few people will recognize</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/burning-behavior/marc-morano-there-is-a-name-that-few-people-will-recognize/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/burning-behavior/marc-morano-there-is-a-name-that-few-people-will-recognize/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2010 19:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[big coal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big oil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big whoop dee do]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burning behavior]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Copenhagen Accord]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[dying planet]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy Tough Love Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evil polluters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[factory farming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fossil fuels and the United States' Future]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fraud]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[garbage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[global warming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gone pecan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[industry apologists]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lies told by energy companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[masters of the universe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[old tired advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[playing hooky]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pollution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[schemes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self inflicted wounds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[smoke]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Speculators]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stupid old men]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[vampires]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[war]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water pollution]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=1219</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I have been posting for the last 8 or 9 days about the article below and the related book Climate Killers. Please read them so you will know who the enemy is and what to do about it. http://www.rollingstone.com/politics/story/31633532/as_the_world_burns/ :}  &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/burning-behavior/marc-morano-there-is-a-name-that-few-people-will-recognize/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burning-behavior/marc-morano-there-is-a-name-that-few-people-will-recognize/">Marc Morano &#8211; There is a name that few people will recognize</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I have been posting for the last 8 or 9 days about the article below and the related book Climate Killers. Please read them so you will know who the enemy is and what to do about it.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.rollingstone.com/politics/story/31633532/as_the_world_burns/">http://www.rollingstone.com/politics/story/31633532/as_the_world_burns/</a></p>
<p>:} </p>
<p>He is the master of the bad word. He sits around and thinks up phrases like Nature Nazis, Envirowussies, and the &#8220;fear promoting business&#8221;. He hides behind the skirts of his right wing masters. You never see him in public and if only he had a last name like Drudge&#8230;.but he doesn&#8217;t&#8230;he sounds like a quarterback and looks like a pug.</p>
<table valign="middle" border="0" width="340" cellPadding="2" cellSpacing="0">
<tr>
<td vAlign="top"><a target="_blank" href="http://www.rollingstone.com/politics/story/31633524/the_climate_killers/" rel="noopener"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" border="0" width="78" src="http://i.realone.com/assets/rn/img/8/6/6/5/31645668-31645669-lthumbnail.jpg" height="78" /></a></td>
<td height="23" vAlign="top">Meet the 17 polluters and deniers who are derailing efforts to curb global warming in Tim Dickinson&#8217;s<a href="http://www.rollingstone.com/politics/story/31633524/the_climate_killers/"><font color="#ba1319"> &#8220;The Climate Killers.&#8221;</font></a></td>
</tr>
</table>
<p><a href="http://www.rollingstone.com/politics/story/31633524/the_climate_killers/6">http://www.rollingstone.com/politics/story/31633524/the_climate_killers/6</a> </p>
<p><font style="font-size: 16px; color: #bb1111; font-family: Georgia">The Drudge of Denial</font><br />
<font style="font-size: 13px; font-family: Georgia">Marc Morano</font><br />
<font style="font-size: 11px; font-style: italic; font-family: Georgia">Founder, Climate Depot</font></p>
<p>Morano, who worked for Sen. James &#8220;Global Warming is a Hoax&#8221; Inhofe, left Congress last year to set up shop as the Matt Drudge of climate denial. Today he runs Climate Depot, a website whose sponsor is funded by oil heir Richard Mellon Scaife. A private version of a congressional blog that Morano ran for Inhofe, the site serves as a clearinghouse for climate kooks. &#8220;He&#8217;s a central cell of the climate-denial machine,&#8221; says Kert Davies, research director for Greenpeace. &#8220;He&#8217;s been very effective in delaying action on this crisis.&#8221;</p>
<p>Morano says climate scientists are in the &#8220;fear-promoting business&#8221; and accuses them of waging a &#8220;war on modern civilization.&#8221; But it&#8217;s Morano who trafficks in wild claims, routinely distorting the work of climate scholars and charging that &#8220;proponents of man-made global warming have been funded to the tune of $50 <em>billion</em>.&#8221; A former producer for Rush Limbaugh, Morano gained fame as one of the first to trumpet Swift-boat lies about John Kerry&#8217;s military record. Andrew Watson, a British climate professor who recently debated Morano on the BBC, said it best in a whispered aside at the end of the show: &#8220;What an asshole.&#8221;</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Should be Dan Morono, don&#8217;t you think? </p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burning-behavior/marc-morano-there-is-a-name-that-few-people-will-recognize/">Marc Morano &#8211; There is a name that few people will recognize</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/burning-behavior/marc-morano-there-is-a-name-that-few-people-will-recognize/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
