<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Sites Requesting Links Archives - Community Energy Systems</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/blog/sites-requesting-links/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/category/blog/sites-requesting-links/</link>
	<description>Censys.org</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 17:35:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Links Here!! Links Here!! – I get asked all the time to post links</title>
		<link>/blog/sites-requesting-links/links-here-links-here-i-get-asked-all-the-time-to-post-links-3/</link>
					<comments>/blog/sites-requesting-links/links-here-links-here-i-get-asked-all-the-time-to-post-links-3/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 17:01:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Energy Tough Love Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sites Requesting Links]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7506</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Over the years I have gotten 100s of requests to post links with other Blogs and Internet Sites that are related to the things that I post about; Sometimes tangentially. Sometimes very tangentially. Below I am going to try to &#8230; <a href="/blog/sites-requesting-links/links-here-links-here-i-get-asked-all-the-time-to-post-links-3/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/blog/sites-requesting-links/links-here-links-here-i-get-asked-all-the-time-to-post-links-3/">Links Here!! Links Here!! – I get asked all the time to post links</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over the years I have gotten 100s of requests to post links with other Blogs and Internet Sites that are related to the things that I post about; Sometimes tangentially. Sometimes very tangentially. Below I am going to try to post some of those with the text of the request where applicable or sometimes just the link.</p>
<p>I am only one guy by the way. That is it, Community Energy Systems and Energy Tough Love is just one guy with 900 bucks in the bank….so there is no way I can track down each post of mine and put the link on the page. Did I mention I was 63 years old. I would be dead by the time i did 10 or 20 post. Is some of this sarcastic? Well yah. But I never mean it spitefully. Please laugh with me not at me. Consider this:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<blockquote><p>Good day,</p>
<p>I emailed you a few months ago and I apologise if you have already replied to this email already. I am the owner of an addiction helpline called Rehab 4 Addiction. My helpline assists those who require addiction treatment.</p>
<p>I am looking to raise awareness about my helpline. I have recovered from my own addiction 22 years ago and I set up this helpline to help others. I would be grateful if you could help me by adding a &#8216;weblink&#8217; on your website to my helpline.</p>
<p>I would suggest you add this to this specific page: <a href="/?p=1052" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">www.censys.org/?p=1052</a></p>
<p>I cite this page because you already have already added another similar resource (<a href="http://www.druglibrary.org/schaffer/debate/myths/myths8.htm" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">www.druglibrary.org/schaffer/debate/myths/myths8.htm</a>) from there.</p>
<p>I am able to add a weblink to your website from my own. I could also feature you on my upcoming newsletter in return.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve included text for you to insert into this page:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong><a href="https://www.rehab4addiction.co.uk/country-wide/drug-alcohol-rehab-birmingham" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Rehab 4 Addiction</a> is a helpline for people experiencing addiction. This helpline aims to stop addiction before it becomes too late. <a href="http://www.rehab4addiction.co.uk/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">www.rehab4addiction.co.uk</a> 0800 111 4108</strong></li>
</ul>
<p>I apologise if you are not the right person in your organisation that can do this for me. If this is the case, could I please ask that you forward this on to the appropriate individual.</p>
<p>I have also attached my website logo to this email. Please add this logo along with the above description if it&#8217;s possible. I sincerely thank you for this.</p>
<p>Many thanks,</p>
<p>Oliver Clark</p>
<p>Rehab 4 Addiction</p>
<p><a href="http://www.rehab4addiction.co.uk/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">www.rehab4addiction.co.uk</a></p></blockquote>
<p>or this:</p>
<p>PO Box 10002 Melbourne City Mail Centre VIC 8001 / Reply with &#8216;Unsubscribe&#8217; in the header if you would like to unsubscribe</p>
<div class="yiv9996923101gmail_extra">
<div class="yiv9996923101gmail_quote">
<p>On Friday, May 18, 2018 at 2:51 AM, Janet Rogers &lt;janet@your-rv-lifestyle.email&gt; wrote:</p>
<blockquote class="yiv9996923101gmail_quote">
<div dir="ltr">
<div>Dear Editor,</div>
<div></div>
<div>My name is Janet and I’m a writer at Your RV Lifestyle. I was doing research on things to do in England and just finished reading your wonderful blog post: <a href="/?cat=117" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">/?cat=117</a></div>
<div></div>
<div>In that article, I noticed that you cited a solid post that I’ve read in the past: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/England" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/England</a></div>
<div></div>
<div>I just finished writing a guide that is even more detailed, updated and comprehensive on the 100 best things to do in England. It is over 10,000 words and packed with practical tips and advice. You can find it here: <a href="https://www.your-rv-lifestyle.com/things-to-do-in-england.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.your-rv-lifestyle.com/things-to-do-in-england.html</a></div>
<div></div>
<div>If you like the guide we’d be humbled if you cited us in your article. Of course, we will also share your article with our 50k newsletter subscribers and followers across our social platforms.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Either way, keep up the great work!</div>
<div></div>
<div>Warmly,<br />
Janet</div>
</div>
</blockquote>
</div>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>or this:</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Energy Tough Love Blog Editorial Team,</p>
<p>I was researching steps to winterize your home and came across your article: Do Not Put It Off – Weatherize today (/?p=3348).</p>
<p>I noticed that you mentioned easy home winterizing checklist <a href="https://www.thespruce.com/easy-home-winterizing-checklist-1824721 on the page">https://www.thespruce.com/easy-home-winterizing-checklist-1824721 on the page</a>. I also love that article.</p>
<p>In fact, it inspired us to create a wonderful post on Four Key Steps to Winterizing Your Home that might be interesting for your readers. You can see it here: <a href="https://www.thinkcrucial.com/blogs/blog/4-steps-winterizing-home">https://www.thinkcrucial.com/blogs/blog/4-steps-winterizing-home</a>.</p>
<p>Please feel free to share it if you think they&#8217;d appreciate it &#8212; I&#8217;d love it if you did!</p>
<p>Cheers,</p>
<p>Chad Rubin,<br />
Founder &#8211; Think Crucial<br />
<img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://ecp.yusercontent.com/mail?url=http%3A%2F%2Ftx.bz-mail-us1.com%2F1%2Fo%2F14c9e1d0b3d64460947893043e9ac9ae.gif&amp;t=1530464334&amp;ymreqid=c4aadb7f-4a91-f3f3-1cb9-5f00d1018a00&amp;sig=bwaUsQad6pNzpjoK0T4aTA--~C" width="0" height="0" /></p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>More when I get the time.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/blog/sites-requesting-links/links-here-links-here-i-get-asked-all-the-time-to-post-links-3/">Links Here!! Links Here!! – I get asked all the time to post links</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/blog/sites-requesting-links/links-here-links-here-i-get-asked-all-the-time-to-post-links-3/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Links Here!! Links Here!! – I get asked all the time to post links</title>
		<link>/blog/cool-sites/links-here-links-here-i-get-asked-all-the-time-to-post-links-2/</link>
					<comments>/blog/cool-sites/links-here-links-here-i-get-asked-all-the-time-to-post-links-2/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 18:08:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[children and the environment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cool sites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy Tough Love Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environmentalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sites Requesting Links]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7497</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Over the years I have gotten 100s of requests to post links with other Blogs and Internet Sites that are related to the things that I post about; Sometimes tangentially. Sometimes very tangentially. Below I am going to try to &#8230; <a href="/blog/cool-sites/links-here-links-here-i-get-asked-all-the-time-to-post-links-2/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/blog/cool-sites/links-here-links-here-i-get-asked-all-the-time-to-post-links-2/">Links Here!! Links Here!! – I get asked all the time to post links</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over the years I have gotten 100s of requests to post links with other Blogs and Internet Sites that are related to the things that I post about; Sometimes tangentially. Sometimes very tangentially. Below I am going to try to post some of those with the text of the request where applicable or sometimes just the link.</p>
<p>I am only one guy by the way. That is it, Community Energy Systems and Energy Tough Love is just one guy with 900 bucks in the bank….so there is no way I can track down each post of mine and put the link on the page. Did I mention I was 63 years old. I would be dead by the time i did 10 or 20 post. Is some of this sarcastic? Well yah. But I never mean it spitefully. Please laugh with me not at me. Consider this:</p>
<p>Sometimes people even offer to write entire articles &#8211;</p>
<div>
<div class="yiv3740630627gmail_signature">
<div dir="ltr">
<div class="yiv3740630627gmail_signature">
<div dir="ltr">
<p dir="ltr">Hi!</p>
<p dir="ltr">There are more than <a href="https://nces.ed.gov/ccd/quickfacts.asp" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">3 million teachers</a> within the U.S. public school system. While some may plan on being work-free during summer break, others might enjoy &#8211; or need &#8211; to find a short-term job during that time.</p>
<p dir="ltr">As a retired teacher, I thought it would be fun to research and write about summer side gigs for teachers. (Side note: Many of these gigs, especially those that take advantage of the growing sharing economy, can also be worked into the school-year schedule.)</p>
<p dir="ltr">Is this something that would be of interest to your readers? If so, I would love the opportunity to write a guest article at no cost to you. Please let me know, and I’ll start writing.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Thanks so much!</p>
<p dir="ltr">Joyce</p>
<p dir="ltr">Joyce Wilson</p>
<p dir="ltr"><a href="mailto:joyce@teacherspark.org" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">joyce@teacherspark.org</a></p>
<p dir="ltr">Teacherspark.org</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p align="center"><span style="font-size: xx-large;">5 Eco-Conscious Summer Jobs for School Teachers</span></p>
<p>As a teacher, you need a second job to make ends meet. But as an environmentalist, the idea of driving for Uber or running people’s errands through an on-demand app doesn’t appeal to you. You want to spend less time commuting in your car, not more. So what are the options? Here are five eco-conscious side gigs that teachers can work during the summer and year-round.</p>
<h2 class="western"><a name="_4etjtkf0wup4"></a>Walking Dogs</h2>
<p>The school year leaves you sitting inside for most of the day. When summer hits, you want to get outdoors as much as possible. Walking dogs for friends and neighbors is a great excuse to spend time outdoors, and the pay isn’t bad either. According to CostHelper.com, the <a href="http://pets.costhelper.com/dog-walker.html"><span style="color: #1155cc;"><u>typical pay</u></span></a> for a dog walker is $18 to $22 for a 30-minute walk. Because the gig comes with minimal overhead costs, most of that pay ends up in your pocket. Dog walkers can also offer pet sitting to boost their earning potential.</p>
<h2 class="western"><a name="_gc7m6o4cvlb7"></a>Building Custom Gardens</h2>
<p>Everyone wants a gorgeous edible garden in their yard, but few want to put in the work. Start a business <a href="https://www.finegardening.com/article/who-says-a-kitchen-garden-cant-be-beautiful"><span style="color: #1155cc;"><u>designing</u></span></a>, building, and maintaining custom vegetable gardens in local backyards. You’ll help your neighbors eat healthier while reducing their carbon footprint, and you’ll enjoy a paying job that hardly feels like work. The only downside? There’s not much gardening to do during the winter months. However, teachers can offer winter yard maintenance to keep money flowing through the off-season.</p>
<h2 class="western"><a name="_wg4vm1wugx8w"></a>Creating an Online Store</h2>
<p>According to the Sierra Club, <a href="https://www.sierraclub.org/sierra/2015-6-november-december/ask-mr-green/hey-mr-green-how-ecofriendly-online-shopping"><span style="color: #1155cc;"><u>online shopping</u></span></a> beats driving to the store when it comes to environmental impact. While boxes and packaging seem wasteful, one delivery truck driving from house to house spends less energy than each household making trips to the store. It’s easy to build an e-commerce website with drag-and-drop website builders, and you don’t have to create a unique product to open an online store. Many online stores earn money by dropshipping popular products like wireless headphones and phone cases from larger retailers. Offer a diversity of products or choose products with staying power so your store remains profitable for the long-term.</p>
<h2 class="western"><a name="_7sbz0mp3ppo3"></a>Flipping Second-Hand Goods</h2>
<p>Our <a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2018/mar/15/can-we-fix-it-the-repair-cafes-waging-war-on-throwaway-culture"><span style="color: #1155cc;"><u>throwaway society</u></span></a> has largely moved away from repairing broken goods, choosing instead to replace items the moment they cease to function. The result? Countless lightly used appliances, gadgets, and furniture items headed to the dump when they still have lots of life. If you’re handy and enjoy hunting for treasures, start a side business picking up broken items, repairing them, and reselling for profit. Yard sales and Craigslist are gold mines for free and cheap items in need of repair. Finance Superhero offers <a href="https://www.financesuperhero.com/best-items-to-flip-make-money/"><span style="color: #1155cc;"><u>tips</u></span></a> for getting started.</p>
<h2 class="western"><a name="_bjxmtuds2766"></a>Blogging</h2>
<p>Starting a blog is perfect for teachers who want to explore their interest in energy and environmentalism. Teachers can blog about topics they’re passionate about and <a href="https://www.bloggingbasics101.com/how-can-i-make-money-from-my-blog/"><span style="color: #1155cc;"><u>generate income</u></span></a> through ad revenue. A blog can also be a great platform for sharing information and selling lesson plans on environmentalism with other educators, who can then use the materials in their own classrooms.</p>
<p>Additionally, <a href="https://www.oberlo.com/blog/business-ideas-that-make-money"><span style="color: #1155cc;"><u>business ideas</u></span></a> such as selling workwear, selfie drones, and electronics online have a smaller environmental impact than driving a rideshare, delivering groceries, or another sharing economy mainstay. They also have minimal start-up costs, so your business doesn’t take months or years to start generating profit like some small businesses. That’s important when your priority is increasing your income, not launching a new career. However, teachers shouldn’t assume their side gig is in the black. Diligent <a href="https://www.score.org/blog/tax-and-record-keeping-tips-your-small-business"><span style="color: #1155cc;"><u>record keeping</u></span></a> is key to ensuring you’re meeting your income goals and not putting more into a gig than you’re getting out.</p>
<p>There are many ways to earn an income on top of a full-time job. But if environmentalism is important to you, you may find it difficult to find a job that aligns with your values. While these five side gigs might not change the world, they’re practical ways for eco-conscious teachers to increase their income without increasing their carbon footprint.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>More whenever.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/blog/cool-sites/links-here-links-here-i-get-asked-all-the-time-to-post-links-2/">Links Here!! Links Here!! – I get asked all the time to post links</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/blog/cool-sites/links-here-links-here-i-get-asked-all-the-time-to-post-links-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Links Here!! Links Here!! &#8211; I get asked all the time to post links</title>
		<link>/blog/burn-free-generation/links-here-links-here-i-get-asked-all-the-time-to-post-links/</link>
					<comments>/blog/burn-free-generation/links-here-links-here-i-get-asked-all-the-time-to-post-links/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 20:14:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[big whoop dee do]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burn free generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cool sites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy blogs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy Tough Love Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environmental blogs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flying high]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[funny]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gone pecan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[masters of the universe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[no nukes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self inflicted wounds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[serious artist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sites Requesting Links]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stewardship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stimulating intercourse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stretching a concept]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[web energy sources]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=7486</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Over the years I have gotten 100s of requests to post links with other Blogs and Internet Sites that are related to the things that I post about; Sometimes tangentially. Sometimes very tangentially. Below I am going to try to &#8230; <a href="/blog/burn-free-generation/links-here-links-here-i-get-asked-all-the-time-to-post-links/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/blog/burn-free-generation/links-here-links-here-i-get-asked-all-the-time-to-post-links/">Links Here!! Links Here!! &#8211; I get asked all the time to post links</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over the years I have gotten 100s of requests to post links with other Blogs and Internet Sites that are related to the things that I post about; Sometimes tangentially. Sometimes very tangentially. Below I am going to try to post some of those with the text of the request where applicable or sometimes just the link.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>I am only one guy by the way. That is it, Community Energy Systems and Energy Tough Love is just one guy with 900 bucks in the bank&#8230;.so there is no way I can track down each post of mine and put the link on the page. Did I mention I was 63 years old. I would be dead by the time i did 10 or 20 post. Is some of this sarcastic? Well yah. But I never mean it spitefully. Please laugh with me not at me. Consider this:</p>
<p>Hello ,</p>
<p>My name is James Giraldo and I’m the Communications Manager on SaveOnEnergy.com®.</p>
<p>I wanted to point out this page: <a href="/?m=200810" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">censys.org</a> which links to a broken kids energy page on <a href="http://www.miamisci.org/af/sln/frankenstein/index.html" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">miamisci.org</a></p>
<p>Our team has created a <a href="https://www.saveonenergy.com/kids-learning-center/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">Kids Learning Center</a> which is filled with free resources similar to the ones previously found on that page. Please take a look, and if you find any of the content useful consider linking to it on your page, or perhaps use it to replace the broken link so your visitors don&#8217;t end up on that broken page.</p>
<p>Here is a hyperlink to our kids learning center:<br />
<a href="https://www.saveonenergy.com/kids-learning-center/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.saveonenergy.com/kids-learning-center/</a></p>
<p>Thank you in advance for your help and attention. Please let me know if you have questions or concerns that I can assist with.</p>
<p>James G.<br />
Communications Director<br />
6860 North Dallas Parkway, Suite 228 | Plano, TX 75024<br />
<a href="mailto:James@admin.saveonenergy.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">James@admin.saveonenergy.com</a><br />
www.saveonenergy.com</p>
<p>Or this:</p>
<p><span style="font-size: small;">Hi censys.org,</span></p>
<p>I was reading a page on your site and I noticed you had link pointing to a page that is broken (no longer valid) which I thought you might want to fix.</p>
<p>The broken link can be found at the middle of the page.  The page that has the broken link is:</p>
<p><a href="/index.php?s=energy&amp;paged=27" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">/index.php?s=energy&amp;paged=27</a></p>
<p>Attached is a screenshot with a circle around the broken link to make it easier to find.</p>
<p>Having broken links on your site isn’t good for your readers and also Google lowers your ranking score if you have them.  It would be awesome if you could replace the broken link with one of our related posts instead, if not, that is okay.</p>
<p><span class="u_b en_0 C4_Z2aVTcY" data-test-id="message-from"><span class="D_F rtlI_rtlI_dz_sSg "><span class="u_N C_Z1VRpVF"><a href="http:www.businesselectric.com">http:www.businesselectric.com</a></span></span></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: small;"><br />
If you would replace it with our link we would share the post with 14,000+ followers in our niche.  We are up for collaborating more with you or negotiating more about it.</span></p>
<p>Thanks for reading my email and have a nice day ?</p>
<p>Regards,<br />
Oliver</p>
<p>Or this:</p>
<div>We recently put together an in-depth resource (~10K words) about work boots, which received over 1000 social shares. It&#8217;s quite different to the other articles you see on the web about this topic.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Here is it: <a href="https://www.thebabbleout.com/shoes/best-work-boots/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.thebabbleout.com/shoes/best-work-boots/</a></div>
<div></div>
<div><strong>Zoey Miller</strong><br />
<em>&#8220;Share your knowledge. It is a way to achieve immortality.&#8221; &#8211; Dalai Lama</em></div>
<div>Email: <a href="mailto:zoey@thebabbleout.com" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">zoey@thebabbleout.com</a></div>
<div>Web: <a href="https://www.thebabbleout.com/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.thebabbleout.com/</a></div>
<div>/</div>
<div></div>
<div>Or this:</div>
<div>/</div>
<div>I just finished writing a guide that is even more detailed, updated and comprehensive on how to choose an air conditioner, according to science. It is more than 7,000 words and is packed with practical tips. You can find it here: <a href="https://www.jenreviews.com/air-conditioner/" target="_blank" rel="nofollow noopener">https://www.jenreviews.com/air-conditioner/</a></div>
<div></div>
<div>Either way, keep up the great work!</div>
<div></div>
<div>Warmly,<br />
Jean</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>More when I get the chance.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/blog/burn-free-generation/links-here-links-here-i-get-asked-all-the-time-to-post-links/">Links Here!! Links Here!! &#8211; I get asked all the time to post links</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/blog/burn-free-generation/links-here-links-here-i-get-asked-all-the-time-to-post-links/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
