<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>cool sites Archives - Community Energy Systems</title>
	<atom:link href="/censys/category/blog/cool-sites/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/censys/category/blog/cool-sites/</link>
	<description>Censys.org</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 19:01:26 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Upheavals Caused By Clean Energy &#8211; All the tree huggers make it look like pixie dust</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/upheavals-caused-by-clean-energy-all-the-tree-huggers-make-it-look-like-pixie-dust/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/upheavals-caused-by-clean-energy-all-the-tree-huggers-make-it-look-like-pixie-dust/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 20:46:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[batteries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burn free generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cool sites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[penetrating ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=8551</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>By &#8220;pixie dust&#8221; I mean that a lot of environmentalists make it sound like there will be no chaos from fossil fuel use to renewal energy systems and that is not true. Dislodging fossil fuel will result in job loses, &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/upheavals-caused-by-clean-energy-all-the-tree-huggers-make-it-look-like-pixie-dust/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/upheavals-caused-by-clean-energy-all-the-tree-huggers-make-it-look-like-pixie-dust/">Upheavals Caused By Clean Energy &#8211; All the tree huggers make it look like pixie dust</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>By &#8220;pixie dust&#8221; I mean that a lot of environmentalists make it sound like there will be no chaos from fossil fuel use to renewal energy systems and that is not true. Dislodging fossil fuel will result in job loses, factories closing and possibly the lack of transportation (for example) for chunks of the population. Especially those not preparing for it now. Lives will be lost. This is the fault of capitalism but it is what we have. Also the reverse is true, as demand for clean energy grows, whole resources will be created from scratch (rare earths for instance). The earth will be scarred, employment will be created with much wrenching and tearing. Lives will be lost. Capitalism will prevail. Just think of what happened when oil and gas took over and from the Luddites. This is a Really Long article about all of that and it only scratches the surface.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/world/2021-11-30/geopolitics-energy-green-upheaval?utm_source=pocket-newtab">https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/world/2021-11-30/geopolitics-energy-green-upheaval?utm_source=pocket-newtab</a></p>
<div class="row article-header--metadata-title">
<div class="col-lg-10 offset-lg-0 col-12 col-md-8 offset-md-2">
<div class="row">
<div class="col-lg-11 article-header--metadata-content">
<h1 class="f-serif ls-0 article-title pt-2" data-drupal-page-title="">Green Upheaval</h1>
<h2 class="f-serif ls-0 article-subtitle ">The New Geopolitics of Energy</h2>
<div class="row no-gutters ls-0 article-byline position-relative">
<h3 class="f-sans m-0 col-12 col-sm-auto mr-sm-4">By <span class="position-relative d-inline-block"><a class="article-byline-author b4-l" href="https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/world/2021-11-30/geopolitics-energy-green-upheaval?utm_source=pocket-newtab#author-info">Jason Bordoff and Meghan L. O’Sullivan</a></span></h3>
<p><span class="article-header--metadata-date align-self-center col-6 col-sm-auto"><a href="https://www.foreignaffairs.com/issues/2022/101/1">January/February 2022</a></span></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>It is not hard to understand why people dream of a future defined by clean energy. As greenhouse gas emissions continue to grow and as extreme weather events become more frequent and harmful, the current efforts to move beyond fossil fuels appear woefully inadequate. Adding to the frustration, the geopolitics of oil and gas are alive and well—and as fraught as ever. Europe is in the throes of a full-fledged energy crisis, with staggering electricity prices forcing businesses across the continent to shutter and energy firms to declare bankruptcy, positioning Russian President Vladimir Putin to take advantage of his neighbors’ struggles by leveraging his country’s natural gas reserves. In September, blackouts reportedly led Chinese Vice Premier Han Zheng to instruct his country’s state-owned energy companies to secure supplies for winter at any cost. And as oil prices surge above $80 per barrel, the United States and other energy-hungry countries are pleading with major producers, including Saudi Arabia, to ramp up their output, giving Riyadh more clout in a newly tense relationship and suggesting the limits of Washington’s energy “independence.”</p>
<p>Proponents of clean energy hope (and sometimes promise) that in addition to mitigating climate change, the energy transition will help make tensions over energy resources a thing of the past. It is true that clean energy will transform geopolitics—just not necessarily in the ways many of its champions expect. The transition will reconfigure many elements of international politics that have shaped the global system since at least World War II, significantly affecting the sources of national power, the process of globalization, relations among the great powers, and the ongoing economic convergence of developed countries and developing ones. The process will be messy at best. And far from fostering comity and cooperation, it will likely produce new forms of competition and confrontation long before a new, more copacetic geopolitics takes shape.</p>
<p>Talk of a smooth transition to clean energy is fanciful: there is no way that the world can avoid major upheavals as it remakes the entire energy system, which is the lifeblood of the global economy and underpins the geopolitical order. Moreover, the conventional wisdom about who will gain and who will lose is frequently off base.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and reeeeaaad. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/upheavals-caused-by-clean-energy-all-the-tree-huggers-make-it-look-like-pixie-dust/">Upheavals Caused By Clean Energy &#8211; All the tree huggers make it look like pixie dust</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/upheavals-caused-by-clean-energy-all-the-tree-huggers-make-it-look-like-pixie-dust/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>When There Is Too Much Electricity &#8211; Yah gotta let it out baby</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/green-economy/when-there-is-too-much-electricity-yah-gotta-let-it-out-baby/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/green-economy/when-there-is-too-much-electricity-yah-gotta-let-it-out-baby/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 19:12:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[burn free generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cool sites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[penetrating ideas]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=8489</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Any Electrical Generation System can generate too much energy in a system where output is unknown. To put it another way where consumption is unknown. And this is just my opinion but I am betting any system would rather have &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/green-economy/when-there-is-too-much-electricity-yah-gotta-let-it-out-baby/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/green-economy/when-there-is-too-much-electricity-yah-gotta-let-it-out-baby/">When There Is Too Much Electricity &#8211; Yah gotta let it out baby</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Any Electrical Generation System can generate too much energy in a system where output is unknown. To put it another way where consumption is unknown. And this is just my opinion but I am betting any system would rather have too much than too little product or produce to sell. If the system is really large a little bit too much is way better then a little bit less. But what to do with the excess?  By the way. contrary to this article, you can turn energy generation off, so long as you know when you have to turn it back on.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.sierraclub.org/sierra/what-do-we-do-too-much-renewable-energy">https://www.sierraclub.org/sierra/what-do-we-do-too-much-renewable-energy</a></p>
<h2>What Do We Do With Too Much Renewable Energy?</h2>
<p>It&#8217;s not easy to turn off a wind turbine, but the electricity has to go somewhere</p>
<p>By <a href="https://www.sierraclub.org/sierra/authors/natasha-khullar-relph">Natasha Khullar Relph</a> | <span class="pubdate">Aug 19 2020</span></p>
<p>We know that green energy is good, but can there be too much of a good thing?</p>
<p>For instance, with unusually low demand during the COVID-19 lockdown, the United Kingdom’s power consumption fell by nearly 20 percent this summer. That caused a surge in unused green energy. In May, the National Grid asked for emergency powers to switch off solar and wind farms and warned of blackouts and a “significant risk of disruption to security of supply.”</p>
<p>Britain is certainly not alone. As the transition to renewable energy gathers pace, early adopter regions like Germany, Denmark, and California are finding that, counterintuitively, too much green power poses problems for their energy supply. Electricity, when generated, must be used instantaneously, and therefore the amount of generation and the amount of demand must be balanced perfectly at all times. This can cause surges in the grid unless there are means of storing or diverting this excess.</p>
<p>Finding that perfect balance is complicated at the best of times, says Cisco DeVries, an energy expert and the CEO of OhmConnect as well as a former aide to the secretary of energy during the Clinton administration. It’s far worse when you throw in sudden surprises such as a global pandemic. Suddenly, people are consuming more power at home, but factories are standing empty. “We’re changing when and where we’re using [energy], and we’re doing it in a way that’s never been done before,” he says. Add the challenges of disconnecting solar power plants and wind farms to changing use patterns, he notes, and you’ve “exponentially complicated the balancing of supply and demand.”</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/green-economy/when-there-is-too-much-electricity-yah-gotta-let-it-out-baby/">When There Is Too Much Electricity &#8211; Yah gotta let it out baby</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/green-economy/when-there-is-too-much-electricity-yah-gotta-let-it-out-baby/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>We Can Make A Change &#8211; If we all pull together we can make big change</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/penetrating-ideas/we-can-make-a-change-if-we-all-pull-together-we-can-make-big-change/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/penetrating-ideas/we-can-make-a-change-if-we-all-pull-together-we-can-make-big-change/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 20:07:17 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[burning reduction methods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children and the environment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cool sites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy conservation measures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environmentalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[penetrating ideas]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=8117</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Periodically I try to be up beat. With the Pandemic and all the doom coming out of the environmental community I thought I would say, &#8220;We can do things together&#8221;! The place to start is small. Ride your bike. Recycle &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/penetrating-ideas/we-can-make-a-change-if-we-all-pull-together-we-can-make-big-change/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/penetrating-ideas/we-can-make-a-change-if-we-all-pull-together-we-can-make-big-change/">We Can Make A Change &#8211; If we all pull together we can make big change</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Periodically I try to be up beat. With the Pandemic and all the doom coming out of the environmental community I thought I would say, &#8220;We can do things together&#8221;! The place to start is small. Ride your bike. Recycle and reduce your garbage. Compost. Walk places when you can. Take the steps not the elevator. I do all of those things and everyday I try to think of more things I can do. Anyway, here are some thoughts on the things we can achieve. Stay safe out there.</p>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="Rm6kbf7CwU"><p><a href="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/climate-change-actions-reduce-carbon-footprint">What lifestyle changes will shrink your carbon footprint the most?</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe title="&#8220;What lifestyle changes will shrink your carbon footprint the most?&#8221; &#8212; Science News" class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" style="position: absolute; clip: rect(1px, 1px, 1px, 1px);" src="https://www.sciencenews.org/article/climate-change-actions-reduce-carbon-footprint/embed#?secret=Rm6kbf7CwU" data-secret="Rm6kbf7CwU" width="584" height="329" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
<div class="byline__wrapper___4FOTC">
<div class="byline-inner">
<p class="byline__authors___2KZu0">By <span class="byline author vcard"><a class="byline-link url fn n" href="https://www.sciencenews.org/author/christie-aschwanden">Christie Aschwanden</a></span></p>
<p class="byline__published___3GjAo"><time class="date entry-date byline__published___3GjAo" datetime="2020-05-14T06:00:00-04:00">May 14, 2020 at 6:00 am</time></p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="single__body___XFYC7">
<div class="content">
<div class="rich-text single__rich-text___BlzVF" data-component="video-embed">
<p class="has-drop-cap">Three years ago, Kim Cobb was feeling “completely overwhelmed” by the problem of climate change. Cobb spends her days studying climate change as director of the Global Change Program at Georgia Tech in Atlanta, but she felt paralyzed over how to be part of the solution in her personal life. The barriers felt immense.</p>
<p>She decided to start small. On January 1, 2017, she made a personal climate resolution: She would walk her kids to school and bicycle to work two days a week. That change didn’t represent a lot in terms of carbon emissions, she says, “but it was a huge lesson in daily engagement.”</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>In the beginning, her modest goal seemed daunting, but she quickly discovered that the two simple activities nourished her physical and mental well-being. She wanted to do them every day. “It’s no longer for the carbon — it’s for the fact that I genuinely love riding my bike and walking my kids to school,” she says. And that made her wonder: What other steps was she thinking of as sacrifices that might actually enrich her life?</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/penetrating-ideas/we-can-make-a-change-if-we-all-pull-together-we-can-make-big-change/">We Can Make A Change &#8211; If we all pull together we can make big change</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/penetrating-ideas/we-can-make-a-change-if-we-all-pull-together-we-can-make-big-change/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Americans Would Not Know Good Design If It Bit Them ON The Ass</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/green-economy/americans-would-not-know-good-design-if-it-bit-them-on-the-ass/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/green-economy/americans-would-not-know-good-design-if-it-bit-them-on-the-ass/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 15:50:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burn free generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cool sites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy conservation measures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environmentalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gaia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Other countries advances]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[serious artist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stewardship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water efficiency]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=8068</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>These people have been conserving massive amounts of energy for years. Americans, Russians and Chinese, NOt So MucH. You know &#8211; energy exuberance and all that poppycock. https://www.cnbc.com/2020/03/12/a-design-concept-is-transforming-the-energy-efficiency-of-buildings.html?utm_source=digg IOT: Powering the digital economy How a decades-old design concept is transforming &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/green-economy/americans-would-not-know-good-design-if-it-bit-them-on-the-ass/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/green-economy/americans-would-not-know-good-design-if-it-bit-them-on-the-ass/">Americans Would Not Know Good Design If It Bit Them ON The Ass</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>These people have been conserving massive amounts of energy for years. Americans, Russians and Chinese, NOt So MucH. You know &#8211; energy exuberance and all that poppycock.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/03/12/a-design-concept-is-transforming-the-energy-efficiency-of-buildings.html?utm_source=digg">https://www.cnbc.com/2020/03/12/a-design-concept-is-transforming-the-energy-efficiency-of-buildings.html?utm_source=digg</a></p>
<div class="ArticleHeader-wrapperHeroNoImage ArticleHeader-wrapperHero ArticleHeader-wrapper ArticleHeader-wrapperNoImage"><a class="ArticleHeader-eyebrow" href="https://www.cnbc.com/iot/">IOT: Powering the digital economy</a></div>
<div></div>
<div class="ArticleHeader-wrapperHeroNoImage ArticleHeader-wrapperHero ArticleHeader-wrapper ArticleHeader-wrapperNoImage">
<div>
<h1 class="ArticleHeader-headline">How a decades-old design concept is transforming the energy efficiency of buildings</h1>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
</div>
<div class="ArticleHeader-time"><time data-testid="published-timestamp">Published Thu, Mar 12 20209:33 AM EDT</time></div>
<div></div>
</div>
<div class="ArticleHeader-authorAndShareInline">
<div class="ArticleHeader-authorContainer">
<div class="ArticleHeader-author">
<div class="Author-author">
<div class="Author-authorInfo">
<div class="Author-authorNameAndSocial"><a class="Author-authorName" href="https://www.cnbc.com/anmar-frangoul-profile--cnbc/">Anmar Frangoul</a></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div id="SpecialReportArticle-KeyPoints-5" class="RenderKeyPoints-keyPoints">
<div class="RenderKeyPoints-wrapper">
<div class="RenderKeyPoints-header">Key Points</div>
<div class="RenderKeyPoints-list">
<div>
<div class="group">
<ul>
<li>The buildings we live and work in have to meet a wide range of needs.</li>
<li>Could a shift in the way they are designed make them more energy efficient?</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div id="SpecialReportArticle-ArticleBody-6" class="ArticleBody-articleBody" data-module="ArticleBody">
<div id="ArticleBody-InlineImage-106438318" class="InlineImage-imageEmbed hasBkg">
<div class="InlineImage-wrapper">
<div class="InlineImage-imagePlaceholder">
<div>
<div class="InlineImage-imageContainer" tabindex="-1" role="button"><picture><source srcset="https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/106438318-1584002256432goldsmithstreet_5593timcrocker.jpg?v=1584002694&amp;w=740&amp;h=416" media="(min-width: 1340px)" /><source srcset="https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/106438318-1584002256432goldsmithstreet_5593timcrocker.jpg?v=1584002694&amp;w=630&amp;h=354" media="(min-width: 1020px)" /><source srcset="https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/106438318-1584002256432goldsmithstreet_5593timcrocker.jpg?v=1584002694&amp;w=900&amp;h=506" media="(min-width: 760px)" /><img decoding="async" class="" src="https://image.cnbcfm.com/api/v1/image/106438318-1584002256432goldsmithstreet_5593timcrocker.jpg?v=1584002694&amp;w=678&amp;h=381" alt="H/O - Goldsmith Street Norwich" /></picture></div>
</div>
</div>
<div>
<div class="InlineImage-imageEmbedCaption">Goldsmith Street, in the English city of Norwich, won the RIBA Stirling Prize for 2019.</div>
<div class="InlineImage-imageEmbedCredit">Tim Crocker</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="group">
<p>The buildings we live and work in have to meet a wide range of needs, whether it’s an office block in the middle of the city or a small house in the suburbs.</p>
<p>Think of a building’s temperature: It can be regulated by radiators, fans and air conditioning systems, while basic actions such as opening and closing a window or door can also be effective. Today, smart technology allows many of these appliances to be controlled remotely using smartphones.</p>
</div>
</div>
<p>You only need to look at your monthly utility bill to know that living in a building — be it large or small — costs money.</p>
<p>The impact of buildings on the environment is also a concern. According to the IEA, final energy use in buildings hit approximately 3,060 million tons of oil equivalent (Mtoe) in 2018, up from 2,820 Mtoe in 2010.</p>
<p>Fossil fuels’ share in buildings’ energy use was at 36% in 2018, the IEA says, a small drop compared to 38% in 2010.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read. Its all you&#8217;ve got to do, right? More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/green-economy/americans-would-not-know-good-design-if-it-bit-them-on-the-ass/">Americans Would Not Know Good Design If It Bit Them ON The Ass</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/green-economy/americans-would-not-know-good-design-if-it-bit-them-on-the-ass/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rivian Could Be The Car Marker Of The Future &#8211; or a Billion Dollar bust</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/rivian-could-be-the-car-marker-of-the-future-or-a-billion-dollar-bust/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/rivian-could-be-the-car-marker-of-the-future-or-a-billion-dollar-bust/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 19:58:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[advanced energy structures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[batteries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big whoop dee do]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burn free generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cool sites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electricity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environmentalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[masters of the universe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[penetrating ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transportation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=7973</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>It is so hard to imagine that Bloomington/Normal may be the next Detroit. All that glamor. All those people. Well all those robots and some new people. All the international stylin.  All that money which means banks. It could also &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/rivian-could-be-the-car-marker-of-the-future-or-a-billion-dollar-bust/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/rivian-could-be-the-car-marker-of-the-future-or-a-billion-dollar-bust/">Rivian Could Be The Car Marker Of The Future &#8211; or a Billion Dollar bust</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>It is so hard to imagine that Bloomington/Normal may be the next Detroit. All that glamor. All those people. Well all those robots and some new people. All the international stylin.  All that money which means banks. It could also be well&#8230; a mirage. Still, Amazon is ordering vehicles already. Ford is the leader in self driving cars. This could be amazing. I can hold my breath for 2 or 3 years I guess.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2019/02/15/rivian-announces-700-million-investment-round-led-by-amazon.html">https://www.cnbc.com/2019/02/15/rivian-announces-700-million-investment-round-led-by-amazon.html</a></p>
<div class="ArticleHeader-wrapperHeroNoImage ArticleHeader-wrapperHero ArticleHeader-wrapper ArticleHeader-wrapperNoImage"><a class="ArticleHeader-eyebrow" tabindex="" title="" role="" href="https://www.cnbc.com/autos/" target="" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-type="" aria-label="">Autos</a></p>
<h1 class="ArticleHeader-headline">Electric truck start-up Rivian announces $700 million investment round led by Amazon</h1>
<div class="ArticleHeader-time"><time data-testid="published-timestamp">Published Fri, Feb 15 20199:20 AM EST</time><time data-testid="lastpublished-timestamp">Updated Fri, Feb 15 20191:34 PM EST</time></div>
</div>
<div class="ArticleHeader-authorAndShareInline">
<div class="ArticleHeader-authorContainer">
<div class="ArticleHeader-author">
<div class="Author-author">
<div class="Author-authorInfo">
<div class="Author-authorPortrait"></div>
<div class="Author-authorNameAndSocial"><a class="Author-authorName" tabindex="" title="" role="" href="https://www.cnbc.com/robert-ferris/" target="" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-type="" aria-label="">Robert Ferris</a><a class="Author-authorTwitter" tabindex="" title="" role="" href="https://twitter.com/RobertoFerris" target="" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-type="" aria-label="">@RobertoFerris</a></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="ArticleHeader-author">
<div class="Author-author">
<div class="Author-authorInfo">
<div class="Author-authorNameAndSocial"><a class="Author-authorName" tabindex="" title="" role="" href="https://www.cnbc.com/paul-a-eisenstein/" target="" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-type="" aria-label="">Paul A. Eisenstein</a><a class="Author-authorTwitter" tabindex="" title="" role="" href="https://twitter.com/DetroitBureau" target="" rel="noopener noreferrer" data-type="" aria-label="">@DetroitBureau</a></div>
<div></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="RenderKeyPoints-list">
<div>
<div class="group">
<ul>
<li>Amazon led a $700 million round of funding in Rivian, a Michigan-based electric vehicle startup.</li>
<li>Rivian plans to launch an electric pickup and electric SUV in the U.S. in 2020.</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p><a href="https://media.ford.com/content/fordmedia/fna/us/en/news/2019/04/24/rivian-500-million-investment-ford.html">https://media.ford.com/content/fordmedia/fna/us/en/news/2019/04/24/rivian-500-million-investment-ford.html</a></p>
<h1 class="page-header">Rivian Announces $500 Million Investment from Ford; Partnership to Deliver All-New Ford Battery Electric Vehicle</h1>
<div class="share-box with-date">
<div class="title"><a href="https://media.ford.com/content/fordmedia/fna/us/en/news/2019/04/24/rivian-500-million-investment-ford.html#">Apr 24, 2019 | DEARBORN, Mich</a></div>
</div>
<ul>
<li>Ford and Rivian form strategic partnership through $500 million minority investment</li>
<li>Ford to build all-new battery electric vehicle using Rivian’s flexible skateboard platform</li>
<li>The investment is subject to customary regulatory approval; Ford’s Joe Hinrichs to join Rivian’s board of directors</li>
</ul>
<p><a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/rivian-announces-350-million-investment-from-cox-automotive-300915155.html">https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/rivian-announces-350-million-investment-from-cox-automotive-300915155.html</a></p>
<div class="row">
<div class="col-sm-10 col-sm-offset-1 col-xs-12 ">
<h1>Rivian Announces $350 Million Investment from Cox Automotive</h1>
</div>
</div>
<div class="row">
<div class="col-sm-10 col-sm-offset-1">
<hr />
</div>
</div>
<div class="row">
<div class="col-lg-6 col-lg-offset-1 col-sm-5 col-sm-offset-1">
<p class="meta">News provided by</p>
<p><a href="https://www.prnewswire.com/news/rivian"> <strong>Rivian <i class="btb bt-long-arrow-right"></i> </strong> </a></p>
<p class="mb-no">Sep 10, 2019, 09:41 ET</p>
</div>
</div>
<p><span class="xn-location">PLYMOUTH, Mich.</span>, Sept. 10, 2019 /PRNewswire/ &#8212; Rivian today announced an equity investment of <span class="xn-money">$350 million</span> from global automotive services company Cox Automotive. In addition to the investment, the companies will explore partnership opportunities in service operations, logistics, and digital retailing.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/rivian-could-be-the-car-marker-of-the-future-or-a-billion-dollar-bust/">Rivian Could Be The Car Marker Of The Future &#8211; or a Billion Dollar bust</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/rivian-could-be-the-car-marker-of-the-future-or-a-billion-dollar-bust/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Things I Could Have Posted Today &#8211; Trump denies California&#8217;s ability to set fuel standards or Iran&#8217;s air strikes on the Saudi oil fields but</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/burning-reduction-methods/the-things-i-could-have-posted-today-trump-denies-californias-ability-to-set-fuel-standards-or-irans-strike-on-the-saudi-oil-fields-but/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/burning-reduction-methods/the-things-i-could-have-posted-today-trump-denies-californias-ability-to-set-fuel-standards-or-irans-strike-on-the-saudi-oil-fields-but/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 20:24:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big coal]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big oil]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big whoop dee do]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burning reduction methods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cool sites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fossil fuels and the United States' Future]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gone pecan]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lies told by energy companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[outdoors]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[scarcity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self inflicted wounds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stewardship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waste]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wild animals]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=7954</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I chose to post about something more radical. INFRASTRUCTURE. The idea behind &#8220;keep it in the ground&#8221; is so subversive. That&#8217;s what the XL Pipeline was all about and why the itt was so hotly contested. If you can&#8217;t bring &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/burning-reduction-methods/the-things-i-could-have-posted-today-trump-denies-californias-ability-to-set-fuel-standards-or-irans-strike-on-the-saudi-oil-fields-but/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burning-reduction-methods/the-things-i-could-have-posted-today-trump-denies-californias-ability-to-set-fuel-standards-or-irans-strike-on-the-saudi-oil-fields-but/">The Things I Could Have Posted Today &#8211; Trump denies California&#8217;s ability to set fuel standards or Iran&#8217;s air strikes on the Saudi oil fields but</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I chose to post about something more radical. INFRASTRUCTURE. The idea behind &#8220;keep it in the ground&#8221; is so subversive. That&#8217;s what the XL Pipeline was all about and why the itt was so hotly contested. If you can&#8217;t bring fossil fuels to the market; What good are they? Well, New York tried to do it through legislation, and things got hot right away.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.globalenergyinstitute.org/epa-proposes-reject-new-yorks-keep-it-ground-scheme">https://www.globalenergyinstitute.org/epa-proposes-reject-new-yorks-keep-it-ground-scheme</a></p>
<div class="c-page-title__wrap">
<div class="o-grid">
<div class="sm-12 ">
<div class="c-page-title__date">May 28, 2019</div>
<h1 class="c-page-title">EPA Proposes to Reject New York’s “Keep it in the Ground” Scheme</h1>
<div class="c-page-title__author">Heath Knakmuhs</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="">
<div>
<article class="node node--type-blog node--promoted node--sticky node--view-mode-full node--type-blog-type-blog clearfix" role="article">
<div class="o-grid o-band--bottom"></div>
</article>
</div>
</div>
<div class="sm-12 lg-8">
<div class="field field--name-body field--type-text-with-summary field--label-hidden field__item">
<p>Last September, I <a href="https://www.globalenergyinstitute.org/start-spreading-news-new-york-126">wrote</a> about one of the boldest efforts yet by New York to halt energy infrastructure in its tracks.  This effort utilized a little-known provision of the Clean Air Act – the “good neighbor” provision at Section 126(b) – to argue that hundreds of energy-related and manufacturing facilities located across nine “upwind” states should be subject to additional, costly controls and limitations in order to assist New York in meeting its air quality obligations under 2008 and 2015 national ozone air quality standards.  Last week, the Federal Register <a href="https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/FR-2019-05-20/pdf/2019-09928.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">published</a> the proposal by the Environmental Protection Agency (“EPA”) to reject New York’s far-reaching petition, providing momentary relief to the thousands of workers across nine states that found themselves within the crosshairs of New York’s “keep it in the ground” ideology.</p>
</div>
</div>
<p>With this week’s EPA action, the comment period is now officially open for the public to weigh-in on whether it supports – or opposes – New York’s attempt to curtail or shut down legitimate business activities across Illinois, Indiana, Kentucky, Maryland, Michigan, Ohio, Pennsylvania, Virginia, and West Virginia.  If you live in any one of these states, and particularly if you live near or work at any of the many <a href="https://www.dec.ny.gov/docs/air_pdf/sips126petition.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">facilities targeted</a> (pages 33-42) by New York’s petition, now is the time for you to speak up.</p>
<p>Take a good look at the map below to see the locations of the many facilities targeted by New York’s petition.  Not surprisingly, power plants and refineries are major targets, but so are countless other facility types.  From a Pennsylvania facility that produces renewable energy from municipal waste to steel plants in Michigan to a box factory in rural Virginia, New York’s petition contorts the Clean Air Act well beyond the intended “major source or group of stationary sources” which are typically the subject of a state petition under Section 126.  Even a facility in western Indiana at Purdue University – which is more than 400 miles away from New York’s westernmost border – is targeted as a “bad neighbor” by New York’s complaint.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burning-reduction-methods/the-things-i-could-have-posted-today-trump-denies-californias-ability-to-set-fuel-standards-or-irans-strike-on-the-saudi-oil-fields-but/">The Things I Could Have Posted Today &#8211; Trump denies California&#8217;s ability to set fuel standards or Iran&#8217;s air strikes on the Saudi oil fields but</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/burning-reduction-methods/the-things-i-could-have-posted-today-trump-denies-californias-ability-to-set-fuel-standards-or-irans-strike-on-the-saudi-oil-fields-but/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Right To Repair Movement &#8211; Could it repair the Earth</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/the-right-to-repair-movement-could-it-repair-the-earth/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/the-right-to-repair-movement-could-it-repair-the-earth/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 21:11:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[big whoop dee do]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burn free generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children and the environment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cool sites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[global warming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[masters of the universe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[penetrating ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self inflicted wounds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waste]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=7948</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>This starts out as a technology issue. Farmers wanted to repair their tractors. Smart phone users wanted to repair their phones. But it turns out that if you follow that thread it leads to wanting to repair everything. Our broken &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/the-right-to-repair-movement-could-it-repair-the-earth/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/the-right-to-repair-movement-could-it-repair-the-earth/">The Right To Repair Movement &#8211; Could it repair the Earth</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This starts out as a technology issue. Farmers wanted to repair their tractors. Smart phone users wanted to repair their phones. But it turns out that if you follow that thread it leads to wanting to repair everything. Our broken economic system. To fixing Silicone Valley&#8217;s technology spew. Fixing our infrastructure so that it works. Not descarfing it and getting new. Maybe even preventing Global Warming. Too tall a task. Maybe not.</p>
<p><a href="https://repair.org/standards">https://repair.org/standards</a></p>
<p>Green standards for electronics establish a consistent set of environmental leadership criteria for the design, use, and end-of-life phases of electronics. Since their initial development, green U.S. electronics standards have successfully pushed manufacturers to incorporate key performance criteria, including requirements for recycled plastics, the reduction of hazardous materials, end-of-life management, and energy efficiency. Historically, by setting a high bar and rewarding significant advances in green design, such mandates have shaped electronics design for the better.</p>
<p>Yet these standards—both in and out of development—have become increasingly ineffectual, as electronics manufacturers now constitute a large voting bloc on most U.S. green standards groups. Standards are arduous to update, and the criteria are often too easy for manufacturers to achieve. Thus, electronics standards, more and more often, fail to function as tools of environmental leadership. Industry and purchasers rely on these standards for guidance in identifying sustainable products—which further perpetuates the low bar that has been set.</p>
<p>U.S. green standards could again lead, were they to integrate challenging, inspiring green design criteria, including (but not limited to) guidelines for increased reuse and repair. Unfortunately, manufacturers have <strong>consistently opposed stronger reuse and repair criteria</strong>. As a result, green standards have systemically failed to incorporate strong policies that would enable repair, reuse, and product life extension for electronics.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and consume the whole website. Mor next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/the-right-to-repair-movement-could-it-repair-the-earth/">The Right To Repair Movement &#8211; Could it repair the Earth</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/the-right-to-repair-movement-could-it-repair-the-earth/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Energy Efficiency In The Home &#8211; A fan sends me an excellent guide</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/burning-reduction-methods/energy-efficiency-in-the-home-a-fan-sends-me-an-excellent-guide/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/burning-reduction-methods/energy-efficiency-in-the-home-a-fan-sends-me-an-excellent-guide/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2019 19:14:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[big whoop dee do]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burning reduction methods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cool sites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[efficient refrigerators]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy conservation measures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy Tough Love Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environmentalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[masters of the universe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[radiant barriers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[residential energy efficiency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self inflicted wounds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stewardship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[weatherization]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=7921</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I know it has been a while since I have put anything up about Residential Energy  Use, which is where this BLOG started out but we get requests from organizations to get a plug and so here you go. Tyler &#60;tyler@greenteensclub.org&#62; &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/burning-reduction-methods/energy-efficiency-in-the-home-a-fan-sends-me-an-excellent-guide/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burning-reduction-methods/energy-efficiency-in-the-home-a-fan-sends-me-an-excellent-guide/">Energy Efficiency In The Home &#8211; A fan sends me an excellent guide</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I know it has been a while since I have put anything up about Residential Energy  Use, which is where this BLOG started out but we get requests from organizations to get a plug and so here you go.</p>
<div class="D_F ac_FT ab_CI en_0"></div>
<div class="o_h D_F em_0 E_fq7 ek_BB" data-test-id="address-info">
<div class="D_F en_0"><span class="u_b en_0 C4_Z2aVTcY" data-test-id="message-from"><span class="D_F rtlI_rtlI_dz_sSg " data-test-id="email-pill">Tyler<span class="u_N C_Z1VRpVF"> &lt;tyler@greenteensclub.org&gt;</span></span></span></div>
<div class="d_6FIA i_6FIA D_F eo_HB"><span class="u_b E_eo6 C_Z1TsNWR">To:</span><span class="D_F rtlI_rtlI_dz_sSg " data-test-id="email-pill"><span class="C4_Z2aVTcY" title="info@censys.org" data-test-id="message-to">info@censys.org</span></span></div>
</div>
<div class="en_0 s_6Fd5 H_6Fd5 M_3gJOe cdPFi_Z281SGl O_cMr O4_cMu"></div>
<div class="D_F en_0 M_3gJOe A_6Eb4 C_Z1VRpVF" data-test-id="message-date">Aug 7 at 1:01 PM</div>
<div class="D_F ab_CI Y_68F4 en_0 cdPFi_ZpQYvz H_6MGW W_6MGW lv_1IWXzk h_Z13pql2 h4_2d9T5e"></div>
<div class="I_52qC D_FY W_6D6F" data-test-id="message-view-body">
<div class="X_6MGW"></div>
<div class="msg-body P_wpofO iy_A mq_AS" data-test-id="message-view-body-content">
<div class="jb_0 X_6MGW N_6Fd5">
<div>
<div id="yiv5534073119">
<p>Hi there,</p>
<p>My name is Tyler and I&#8217;m a member of GreenTeensClub. We&#8217;re spreading resources that help make our planet a little healthier, like this home energy efficiency guide: https://www.basementguides.com/basement-and-home-energy/</p>
<p>I think your site is a great place to share this resource: /censys/date/2015/05</p>
<p>The page includes the biggest culprits of energy waste in a home, tips for locating the source of energy-waste issues, and how to lower your bills while reducing your footprint.</p>
<p>Please help us spread awareness of the importance of making homes more energy efficient. Even if we only get a few people to make minor changes, then we&#8217;ve made a huge difference.</p>
<p>Thanks!<br />
Tyler</p>
<p>GreenTeensClub</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<blockquote class="wp-embedded-content" data-secret="S02cDynZVE"><p><a href="https://www.basementguides.com/basement-and-home-energy/">Basement And Home Energy</a></p></blockquote>
<p><iframe title="&#8220;Basement And Home Energy&#8221; &#8212; Basement Guides" class="wp-embedded-content" sandbox="allow-scripts" security="restricted" style="position: absolute; clip: rect(1px, 1px, 1px, 1px);" src="https://www.basementguides.com/basement-and-home-energy/embed/#?secret=S02cDynZVE" data-secret="S02cDynZVE" width="584" height="329" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burning-reduction-methods/energy-efficiency-in-the-home-a-fan-sends-me-an-excellent-guide/">Energy Efficiency In The Home &#8211; A fan sends me an excellent guide</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/burning-reduction-methods/energy-efficiency-in-the-home-a-fan-sends-me-an-excellent-guide/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Commercial Airplanes Are A Huge Cause Of Global Warming &#8211; People say no way</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/commercial-airplanes-are-a-huge-cause-of-global-warming-people-say-no-way/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/commercial-airplanes-are-a-huge-cause-of-global-warming-people-say-no-way/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2019 16:01:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[advanced energy structures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[airforce]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[batteries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burn free generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cool sites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electricity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environmentalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transportation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=7914</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Her is why I say that Airplanes are the prime culprits of Global Warming. First: They Fly High. While fossil fueled Power Plants and Surface Transport Fleets emit huge green house gases many of them are mitigated before they can &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/commercial-airplanes-are-a-huge-cause-of-global-warming-people-say-no-way/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/commercial-airplanes-are-a-huge-cause-of-global-warming-people-say-no-way/">Commercial Airplanes Are A Huge Cause Of Global Warming &#8211; People say no way</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Her is why I say that Airplanes are the prime culprits of Global Warming. First: They Fly High. While fossil fueled Power Plants and Surface Transport Fleets emit huge green house gases many of them are mitigated before they can have much of a green house effect. But most jets fly right up there. I mean even some prop planes do too.</p>
<p>Second: The Fuel. Especially military flight fuel is bloody near kerosene.</p>
<p>Third: There are so many. It may be a myth but after 911 when so many planes were grounded the tempeture dropped a degree.</p>
<p>So this is kinda cool. Maybe we should call them personal air taxi&#8217;s or something. Yes they will be expensive. So what.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.vox.com/2019/5/14/18535971/electric-airplane-aircraft-aviation-clean-energy">https://www.vox.com/2019/5/14/18535971/electric-airplane-aircraft-aviation-clean-energy</a></p>
<div class="c-entry-hero__header-wrap">
<h1 class="c-page-title">Aircraft fuel is notoriously dirty. This airline is betting on clean electricity.</h1>
</div>
<p class="c-entry-summary p-dek">Harbour Air wants to become the world’s first all-electric airline and start flying passengers by 2022.</p>
<div class="c-byline">By <span class="c-byline__item"> <a href="https://www.vox.com/authors/umair-irfan">Umair Irfan</a> </span> <span class="c-byline__item"> <time class="c-byline__item" datetime="2019-05-14T16:30:00+00:00" data-ui="timestamp"> May 14, 2019, 12:30pm EDT </time></span></div>
<p id="khu5UD">It’s becoming increasingly difficult to ignore the fact that air travel is a massive and growing problem for the global climate.</p>
<p id="e0cf0M">In the US, transportation is now the largest source of greenhouse gas emissions, and aircraft account for <a href="https://www.epa.gov/regulations-emissions-vehicles-and-engines/regulations-greenhouse-gas-emissions-aircraft">12 percent</a> of transportation emissions. <a href="https://www.bts.dot.gov/newsroom/2018-traffic-data-us-airlines-and-foreign-airlines-us-flights">US air travel</a> reached a record high last year, pushing up overall <a href="https://www.vox.com/2019/1/8/18174082/us-carbon-emissions-2018">emissions</a> even while the power sector saw a decline.</p>
<p id="P7RqPM">To make matters worse, demand for flights is growing. Emissions from air travel are poised to spike up to <a href="https://ec.europa.eu/clima/policies/transport/aviation_en">sevenfold</a> globally by 2050 if nothing else changes.</p>
<p id="w6PQSS">That’s why it’s so urgent to decarbonize air travel. Yet the technical challenges are immense. Alternatives like carbon-neutral biofuels remain far too costly. And the stodgy rules in the heavily regulated, risk-averse aviation sector lag far behind advances in electric drivetrains.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>They are currently flying small electric planes on a regional basis.</p>
<p>Go there and see the future. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/commercial-airplanes-are-a-huge-cause-of-global-warming-people-say-no-way/">Commercial Airplanes Are A Huge Cause Of Global Warming &#8211; People say no way</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/commercial-airplanes-are-a-huge-cause-of-global-warming-people-say-no-way/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Two Weeks Ago I Said Trees Would Beat Global Global Warming</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/two-weeks-ago-i-said-trees-would-beat-global-global-warming/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/two-weeks-ago-i-said-trees-would-beat-global-global-warming/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 16:10:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[advanced energy structures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burn free generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[carbon sequestration]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children and the environment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cool sites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environmentalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[flying high]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gaia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[landscaping]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[national organizations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[old tired advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[penetrating ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[schemes]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stewardship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water efficiency]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=7902</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>This week&#8217;s articles says &#8211; Not Likely. I say the trees are a good start. The point is that some people argue for trees or solar panels in the desert for instance. But the desert is an ecosystem that trees &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/two-weeks-ago-i-said-trees-would-beat-global-global-warming/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/two-weeks-ago-i-said-trees-would-beat-global-global-warming/">Two Weeks Ago I Said Trees Would Beat Global Global Warming</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This week&#8217;s articles says &#8211; Not Likely. I say the trees are a good start. The point is that some people argue for trees or solar panels in the desert for instance. But the desert is an ecosystem that trees or solar panels would disrupt. Deserts are not &#8220;throw away&#8221; ecosystems. So we can only deploy so much of each. This is why i think geothermal is the ultimate solution.</p>
<p><a href="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/crux/2019/07/10/reforestation-climate-change-plant-trees/#.XS870XtOnct">http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/crux/2019/07/10/reforestation-climate-change-plant-trees/#.XS870XtOnct</a></p>
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" class="wp-image-12391 lazyloaded" src="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/crux/files/2019/07/Planting-Trees.jpg" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" srcset="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/crux/files/2019/07/Planting-Trees.jpg 1000w, http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/crux/files/2019/07/Planting-Trees-300x200.jpg 300w, http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/crux/files/2019/07/Planting-Trees-768x512.jpg 768w" alt="planting trees" data-lazy-srcset="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/crux/files/2019/07/Planting-Trees.jpg 1000w, http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/crux/files/2019/07/Planting-Trees-300x200.jpg 300w, http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/crux/files/2019/07/Planting-Trees-768x512.jpg 768w" data-lazy-sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" data-lazy-src="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/crux/files/2019/07/Planting-Trees.jpg" data-was-processed="true" /><figcaption>Planting trees, while beneficial to the planet, is not an easy solution to climate change. (Credit: Janelle Lugge/Shutterstock)</figcaption></figure>
<p>Last week, a new study in the journal <em><a href="https://science.sciencemag.org/content/365/6448/76" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="Science (opens in a new tab)">Science</a></em> highlighted the role forests could play in <a href="http://blogs.discovermagazine.com/d-brief/2019/07/04/could-planting-tons-of-trees-solve-climate-change/#.XR9vR9NKjm1" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener" aria-label="tackling climate change (opens in a new tab)">tackling climate change</a>. Researchers estimated that by restoring forests to their maximum potential, we could cut down atmospheric carbon dioxide (CO<sub>2</sub>) by 25 percent — a move that would take us back to levels not seen in over a century. Though the study brings hope in the fight against climate change, other experts warn the solution is not that simple.</p>
<p>The study, led by scientists at ETH-Zürich, Switzerland, determined the planet has 0.9 billion hectares of land available to hold more trees — an area the size of the continental U.S. Converting those areas into forests would be a game-changer for climate change, the authors suggested.</p>
<p>“[The study] is probably the best assessment we have to date of how much land could support tree cover on our planet,” says Robin Chazdon, a forest ecologist and professor emeritus at the University of Connecticut not involved in the study, But she is quick to point out that restoring forests is not as simple as it sounds.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and think. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/two-weeks-ago-i-said-trees-would-beat-global-global-warming/">Two Weeks Ago I Said Trees Would Beat Global Global Warming</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/two-weeks-ago-i-said-trees-would-beat-global-global-warming/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
