<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>green cars Archives - Community Energy Systems</title>
	<atom:link href="/censys/category/blog/green-cars/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/censys/category/blog/green-cars/</link>
	<description>Censys.org</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 21:07:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Some Things Billed As Environmental Aren&#8217;t &#8211; In this case TESLA</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/green-cars/some-things-billed-as-environmental-arent-in-this-case-tesla/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/green-cars/some-things-billed-as-environmental-arent-in-this-case-tesla/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 21:07:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[advanced energy structures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burning reduction methods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environmentalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green cars]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=8416</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I repeat this only once. Elon Musk is a genius. His Electric Cars are also amazing and GENERALLY good for the environment, especially if charged by Solar and Wind Power. But they need some fire suppression ability because 4 hours &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/green-cars/some-things-billed-as-environmental-arent-in-this-case-tesla/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/green-cars/some-things-billed-as-environmental-arent-in-this-case-tesla/">Some Things Billed As Environmental Aren&#8217;t &#8211; In this case TESLA</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I repeat this only once. Elon Musk is a genius. His Electric Cars are also amazing and GENERALLY good for the environment, especially if charged by Solar and Wind Power. But they need some fire suppression ability because 4 hours and 30,000 gallons of water is like a major house fire. That&#8217;s is when these type of wrecks are uncommon. What happens when they are everywhere?</p>
<p>Then there is the whole disabling the auto pilot function. I mean Morons aren&#8217;t good for the environment either.</p>
<p><a href="https://slate.com/technology/2021/04/tesla-crash-texas-drivers-seat-fire-autopilot.html?via=rss">https://slate.com/technology/2021/04/tesla-crash-texas-drivers-seat-fire-autopilot.html?via=rss</a></p>
<p>The Industry</p>
<h1 class="article__hed">The Most Disturbing Part of the Latest Tesla Crash</h1>
<div class="article__meta">
<div class="article__byline">By <a href="https://slate.com/author/aaron-mak">Aaron Mak</a></div>
</div>
<p class="slate-paragraph slate-graf" data-uri="slate.com/_components/slate-paragraph/instances/cknp1wfy2005ammm9uxxs9udy@published" data-word-count="109">Two men died near Houston, Texas, on Saturday while riding in a 2019 Tesla Model S that, according to <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/18/business/tesla-fatal-crash-texas.html">local authorities</a>, was speeding into a turn and ended up going off the road and crashing into a tree. It took first responders four hours and more than 30,000 gallons of water to put out the resulting fire, which kept reigniting; when damaged, the lithium ion batteries in electric cars can cause fires that are very difficult to extinguish because of how they store energy. Authorities <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/4/18/22390612/two-people-killed-fiery-tesla-crash-no-driver">reportedly</a> attempted to ask Tesla for advice on how to put out the fire, but it’s unclear whether they ended up getting any help.</p>
<p class="slate-paragraph slate-graf" data-uri="slate.com/_components/slate-paragraph/instances/cknp1x3jq000f3g6dtaabx219@published" data-word-count="83">Besides the fire, there was something especially disturbing about the crash: No one was in the driver’s seat. One of the men was in the passenger seat and the other in the rear. There has been no official confirmation that they had engaged the car’s “autopilot” feature—something that is beloved by many Tesla owners and that critics of the company say is marketed in unsafe ways—though their wives <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/04/18/business/tesla-fatal-crash-texas.html">reportedly</a> told authorities that they had been discussing the feature before leaving for their drive.</p>
<p>Unlike the systems that companies like Google and Uber have been developing and testing for years, Tesla’s autopilot is not completely autonomous, though it does allow the cars to accelerate, steer, and brake by themselves. The company warns drivers that they need to be behind the wheel and paying attention in case the system makes a mistake and they have to intervene. There have nevertheless been a number of <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/nation/2021/04/19/tesla-texas-driverless-crash/">serious accidents</a> in which the autopilot feature appeared to be involved. For instance, a man died in 2018 while using the autopilot in California; data from his phone indicates that <a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/transportation/2020/02/11/telsa-running-autopilot-repeatedly-veered-toward-spot-where-apple-engineer-later-crashed-died-federal-investigators-say/">a video game</a> had been active on the device. The National Highway Traffic Safety Administration also <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2021/03/23/business/teslas-autopilot-safety-investigations.html">confirmed</a> to the New York Times in March that it is currently investigating the potential role of Tesla’s autopilot feature in 23 crashes.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/green-cars/some-things-billed-as-environmental-arent-in-this-case-tesla/">Some Things Billed As Environmental Aren&#8217;t &#8211; In this case TESLA</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/green-cars/some-things-billed-as-environmental-arent-in-this-case-tesla/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Future Is Built In Batteries &#8211; Where the structure becomes the storage device</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/green-transportation/the-future-is-built-in-batteries-where-the-structure-becomes-the-storage-device/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/green-transportation/the-future-is-built-in-batteries-where-the-structure-becomes-the-storage-device/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 20:44:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[advanced energy structures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[batteries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burn free generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[public transportation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=8399</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>While I have always said the storage is NOT the problem in renewable energy because you can always pump something like water or air during good times and discharge it in bad times. The storage of energy in moving things &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/green-transportation/the-future-is-built-in-batteries-where-the-structure-becomes-the-storage-device/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/green-transportation/the-future-is-built-in-batteries-where-the-structure-becomes-the-storage-device/">The Future Is Built In Batteries &#8211; Where the structure becomes the storage device</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While I have always said the storage is NOT the problem in renewable energy because you can always pump something like water or air during good times and discharge it in bad times. The storage of energy in moving things was always gonna be a problem and batteries were only an interim solution. Now some people are getting a handle on this problem, and I am supper EXCITED about it. This article is real techincal. Sorry.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2021/03/210322091632.htm">https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2021/03/210322091632.htm</a></p>
<h1 id="headline" class="headline">Big breakthrough for &#8216;massless&#8217; energy storage</h1>
<dl class="dl-horizontal dl-custom">
<dt>Date:</dt>
<dd id="date_posted">March 22, 2021</dd>
<dt>Source:</dt>
<dd id="source">Chalmers University of Technology</dd>
<dt>Summary:</dt>
<dd id="abstract">Researchers have produced a structural battery that performs ten times better than all previous versions. It contains carbon fiber that serves simultaneously as an electrode, conductor, and load-bearing material. Their latest research breakthrough paves the way for essentially &#8216;massless&#8217; energy storage in vehicles and other technology.</dd>
</dl>
<p id="first" class="lead">Researchers from Chalmers University of Technology have produced a structural battery that performs ten times better than all previous versions. It contains carbon fibre that serves simultaneously as an electrode, conductor, and load-bearing material. Their latest research breakthrough paves the way for essentially &#8216;massless&#8217; energy storage in vehicles and other technology.</p>
<div id="text">
<p>The batteries in today&#8217;s electric cars constitute a large part of the vehicles&#8217; weight, without fulfilling any load-bearing function. A structural battery, on the other hand, is one that works as both a power source and as part of the structure &#8212; for example, in a car body. This is termed &#8216;massless&#8217; energy storage, because in essence the battery&#8217;s weight vanishes when it becomes part of the load-bearing structure. Calculations show that this type of multifunctional battery could greatly reduce the weight of an electric vehicle.</p>
<p>The development of structural batteries at Chalmers University of Technology has proceeded through many years of research, including previous discoveries involving certain types of carbon fibre. In addition to being stiff and strong, they also have a good ability to store electrical energy chemically. This work was named by Physics World as one of 2018&#8217;s ten biggest scientific breakthroughs.</p>
</div>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read. It is kinda long too. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/green-transportation/the-future-is-built-in-batteries-where-the-structure-becomes-the-storage-device/">The Future Is Built In Batteries &#8211; Where the structure becomes the storage device</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/green-transportation/the-future-is-built-in-batteries-where-the-structure-becomes-the-storage-device/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tomorrow * NO Cars &#8211; What then</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/green-cars/tomorrow-no-cars-what-then/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/green-cars/tomorrow-no-cars-what-then/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 20:20:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[burning reduction methods]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[climate change]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environmentalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[global warming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water pollution]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=8380</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>If Schumer could pull this off I would be &#8220;dancin in the streets&#8221;. It would not be as good and banning Airline Flights, but heh I will take whatever I can get. It would be really good for the lower &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/green-cars/tomorrow-no-cars-what-then/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/green-cars/tomorrow-no-cars-what-then/">Tomorrow * NO Cars &#8211; What then</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If Schumer could pull this off I would be &#8220;dancin in the streets&#8221;. It would not be as good and banning Airline Flights, but heh I will take whatever I can get. It would be really good for the lower level atmosphere and especially good for bodies of water, whether flowing bodies like rivers or standing bodies like lakes or oceans. Unfortunately, the upper atmosphere is where the real global warming is taking place. Still &#8211; I am not minimizing this. IT be good.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/17/22334634/schumer-electric-vehicle-swap-discount-infrastructure-interview">https://www.theverge.com/2021/3/17/22334634/schumer-electric-vehicle-swap-discount-infrastructure-interview</a></p>
<div class="c-entry-group-labels c-entry-group-labels--feature">
<ul aria-labelledby="heading-label--53fhlluw">
<li class="c-entry-group-labels__item"><a href="https://www.theverge.com/policy"> Policy </a></li>
</ul>
</div>
<h1 class="c-page-title">Chuck Schumer wants to replace every gas car in America with an electric vehicle</h1>
<p class="c-entry-summary p-dek">The Senate majority leader is reviving his plan to give people discounts for swapping their gas car for an electric one</p>
<div class="c-byline"><span class="c-byline-wrapper"> By <span class="c-byline__item"> <a href="https://www.theverge.com/authors/andrew-j-hawkins" data-analytics-link="author-name"><span class="c-byline__author-name">Andrew J. Hawkins</span></a><a class="c-byline__twitter-handle" href="https://www.twitter.com/andyjayhawk">@andyjayhawk</a> </span> <span class="c-byline__item"> <time class="c-byline__item" datetime="2021-03-17T15:23:13" data-ui="timestamp"> Mar 17, 2021, 11:23am </time></span></span></div>
<p id="UnXkqU" class="p--has-dropcap p-large-text drop-letter-w"><span role="text"><span class="sr-only"><strong>W</strong>ith</span></span> the $1.9 trillion COVID relief bill signed into law, Senate Majority Leader Chuck Schumer (D-NY) is ready to tackle the next major challenge: President Joe Biden’s call for a massive infrastructure bill. As part of that package, Schumer said he plans to include his ambitious proposal to get every American to swap their gas-guzzling car for an electric one.</p>
<p id="4s4nuu">“It’s a bold new plan designed to accelerate America’s transition to all electric vehicles on the road, to developing a charging infrastructure, and to grow American jobs through clean manufacturing,” Schumer told <em>The Verge</em> in a brief interview this week. “And the ultimate goal is to have every car manufactured in America be electric by 2030, and every car on the road be clean by 2040.”</p>
<p id="9dBBWh">The top-line details of the <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2019/10/25/20931983/schumer-electric-car-trade-in-gas-discount-proposal-zero-emission">“cash for clunkers’’-style plan</a> haven’t changed much since Schumer first proposed it in <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/10/24/opinion/chuck-schumer-electric-car.html">an op-ed in <em>The</em> <em>New York Times</em> in late 2019</a>. But the political landscape has certainly shifted in favor of the Democrats, breathing new life into the idea. Under the proposal, anyone who trades in their gas car for an electric one would get a “substantial” point-of-sale discount, Schumer says. He wouldn’t say how much of a discount, only that it would be “deep.” A spokesperson later confirmed they are eyeing rebates that are “more generous” than the current $7,500 federal EV tax credit.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/green-cars/tomorrow-no-cars-what-then/">Tomorrow * NO Cars &#8211; What then</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/green-cars/tomorrow-no-cars-what-then/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Elon Musk Throws A Tempertantrum &#8211; NOone listens</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/green-cars/elon-musk-throws-a-tempertantrum-noone-listens/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/green-cars/elon-musk-throws-a-tempertantrum-noone-listens/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 20:18:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[batteries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big whoop dee do]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burn free generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electricity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[self inflicted wounds]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=8112</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Really &#8211; wouldn&#8217;t that be cool? But you know, self absorbed rich young guys with big mouths, the press eats them up. More! More! More! Is he right well? Newsome is no fascist. He is just a little old Democrat. &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/green-cars/elon-musk-throws-a-tempertantrum-noone-listens/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/green-cars/elon-musk-throws-a-tempertantrum-noone-listens/">Elon Musk Throws A Tempertantrum &#8211; NOone listens</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Really &#8211; wouldn&#8217;t that be cool? But you know, self absorbed rich young guys with big mouths, the press eats them up. More! More! More! Is he right well? Newsome is no fascist. He is just a little old Democrat. Could the car industry open up? Well probably, slowly. But Elon wants what Elon wants and Elon usually gets. Thus the outburst.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/04/29/tesla-tsla-earnings-q1-2020.html">https://www.cnbc.com/2020/04/29/tesla-tsla-earnings-q1-2020.html</a></p>
<div class="ArticleHeader-wrapperHeroNoImage ArticleHeader-wrapperHero ArticleHeader-wrapper ArticleHeader-wrapperNoImage">
<div>
<h1 class="ArticleHeader-headline">Tesla rises as company ekes out a Q1 profit</h1>
</div>
<div class="ArticleHeader-time"><time data-testid="published-timestamp">Published Wed, Apr 29 20203:31 PM EDT </time><time data-testid="lastpublished-timestamp">Updated Wed, Apr 29 20208:37 PM EDT</time></div>
</div>
<div class="ArticleHeader-authorAndShareInline">
<div class="ArticleHeader-authorContainer">
<div class="ArticleHeader-author">
<div class="Author-author">
<div class="Author-authorInfo">
<div class="Author-authorPortrait"></div>
<div class="Author-authorNameAndSocial"><a class="Author-authorName" href="https://www.cnbc.com/lauren-feiner/">Lauren Feiner</a><a class="Author-authorTwitter" href="https://twitter.com/lauren_feiner" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@lauren_feiner</a></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="ArticleHeader-author">
<div class="Author-author">
<div class="Author-authorInfo">
<div class="Author-authorPortrait"></div>
<div class="Author-authorNameAndSocial"><a class="Author-authorName" href="https://www.cnbc.com/lora-kolodny/">Lora Kolodny</a><a class="Author-authorTwitter" href="https://twitter.com/@lorakolodny" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">@lorakolodny</a></div>
<div></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="RenderKeyPoints-list">
<div>
<div class="group">
<ul>
<li>Tesla reported first-quarter results on Wednesday, including a $16 million profit.</li>
<li>A Covid-19 outbreak in China forced Elon Musk’s electric-vehicle maker to suspend manufacturing in Shanghai for more than a week in February and in the U.S. at the end of March.</li>
<li>Musk and Tesla CFO Zachary Kirkhorn are expected to update shareholders on the impact of the coronavirus on their business so far and their plans to bring production back online in the U.S.</li>
</ul>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>Excerpt:</p>
<p>Musk slammed the Bay Area’s shelter-in-place orders as “unconstitutional” and “fascism” in a <a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2020/04/29/elon-musk-slams-coronavirus-shelter-in-place-orders-as-fascist.html">profanity-laced tirade</a> on an earnings call Wednesday evening.</p>
<p>He said: “I think we are a bit worried about not being able to resume production in the Bay Area and that should be identified as a serious risk. We only have two car factories now, one in Shanghai and one in the Bay Area.”</p>
<p>And he continued sounding more and more incensed, at one point asking, “What the f&#8211;k?”</p>
<p>Musk also ranted about the health orders: “I think people are going to be very angry about this and are very angry. It’s like somebody wants to stay in the house? That’s great, they should be allowed to stay in the house, and they should not be compelled to leave. But to say that they cannot leave their house, and they will be arrested if they do, this is fascist. This is not democratic. This is not freedom. Give people back their goddamn freedom.”</p>
<p>(Leaving a place of residence is not a crime in California under Covid-19 health orders.)</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and listen to loud shouting. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/green-cars/elon-musk-throws-a-tempertantrum-noone-listens/">Elon Musk Throws A Tempertantrum &#8211; NOone listens</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/green-cars/elon-musk-throws-a-tempertantrum-noone-listens/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Replacement Batteries For EV &#8211; The Secondary Markets are developing</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/replacement-batteries-for-ev-the-secondary-markets-are-developing/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/replacement-batteries-for-ev-the-secondary-markets-are-developing/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 22:11:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[advanced energy structures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[air pollution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[batteries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burn free generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cool sites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electricity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy Tough Love Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environmentalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[penetrating ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=7461</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>I haven&#8217;t written or posted about environmentally sound cars, but this article caught my eye. Having robust Secondary and Tertiary markets means that EVs are here to stay and will eventually conquer the market. https://www.greencarreports.com/news/1116722_nissan-begins-offering-rebuilt-leaf-battery-packs Nissan begins offering rebuilt Leaf &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/replacement-batteries-for-ev-the-secondary-markets-are-developing/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/replacement-batteries-for-ev-the-secondary-markets-are-developing/">Replacement Batteries For EV &#8211; The Secondary Markets are developing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I haven&#8217;t written or posted about environmentally sound cars, but this article caught my eye. Having robust Secondary and Tertiary markets means that EVs are here to stay and will eventually conquer the market.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.greencarreports.com/news/1116722_nissan-begins-offering-rebuilt-leaf-battery-packs">https://www.greencarreports.com/news/1116722_nissan-begins-offering-rebuilt-leaf-battery-packs</a></p>
<h1>Nissan begins offering rebuilt Leaf battery packs</h1>
<div id="leftcol">
<div class="article_body">
<div class="article_content">
<div class="author-line">
<div id="byline" class="byline">
<div class="reviewer"><span class="ex-author "> <a title="View Eric C. Evarts's Profile" href="https://www.greencarreports.com/writer/10064169_eric-c-evarts" target="_blank" rel="author noopener">Eric C. Evarts</a></span></div>
</div>
<div class="by-line-comments-views-date"><a class="comment comment-disqus" href="https://www.greencarreports.com/news/1116722_nissan-begins-offering-rebuilt-leaf-battery-packs#disqus_thread">67 Comments</a> <span class="date">May 14, 2018</span></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>Starting this month, Nissan has begun offering rebuilt battery packs for the older Leafs, filling a gap for drivers of older cars whose packs have begun to run down.</p>
<p>The company built a new facility in Japan to rebuild the packs, and will sell them for about $2,850 (based on the price in Japan), <a href="https://insideevs.com/nissan-introduces-refabricated-batteries-for-older-leaf-in-japan-from-new-4r-plant/">according to <em>Inside EVs.</em></a> A Nissan spokesman told Green Car Reports that the company is investigating offering the program in the United States, but has not yet made a decision.</p>
<p>Electric car repair trainer Craig Van Batenburg, of the Automotive Career Development Center in Worcester, Massachusetts, said the refurbished battery packs are new among electric carmakers. Previously, older battery packs had to be replaced with new ones, which cost more than $6,500 (minus a $1,000 trade-in, or core charge, on the old battery pack.)</p>
<p>The cost covers the 24-kwh battery pack in the original Leaf, which was rated at only 73 miles of range when new.</p>
<p>Owners of early Leafs had problems with the cars losing range after only a year or two in hot climates such as Phoenix, Arizona.</p>
<p><strong>READ THIS: <a href="https://www.greencarreports.com/news/1079475_nissan-buys-back-leaf-electric-cars-under-arizona-lemon-law">Nissan Buys Back Leaf Electric Cars Under Arizona Lemon Law [2012]</a></strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/replacement-batteries-for-ev-the-secondary-markets-are-developing/">Replacement Batteries For EV &#8211; The Secondary Markets are developing</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/replacement-batteries-for-ev-the-secondary-markets-are-developing/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pana IL Students Need Money For Solar Car &#8211; Please help them out</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/pana-il-students-need-money-for-solar-car-please-help-them-out/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/pana-il-students-need-money-for-solar-car-please-help-them-out/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 21:15:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[advanced energy structures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burn free generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children and the environment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electricity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy Tough Love Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environmentalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[gaia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[penetrating ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[photovoltaic panels]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[serious artist]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar power]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[spirituality]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stewardship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transportation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=6106</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Disclaimer: I know no student involved in this endeavor nor do I know anybody at their High School. These have got to be brave and hard working students. They deserve all the support we can give. According to the article &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/pana-il-students-need-money-for-solar-car-please-help-them-out/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/pana-il-students-need-money-for-solar-car-please-help-them-out/">Pana IL Students Need Money For Solar Car &#8211; Please help them out</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Disclaimer: I know no student involved in this endeavor nor do I know anybody at their High School. These have got to be brave and hard working students. They deserve all the support we can give. According to the article they need at least $9,000 to complete the project so please give all you can.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.sj-r.com/news/20171211/pana-students-take-on-solar-car-challenge">http://www.sj-r.com/news/20171211/pana-students-take-on-solar-car-challenge</a></p>
<h1 class="headline">Pana students take on solar car challenge</h1>
<p><span class="byline-item">By <a href="mailto:jason.nevel@sj-r.com">Jason Nevel</a><br />
Staff Writer<br />
</span></p>
<div class="article-meta">
<div class="inner">
<div class="article-meta-main"><span class="article-meta-date">Posted Dec 11, 2017 at 6:28 PM</span> <span class="article-meta-updated">Updated Dec 11, 2017 at 6:28 PM</span></div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="article-meta"></div>
<div class="inner">
<p>PANA – Apparently building a moonbuggy wasn’t hard enough.</p>
<p>Pana High School students this year are setting out to build a solar-powered car from scratch and race it across Texas to California as part of the <a href="http://www.solarcarchallenge.org/challenge/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">2018 Solar Car Challenge</a>.</p>
<p>Building the battery-powered four-wheeled rovers that Apollo astronauts used on the moon in the early 1970s is a tradition at Pana.</p>
<p>But industrial arts teacher Steve Bonser said students learned about the solar car challenge this summer and decided to give it a shot — despite being warned it wouldn’t be easy.</p>
<p>“The kids voted unanimously to up the game and take on a lot more work and build this solar car,” he said.</p>
<p><strong>Starting to take shape</strong></p>
<p>The framework of what will hopefully become a solar-powered car is beginning to take shape in the shop at the junior high school.</p>
<p>Bonser said the students have finished most of the design work and constructed the frame for the 8-foot long car. The goal is to have the entire vehicle, which will be street legal, finished in March.</p>
<p>Still early on in the process, Bonser said, the school was fortunate Battery Specialists in Taylorville donated a golf cart, which will provide some parts.</p>
<div class="ad-container"> The school also acquired solar panels that will power the battery. But much of how it will all come together is still an unknown.</div>
</div>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read. Please donate to this project. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/pana-il-students-need-money-for-solar-car-please-help-them-out/">Pana IL Students Need Money For Solar Car &#8211; Please help them out</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/pana-il-students-need-money-for-solar-car-please-help-them-out/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Major Energy Transition Has Begun &#8211; Just the first sentence makes this article important</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/a-major-energy-transition-has-begun-just-the-first-sentence-makes-this-article-important/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/a-major-energy-transition-has-begun-just-the-first-sentence-makes-this-article-important/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 20:55:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[advanced energy structures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[batteries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[big whoop dee do]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burn free generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[children and the environment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cool sites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electricity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy Tough Love Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[international energy groups]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[masters of the universe]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[national organizations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Other countries advances]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[penetrating ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[residential energy efficiency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[solar power]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wind power]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=6072</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>This is a really really long good article. So I am going to shut up and let you read. I have not felt this good in a long time. https://www.platts.com/latest-news/electric-power/london/feature-china-and-the-new-energy-economy-26831057 Feature: China and the New Energy Economy London (Platts)&#8211;31 Oct &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/a-major-energy-transition-has-begun-just-the-first-sentence-makes-this-article-important/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/a-major-energy-transition-has-begun-just-the-first-sentence-makes-this-article-important/">A Major Energy Transition Has Begun &#8211; Just the first sentence makes this article important</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This is a really really long good article. So I am going to shut up and let you read. I have not felt this good in a long time.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.platts.com/latest-news/electric-power/london/feature-china-and-the-new-energy-economy-26831057">https://www.platts.com/latest-news/electric-power/london/feature-china-and-the-new-energy-economy-26831057</a></p>
<div id="TopDiv" class="wrapper">
<div id="ctl00_ctl00_privacyPlicyBanner" class="showprivacyPlicyBanner"></div>
<div id="ctl00_ctl00_headerMenu" class="header_subpage">
<div id="ctl00_ctl00_divHeaderArea" class="headerArea">
<div id="ctl00_ctl00_divLogoHeader" class="logoHeader logoHeader"><a href="https://www.platts.com/"> <img decoding="async" src="https://www.platts.com/Im.Platts.content/LandingPagesXml/Images/PlattsLogo.png" alt="Platts" /></a></div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<h1>Feature: China and the New Energy Economy</h1>
<div class="clr"></div>
<p class="commondate">London (Platts)&#8211;31 Oct 2017 1239 pm EDT/1639 GMT</p>
<p>There is an increasingly inescapable sense that an energy transition of enormous proportions is taking place. The number of &#8216;bans&#8217; announced on Internal Combustion Engine (ICE) vehicles is growing, even if governments are placing them relatively far out on the political horizon.</p>
<p>More and more car manufacturers are taking note and shifting R&amp;D spending into Electric Vehicles (EVs), a move which has profound implications for the development curves, and thus future cost, of EVs versus ICE vehicles.</p>
<p>In October, US automaker General Motors said that it would launch two new pure electric models in 2018 and a further 18 by 2023.</p>
<p>Its competitor Ford announced the creation of a new internal team to &#8220;think big and move fast&#8221; in order to accelerate the electrification of its auto production. Both are some way behind their European counterparts.</p>
<p>It is not hard to see why such decisions are being made now. While the number of EVs on the road remains just a fraction of the total parc, global sales are growing by about 40% year-on-year, making EVs the biggest growth story in the auto market in decades.</p>
<p>And, if governments are going to regulate against ICE vehicles and subsidize EVs, thereby changing the consumer choices which otherwise might be made, then what other path is there to tread?</p>
<h2>
CHINESE WHISPERS</h2>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read. Rejoice. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/a-major-energy-transition-has-begun-just-the-first-sentence-makes-this-article-important/">A Major Energy Transition Has Begun &#8211; Just the first sentence makes this article important</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/a-major-energy-transition-has-begun-just-the-first-sentence-makes-this-article-important/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>GM Goes All Electric &#8211; Well, not right away but it is a good start</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/gm-goes-all-electric-well-not-right-away-but-it-is-a-good-start/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/gm-goes-all-electric-well-not-right-away-but-it-is-a-good-start/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 15:41:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[advanced energy structures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[air pollution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[architecture]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[batteries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burn free generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cool sites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electricity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy Tough Love Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environmentalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[fossil fuels and the United States' Future]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[lies told by energy companies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Other countries advances]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water efficiency]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=6055</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Much like Solar and Wind, Electric Cars have had an up hill battle. But what does that mean. It makes it sound like this is natural. Well it is not. Electric Cars were not about &#8220;ramping up&#8221; to need. It &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/gm-goes-all-electric-well-not-right-away-but-it-is-a-good-start/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/gm-goes-all-electric-well-not-right-away-but-it-is-a-good-start/">GM Goes All Electric &#8211; Well, not right away but it is a good start</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Much like Solar and Wind, Electric Cars have had an up hill battle. But what does that mean. It makes it sound like this is natural. Well it is not. Electric Cars were not about &#8220;ramping up&#8221; to need. It was about battling the forces of evil who did not want alternative forms of energy to succeed. Yah that is right, the fossil fuel industry and their investors and supporters have done everything in their considerable power to prevent their success. They have lied, cheated and lobbied elected bodies all the way down to townships in Colorado for example.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/10/2/16400900/gm-electric-car-hydrogen-fuel-cell-2023">https://www.theverge.com/2017/10/2/16400900/gm-electric-car-hydrogen-fuel-cell-2023</a></p>
<div class="c-entry-hero__header-wrap">
<h1 class="c-page-title">GM will release at least 20 all-electric cars by 2023</h1>
<div class="c-entry-hero__meta">
<div class="c-entry-stat--comment" data-cid="site/entry_stat-1507127288_1469_12946" data-cdata="{&quot;id&quot;:16164941,&quot;comment_count&quot;:9,&quot;recommended_count&quot;:0,&quot;url&quot;:&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2017/10/2/16400900/gm-electric-car-hydrogen-fuel-cell-2023&quot;}"><a class="p-comment-notification has-content" href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/10/2/16400900/gm-electric-car-hydrogen-fuel-cell-2023#comments" data-ui="comment"> <span class="c-entry-stat__comment-data" data-ui="comment-data">9</span> <span class="u-hidden-text">comments</span> </a></div>
</div>
</div>
<h2 class="c-entry-summary p-dek">Both battery and hydrogen fuel cell vehicles</h2>
<div class="c-byline">by <span class="c-byline__item"> <a href="http://www.theverge.com/users/andyjayhawk">Andrew J. Hawkins</a><a class="c-byline__twitter-handle" href="http://www.twitter.com/andyjayhawk">@andyjayhawk</a> </span> <time class="c-byline__item" data-ui="timestamp"> Oct 2, 2017, 12:00pm EDT</time></div>
<p id="hmZlpm">General Motors announced today that it will introduce two new all-electric vehicles within the next 18 months, the first of at least 20 new EVs that the automaker will launch by 2023. GM also renewed its commitment to hydrogen fuel cell technology, a <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/4/13/15257576/hydrogen-fuel-cell-honda-clarity-self-driving-ny-auto-show-2017">clean fuel concept</a> that still needs major infrastructure upgrades before it can become a viable alternative.</p>
<p id="rUwDEh">At a press conference in Detroit this morning, GM’s executive vice president of global product development Mark Reuss said that the company was “committed to an all-electric future,” but cautioned that it wasn’t going to happen “by flipping a switch.”</p>
<div class="c-float-right">
<aside id="SKqhlv"><q>“These aren’t just words in a war of press releases.”</q></aside>
</div>
<p id="Lv5RDv">“These aren’t just words in a war of press releases,” Reuss added. “We are far along in our plan to lead the way to that future world.”</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read the good news. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/gm-goes-all-electric-well-not-right-away-but-it-is-a-good-start/">GM Goes All Electric &#8211; Well, not right away but it is a good start</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/gm-goes-all-electric-well-not-right-away-but-it-is-a-good-start/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Norway Goes Crazy For Electric Cars &#8211; The government helps</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/norway-goes-crazy-for-electric-cars-the-government-helps/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/norway-goes-crazy-for-electric-cars-the-government-helps/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 21:18:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[2016 presidential elections]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advanced energy structures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[batteries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burn free generation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cool sites]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[economics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electricity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy Tough Love Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Other countries advances]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[penetrating ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[public transportation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stewardship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sustainability]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[water efficiency]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=5988</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Norway has a very different approach to the environment then Donald Trump ( I prefer to call dolt 45). They are plunging headlong into a green energy future and I hope the rest of the world follows. http://www.pbs.org/newshour/bb/norways-government-made-electric-cars-irresistible/ How Norway’s &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/norway-goes-crazy-for-electric-cars-the-government-helps/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/norway-goes-crazy-for-electric-cars-the-government-helps/">Norway Goes Crazy For Electric Cars &#8211; The government helps</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Norway has a very different approach to the environment then Donald Trump ( I prefer to call dolt 45). They are plunging headlong into a green energy future and I hope the rest of the world follows.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.pbs.org/newshour/bb/norways-government-made-electric-cars-irresistible/">http://www.pbs.org/newshour/bb/norways-government-made-electric-cars-irresistible/</a></p>
<h1 class="single-title">How Norway’s government made electric cars irresistible</h1>
<div class="meta"><em>May 29, 2017 at 6:35 PM EDT</em></div>
<p>In Scandinavia, which is a world leader in green technology, politicians and environmentalists want the president to follow their lead, and increase investment in environmentally friendly technologies like electric cars.</p>
<p>Special correspondent Malcolm Brabant reports from Norway, the world’s fastest growing electric car market.</p>
<p><strong>MALCOLM BRABANT:</strong> Norway prides itself on being one of the world’s most pristine countries. Yet, amid the stunning scenery, there are reminders that its vast wealth comes from decades of gas and oil production.</p>
<p>But Norwegians are turning their backs on fossil fuels and embracing electric cars like nowhere else.</p>
<p>Ann Kunish, who moved from Wisconsin 30 years ago, is one of the new converts.</p>
<p><strong>ANN KUNISH</strong>, Music Librarian: This car is a no-brainer. There’s no question about it. It’s very, very easy to choose electric cars. The Norwegian government has made it much more financially feasible to buy them. They don’t have the same fees, free parking in municipal spots. More and more charging stations are being built, lower yearly fee to use the roads, no tolls.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and read. More next week.</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/norway-goes-crazy-for-electric-cars-the-government-helps/">Norway Goes Crazy For Electric Cars &#8211; The government helps</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/burn-free-generation/norway-goes-crazy-for-electric-cars-the-government-helps/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Environmentally Friendly Cars &#8211; I suppose it depends on what you mean by friendly</title>
		<link>/censys/blog/burning-behavior/environmentally-friendly-cars-i-suppose-it-depends-on-what-you-mean-by-friendly/</link>
					<comments>/censys/blog/burning-behavior/environmentally-friendly-cars-i-suppose-it-depends-on-what-you-mean-by-friendly/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Doug Nicodemus]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 19:20:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[advanced energy structures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[air pollution]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[batteries]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[burning behavior]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[earth day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[electricity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[energy conservation measures]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Energy Tough Love Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[environmentalism]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[german engineering]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green cars]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[green economy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LEDs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stewardship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[waste]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/censys/?p=5967</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<p>Like I have always said, is there such a thing as an environmentally friendly car? I prefer to think instead of minimal impact on the environment. Really given all of the mining that goes on just to produce cars and &#8230; <a href="/censys/blog/burning-behavior/environmentally-friendly-cars-i-suppose-it-depends-on-what-you-mean-by-friendly/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burning-behavior/environmentally-friendly-cars-i-suppose-it-depends-on-what-you-mean-by-friendly/">Environmentally Friendly Cars &#8211; I suppose it depends on what you mean by friendly</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Like I have always said, is there such a thing as an environmentally friendly car? I prefer to think instead of minimal impact on the environment. Really given all of the mining that goes on just to produce cars and all the fossil fuels it takes to fuel them, we would be better off without them. Mass transportation is the only hope for the future.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.caranddriver.com/best-hybrid-electric-cars">http://www.caranddriver.com/best-hybrid-electric-cars</a></p>
<h1 class="sserif f36 lh36 f44-dk lh44-dk ls-sm">Hybrid and Electric Cars 2017-2018: The Best and the Rest</h1>
<div class="flex-dk w100p">
<p class="flex flex-col serif-2 f20 f22-dk lh26 lh-28-dk w100p text-charcoal pv3 pv5-dk ma0">Interested in a hybrid or an electric vehicle to help save gasoline, and possibly the planet, too? The vehicles that wear an Editors&#8217; Choice badge are our picks for the best hybrids and best EVs of 2017 and 2018.</p>
</div>
<div class="text-center flex-tb align-items-center-tb h200 h160-tb hover-filter"><a href="http://www.caranddriver.com/toyota/prius-c"> <img decoding="async" class="maxw300 w100p hauto " src="http://buyersguide.caranddriver.com/media/assets/submodel/280_8052.jpg" alt="The  Prius C" /> </a></div>
<div class="ma1 ma2-tb ma3-dk">
<div class="flex-shrink minw130">
<div class="fw-bold sserif ls-sm mb4">
<h2 class="f26 lh28 f24-tb lh26-tb inline-block tr-text">Toyota Prius C</h2>
</div>
</div>
<div class="flex flex-wrap-tb justify-between">
<div class="flex-shrink minw130 mr3">
<div class="mb2">
<div class="block">
<div class="tr-opacity trd-3 opacity0 pos-abs bg-white pa3 maxw200 border-gainsboro border-all box-shadow sserif-2 f12 fw-normal lh18 text-nero">
<div>The Editors&#8217; Rating summarizes a vehicle&#8217;s overall degree of excellence and is determined by our editors, who evaluate hundreds of vehicles every year and consider numerous factors both objective and subjective.</div>
<div class="arrow-bottom"></div>
</div>
<div class="sserif-2 f12 fw-normal text-dim-grey">Editors&#8217; Rating</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li class="w100p w50p-nm flex pb3 pr2-nm">
<div class="flex w100p">
<div class="w100p f18-tb pa4 box-shadow-card">
<div class="ma1 ma2-tb ma3-dk">
<div class="flex flex-wrap-tb justify-between">
<div class="flex-shrink minw130 mr3"></div>
<div class="flex-shrink-none">
<div class="sserif-2 f12 fw-normal text-dim-grey">
<div>Starting at</div>
</div>
<div class="sserif-2 f20 text-black fw-bold mt1 block ls-sm">$21,035</div>
</div>
</div>
<p class="serif-2 f16 lh22 mv4 hide-mb">Take the uninspired underpinnings of the Toyota Yaris and mix with it an even less powerful version of the Prius hybrid powertrain and you get the Prius C.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</li>
<li class="w100p w50p-nm flex pb3 pl1-nm">
<div class="flex w100p">
<div class="w100p f18-tb pa4 box-shadow-card">
<div class="pos-abs z20 bg-opacity65 pr2 br2"></div>
<div class="text-center flex-tb align-items-center-tb h200 h160-tb hover-filter"><a href="http://www.caranddriver.com/honda/cr-z"> <img decoding="async" class="maxw300 w100p hauto " src="http://buyersguide.caranddriver.com/media/assets/submodel/280_7355.jpg" alt="The  CR-Z" /> </a></div>
<div class="ma1 ma2-tb ma3-dk">
<div class="flex-shrink minw130">
<div class="fw-bold sserif ls-sm mb4">
<h2 class="f26 lh28 f24-tb lh26-tb inline-block tr-text">Honda CR-Z</h2>
</div>
</div>
<div class="flex flex-wrap-tb justify-between">
<div class="flex-shrink minw130 mr3">
<div class="mb2">
<div class="block">
<div class="tr-opacity trd-3 opacity0 pos-abs bg-white pa3 maxw200 border-gainsboro border-all box-shadow sserif-2 f12 fw-normal lh18 text-nero">
<div>The Editors&#8217; Rating summarizes a vehicle&#8217;s overall degree of excellence and is determined by our editors, who evaluate hundreds of vehicles every year and consider numerous factors both objective and subjective.</div>
<div class="arrow-bottom"></div>
</div>
<div class="sserif-2 f12 fw-normal text-dim-grey">Editors&#8217; Rating</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</li>
<li class="w100p w50p-nm flex pb3 pl1-nm">
<div class="flex w100p">
<div class="w100p f18-tb pa4 box-shadow-card">
<div class="ma1 ma2-tb ma3-dk">
<div class="flex flex-wrap-tb justify-between">
<div class="flex-shrink minw130 mr3"></div>
<div class="flex-shrink-none">
<div class="sserif-2 f12 fw-normal text-dim-grey">
<div>Starting at</div>
</div>
<div class="sserif-2 f20 text-black fw-bold mt1 block ls-sm">$21,130</div>
</div>
</div>
<p class="serif-2 f16 lh22 mv4 hide-mb">The CR-Z is an ambitious attempt at making a sporty hybrid, but its performance doesn’t match its adventurous styling.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</li>
<li class="w100p w50p-nm flex pb3 pr2-nm">
<div class="flex w100p">
<div class="w100p f18-tb pa4 box-shadow-card">
<div class="pos-abs z20 bg-opacity65 pr2 br2"></div>
<div class="text-center flex-tb align-items-center-tb h200 h160-tb hover-filter"><a href="http://www.caranddriver.com/hyundai/ioniq"> <img decoding="async" class="maxw300 w100p hauto " src="http://buyersguide.caranddriver.com/media/assets/submodel/280_7522.jpg" alt="The  Ioniq" /> </a></div>
<div class="ma1 ma2-tb ma3-dk">
<div class="flex-shrink minw130">
<div class="fw-bold sserif ls-sm mb4">
<h2 class="f26 lh28 f24-tb lh26-tb inline-block tr-text">Hyundai Ioniq</h2>
</div>
</div>
<div class="flex flex-wrap-tb justify-between">
<div class="flex-shrink minw130 mr3">
<div class="mb2">
<div class="block">
<div class="tr-opacity trd-3 opacity0 pos-abs bg-white pa3 maxw200 border-gainsboro border-all box-shadow sserif-2 f12 fw-normal lh18 text-nero">
<div>The Editors&#8217; Rating summarizes a vehicle&#8217;s overall degree of excellence and is determined by our editors, who evaluate hundreds of vehicles every year and consider numerous factors both objective and subjective.</div>
<div class="arrow-bottom"></div>
</div>
<div class="sserif-2 f12 fw-normal text-dim-grey">Editors&#8217; Rating</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</li>
<li class="w100p w50p-nm flex pb3 pr2-nm">
<div class="flex w100p">
<div class="w100p f18-tb pa4 box-shadow-card">
<div class="ma1 ma2-tb ma3-dk">
<div class="flex flex-wrap-tb justify-between">
<div class="flex-shrink minw130 mr3"></div>
<div class="flex-shrink-none">
<div class="sserif-2 f12 fw-normal text-dim-grey">
<div>Starting at</div>
</div>
<div class="sserif-2 f20 text-black fw-bold mt1 block ls-sm">$23,035</div>
</div>
</div>
<p class="serif-2 f16 lh22 mv4 hide-mb">Sharing its underpinnings with the Kia Niro, the Hyundai Ioniq is a hybrid in many flavors.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</li>
<li class="w100p w50p-nm flex pb3 pl1-nm">
<div class="flex w100p">
<div class="w100p f18-tb pa4 box-shadow-card">
<div class="pos-abs z20 bg-opacity65 pr2 br2"></div>
<div class="text-center flex-tb align-items-center-tb h200 h160-tb hover-filter"><a href="http://www.caranddriver.com/mitsubishi/i-miev"> <img decoding="async" class="maxw300 w100p hauto " src="http://buyersguide.caranddriver.com/media/assets/submodel/280_7572.jpg" alt="The  i-MiEV" /> </a></div>
<div class="ma1 ma2-tb ma3-dk">
<div class="flex-shrink minw130">
<div class="fw-bold sserif ls-sm mb4">
<h2 class="f26 lh28 f24-tb lh26-tb inline-block tr-text">Mitsubishi i-MiEV</h2>
</div>
</div>
<div class="flex flex-wrap-tb justify-between">
<div class="flex-shrink minw130 mr3">
<div class="mb2">
<div class="block">
<div class="tr-opacity trd-3 opacity0 pos-abs bg-white pa3 maxw200 border-gainsboro border-all box-shadow sserif-2 f12 fw-normal lh18 text-nero">
<div>The Editors&#8217; Rating summarizes a vehicle&#8217;s overall degree of excellence and is determined by our editors, who evaluate hundreds of vehicles every year and consider numerous factors both objective and subjective.</div>
<div class="arrow-bottom"></div>
</div>
<div class="sserif-2 f12 fw-normal text-dim-grey">Editors&#8217; Rating</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<div class="flex-shrink minw130 mr3"></div>
<div class="flex-shrink-none">
<div class="sserif-2 f12 fw-normal text-dim-grey">
<div>Starting at</div>
</div>
<div class="sserif-2 f20 text-black fw-bold mt1 block ls-sm">$23,845</div>
</div>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>Go there and think. More next week.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>:}</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/blog/burning-behavior/environmentally-friendly-cars-i-suppose-it-depends-on-what-you-mean-by-friendly/">Environmentally Friendly Cars &#8211; I suppose it depends on what you mean by friendly</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="/censys/">Community Energy Systems</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/censys/blog/burning-behavior/environmentally-friendly-cars-i-suppose-it-depends-on-what-you-mean-by-friendly/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
